[{"question":"If 23<sub>x<\/sub> + 101<sub>x<\/sub> = 130<sub>x<\/sub>, find the value of x","options":["7","6","5","4",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Simplify: (\\(\\frac{3}{4} - \\frac{2}{3}\\)) x 1\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{60}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{72}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{10}\\)","1\\(\\frac{7}{10}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Simplify:(\\(\\frac{10\\sqrt{3}}{\\sqrt{5}} - \\sqrt{15}\\))<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["75.00","15.00","8.66","3.87",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The distance, d, through which a stone falls from rest varies directly as the square of the time, t, taken. If the stone falls 45cm in 3 seconds, how far will it fall in 6 seconds?","options":["90cm","135cm","180cm","225cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"On a map, 1cm represent 5km. Find the area on the map that represents 100km<sup>2<\/sup>.","options":["2cm<sup>2<\/sup>","4cm<sup>2<\/sup>","8cm<sup>2<\/sup>","8cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Simplify; \\(\\frac{3^{n - 1} \\times 27^{n + 1}}{81^{n}}\\)","options":["3<sup>2n<\/sup>","9","3<sup>n<\/sup>","3<sup>n + 1<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"What sum of money will amount to D10,400 in 5 years at 6% simple interest?","options":["D8,000.00","D10,000.00","D12,000.00","D16,000.00",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The roots of a quadratic equation are \\(\\frac{4}{3}\\) and -\\(\\frac{3}{7}\\). Find the equation","options":["21x<sup>2<\/sup> - 19x - 12 = 0","21x<sup>2<\/sup> + 37x - 12 = 0","21x<sup>2<\/sup> - x + 12 = 0","21x<sup>2<\/sup> + 7x - 4 = 0",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Find the values of y for which the expression \\(\\frac{y^2 - 9y + 18}{y^2 + 4y - 21}\\) is undefined","options":["6, -7","3, -6","3, -7","-3, -7",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Given that 2x + y = 7 and 3x - 2y = 3, by how much is 7x greater than 10?","options":["1","3","7","17",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Simplify; \\(\\frac{2}{1 - x} - \\frac{1}{x}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x + 1}{x(1 - x)}\\)","\\(\\frac{3x - 1}{ x(1 - x)}\\)","\\(\\frac{3x + 1}{ x(1 - x)}\\)","\\(\\frac{x  + 1}{ x(1 - x)}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Make s the subject of the relation: P = S + \\(\\frac{sm^2}{nr}\\)","options":["s = \\(\\frac{mrp}{nr + m^2}\\)","s = \\(\\frac{nr + m^2}{mrp}\\)","s = \\(\\frac{nrp}{mr + m^2}\\)","s = \\(\\frac{nrp}{nr + m^2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Factorize; (2x + 3y)<sup>2<\/sup> - (x - 4y)<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["(3x - y)(x + 7y)","(3x + y)(2x - 7y)","(3x + y)(x - 7y)","(3x - y)(2x + 7y)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The curve surface area of a cylinder, 5cm high is 110cm <sup>2<\/sup>. Find the radius of its base. [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["2.6cm","3.5cm","3.6cm","7.0cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The volume of a pyramid with height 15cm is 90cm<sup>3<\/sup>. If its base is a rectangle with dimension xcm by 6cm, find the value of x","options":["3","5","6","8",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Calculate the gradient of the line PQ","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A straight line passes through the point P(1,2) and Q<br>\r\n(5,8). Calculate the length PQ","options":["\\(4\\sqrt{11}\\)","\\(4\\sqrt{10}\\)","\\(2\\sqrt{17}\\)","\\(2\\sqrt{13}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"If cos \\(\\theta\\) = x and sin 60<sup>o<\/sup> = x + 0.5 0<sup>o<\/sup> < \\(\\theta\\) < 90<sup>o<\/sup>, find, correct to the nearest degree, the value of \\(\\theta\\)","options":["32<sup>o<\/sup>","40<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","69<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\nAge(years) & 13 & 14 & 15 & 16 & 17 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\nFrequency & 10 & 24 & 8 & 5 & 3<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe table shows the ages of students in a club. How many students are in the club?","options":["50","55","60","65",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\nAge(years) & 13 & 14 & 15 & 16 & 17 \\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\nFrequency & 10 & 24 & 8 & 5 & 3<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\nFind the median age","options":["13","14","15","16",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A fair die is thrown two times. What is the probability that the sum of the scores is at least 10?","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{36}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The marks of eight students in a test are: 3, 10, 4, 5, 14, 13, 16 and 7. Find the range","options":["16","14","13","11",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"If log<sub>2<\/sub>(3x - 1) = 5, find x.","options":["2.00","3.67","8.67","11",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A sphere of radius rcm has the same volume as cylinder of radius 3cm and height 4cm. Find the value of r","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","2","3","6",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Express 1975 correct to 2 significant figures","options":["20","1,900","1,980","2,000",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The perimeter of a sector of a circle of radius 21cm is 64cm. Find the angle of the sector [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["70<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","55<sup>o<\/sup>","42<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"If 20(mod 9) is equivalent to y(mod 6), find y.","options":["1","2","3","4",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{(p - r)^2 - r^2}{2p^2 - 4pr}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","p - 2r","\\(\\frac{1}{p - 2r}\\)","\\(\\frac{2p}{p - 2r}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A bag contains 5 red and 4 blue identical balls. Id two balls are selected at random from the bag, one after the other, with replacement, find the probability that the first is red and the second is blue","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{20}{81}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{9}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The relation y = x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x + k passes through the point (2,0). Find the value of k","options":["- 8","- 4","4","8",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Find the next three terms of the sequence; 0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8...","options":["13, 19, 23","9, 11, 13","11, 15, 19","13, 21, 34",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Halima is n years old. Her brother's age is 5 years more than half of her age. How old is her brother?","options":["\\(\\frac{n}{2} + \\frac{5}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{n}{2}\\) - 5","5 - \\(\\frac{n}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{n}{2}\\) + 5",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"If {X: 2 d- x d- 19; X integer} and 7 + x = 4 (mod 9), find the highest value of x","options":["2","5","15","18",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The sum 11011<sub>2<\/sub>, 1111<sub>2<\/sub> and 10<sub>m<\/sub>10<sub>n<\/sub>0<sub>2<\/sub>. Find the value of m and n.","options":["m = 0, n = 0","m = 1, n = 0","m = 0, n = 1","m = 1, n = 1",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A trader bought an engine for $15,000.00 outside Nigeria. If the exchange rate is $0.070 to N1.00, how much did the engine cost in Niara?","options":["N250,000.00","N200,000.00","N150,000.00","N100,000.00",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{27^x \\times 3^{1 - x}}{9^{2x}} = 1\\), find the value of x.","options":["1","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","-\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","-1",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Find the 7<sup>th<\/sup> term of the sequence: 2, 5, 10, 17, 6,...","options":["37","48","50","63",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Given that log<sub>x<\/sub> 64 = 3, evaluate x log<sub>8<\/sub>","options":["6","9","12","24",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If 2<sup>n<\/sup> = y, Find 2\\(^{(2 + \\frac{n}{3})}\\)","options":["4y\\(^\\frac{1}{3}\\)","4y\\(^-3\\)","2y\\(^\\frac{1}{3}\\)","2y\\(^-3\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Factorize completely: 6ax - 12by - 9ay + 8bx","options":["(2a - 3b)(4x + 3y)","(3a + 4b)(2x - 3y)","(3a - 4b)(2x + 3y)","(2a + 3b)(4x -3y)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Find the equation whose roots are \\(\\frac{3}{4}\\) and -4","options":["4x<sup>2<\/sup> - 13x + 12 = 0","4x<sup>2<\/sup> - 13x - 12 = 0","4x<sup>2<\/sup> + 13x - 12 = 0","4x<sup>2<\/sup> + 13x + 12 = 0",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If m = 4, n = 9 and r = 16., evaluate \\(\\frac{m}{n}\\) - 1\\(\\frac{7}{9}\\) + \\(\\frac{n}{r}\\)","options":["1\\(\\frac{5}{16}\\)","1\\(\\frac{1}{16}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{16}\\)","- 1\\(\\frac{37}{48}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Adding 42 to a given positive number gives the same result as squaring the number. Find the number","options":["14","13","7","6",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Ada draws the graph of y = x<sup>2<\/sup> - x - 2 and y = 2x - 1 on the same axes. Which of these equations is she solving?","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup>  - x - 3 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x - 1 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x - 3 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> +  3x - 1 = 0",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The volume of a cone of height 3cm is 38\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)cm<sup>3<\/sup>. Find the radius of its base. [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["3.0cm","3.5cm","4.0cm","4.5cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The dimension of a rectangular tank are 2m by 7m by 11m. If its volume is equal to that of a cylindrical tank of height 4cm, calculate the base radius of the cylindrical tank. [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["14cm","7m","3\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)m","1\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)m",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\nx & 0 & 1\\frac{1}{2} & 2 & 4\\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline <br>\r\ny & 0 & 5\\frac{1}{2} &  &  <br>\r\n\\end{array}\\) <br>\r\nThe table given shows some values for a linear graph. Find the gradient of the line","options":["1","2","3","4",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The population of students in a school is 810. If this is represented on a pie chart, calculate the sectoral angle for a class of 7 students","options":["32<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","75<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The scores of twenty students in a test are as follows: 44, 47, 48, 49, 50, 51, 52, 53, 53, 54, 58, 59, 60, 61, 63, 65, 67, 70, 73, 75. Find the third quartile.","options":["62","63","64","65",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} <br>\r\nScores & 0 - 4 & 5 - 9 & 10 - 14\\\\ <br>\r\n\\hline Frequency & 2 & 1 & 2\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe table shows the distribution of the scores of some students in a test. Calculate the mean scores.","options":["5.6","6.2","6.6","7.0",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The probability that kebba, Ebou and Omar will hit a target are \\(\\frac{2}{3}\\), \\(\\frac{3}{4}\\) and \\(\\frac{4}{5}\\) respectively. Find the probability that only Kebba will hit the target.","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{60}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{30}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{60}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Tom will be 25 years old in n years' time. If he is 5 years younger than Bade's present age.","options":["(30 - n)years","(20 - n)years","(25 - n)years","(30 + n)years",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{\\sqrt{2} + \\sqrt{3}}{3}\\) is simplified as m + n\\(\\sqrt{6}\\), find the value of (m + n)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","1\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","1\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Make K the subject of the relation T = \\(\\sqrt{\\frac{TK - H}{K - H}}\\)","options":["K = \\(\\frac{H(T^2 - 1)}{T^2 - T}\\)","K = \\(\\frac{HT}{(T - 1)^2}\\)","K = \\(\\frac{H(T^2 + 1)}{T}\\)","K = \\(\\frac{H(T - 1)}{T}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Which of the following is used to determine the mode of a grouped data?","options":["Bar chart","Frequency  polygon","Ogive","Histogram",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Simplify: \\(\\frac{3x - y}{xy} +  \\frac{2x + 3y}{2xy} + \\frac{1}{2}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{4x + 5y - xy}{2xy}\\)","\\(\\frac{5y - 4x + xy}{2xy}\\)","\\(\\frac{5x + 4y - xy}{2xy}\\)","\\(\\frac{4x - 5y + xy}{2xy}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A farmer uses \\(\\frac{2}{5}\\) of his land to grow cassava, \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) of the remaining for yam and the rest for maize. Find the part of the land used for maize","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{15}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The rate of consumption of petrol by a vehicle varies directly as the square of the distance covered. If 4 litres of petrol is consumed on a distance of 15km. how far would the vehicle go on 9 litres of petrol?","options":["22\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)km","30km","33\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)km","45km",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A trader bought 100 oranges at 5 for N40.00 and 20 for N120.00. Find the profit or loss percent","options":["20% profit","20% loss","25% profit","25% loss",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Find the value of p if \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)p + 3q = 10 and 2p - q = 7","options":["4","3","-3","-4",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Calculate the mean deviation of 5, 3, 0, 7, 2, 1","options":["0.0","2.0","2.5","3.0",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A letter is selected from the letters of the English alphabet. What is the probability that the letter selected is from the word MATHEMATICS?","options":["\\(\\frac{9}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{26}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{26}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Simplify 10\\(\\frac{2}{5} - 6 \\frac{2}{3} + 3\\)","options":["6\\(\\frac{4}{15}\\)","6\\(\\frac{11}{15}\\)","7\\(\\frac{4}{15}\\)","7\\(\\frac{11}{15}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If 23<sub>x<\/sub> = 32<sub>5<\/sub>, find the value of x","options":["7","6","5","4",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The volume of a cube is 512cm<sup>3<\/sup>. Find the length of its side","options":["6cm","7cm","8cm","9cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If one student is selected at random, find the probability that he\/she scored at most 2 marks","options":["\\(\\frac{11}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{20}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{22}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{19}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Simplify: \\(\\sqrt{12} ( \\sqrt{48} - \\sqrt{3}\\))","options":["18","16","14","12",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Given that x > y and 3 < y, which of the following is\/are true?  i. y > 3  ii. x < 3 iii. x > y > 3","options":["i","i and ii","i and iii","i, ii and iii",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Three quarters of a number added to two and a half of the number gives 13. Find the number","options":["4","5","6","7",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If x = {0, 2, 4, 6}, y = {1, 2, 3, 4} and z = {1, 3} are subsets of u = {x:0 \\(\\geq\\) x \\(\\geq\\) 6}, find x \\(\\cap\\) (Y' \\(\\cup\\) Z)","options":["{0, 2, 6}","{1, 3}","{0, 6)","{9}",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Find the truth set of the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> = 3(2x + 9)","options":["{x : x = 3, x = 9}","{x : x = -3, x = -9}","{x : x = 3, x = -9}","{x : x = -3, x = 9}",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The coordinates of points P and Q are (4, 3) and (2, -1) respectively. Find the shortest distance between P and Q.","options":["10\\(sqrt{2}\\)","4\\(sqrt{5}\\)","5\\(sqrt{2}\\)","2\\(sqrt{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Make u the subject of formula, E = \\(\\frac{m}{2g}\\)(v<sup>2<\/sup> - u<sup>2<\/sup>)","options":["u = \\(\\sqrt{v^2 - \\frac{2Eg}{m}}\\)","u = \\(\\sqrt{\\frac{v^2}{m} - \\frac{2Eg}{4}}\\)","u = \\(\\sqrt{v- \\frac{2Eg}{m}}\\)","u = \\(\\sqrt{\\frac{2v^2Eg}{m}}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"F x varies inversely as y and y varies directly as Z, what is the relationship between x and z?","options":["x \\(\\alpha\\) z","x \\(\\alpha \\frac{1}{z}\\)","x \\(\\alpha z^2\\)","x \\(\\alpha \\frac{1}{z^2}\\0",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Find the gradient of the line joining the points (2, -3) and 2, 5)","options":["9","1","2","undefined",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If (x - a) is a factor pf bx - ax + x<sup>2<\/sup>, find the other factor.","options":["(x + b)","(x - b)","(a + b)","(a - b)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c}height & 2 & 3 & 4 & 5 & 6 \\\\ \\hline frequency & 2 & 4 & 5 & 3 & 1<br>\r\n\\end{array}\\)<br>\r\nThe table shows the distribution of the height of plants in a nursery. Calculate the mean height of the plants.","options":["3.8","3.0","2.8","2.3",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The area of a sector a circle with diameter 12cm is 66cm<sup>2<\/sup>. If the sector is folded to form a cone, calculate the radius of the base of the cone [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["3.0cm","3.5cm","7.0cm","7.5cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A chord, 7cm long, is drawn in a circle with radius 3.7cm. Calculate the distance of the chord from the centre of the circle","options":["0.7cm","1.2cm","2.0cm","2.5cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Which of the following is a measure of dispersion?","options":["range","percentile","median","quartile",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A ship sails x km due east to a point E and continues x km due north to F. Find the bearing the bearing of f from the starting point.","options":["045<sup>o<\/sup>","090<sup>o<\/sup>","135<sup>o<\/sup>","225<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A box contains 13 currency notes, all of which are either N50 or N20 notes. The total value of the currency notes is N530. How many N50 notes are in the box?","options":["4","6","8","9",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If x : y = 3 : 2 and y : z = 5 : 4, find the value of x in the ratio x : y : z","options":["8","10","15","20",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Given that cos x = \\(\\frac{12}{13}\\), evaluate \\(\\frac{1 - \\tan x}{\\tan x}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{7}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"approximate 0.0033780 to 3 significant figures","options":["338","0.338","0.00338","0.003",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{8^2 \\times 4^n + 1}{2^{2n} \\times 16}\\)","options":["16","8","4","1",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{2}{x - 3} - \\frac{3}{x - 2}\\) is equal to \\(\\frac{p}{(x - 3)(x - 2)}\\), find p","options":["-x - 5","-(x + 3)","5x - 13","5 - x",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Subtract \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)(a - b - c) from the sum of \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)(a - b + c) and \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) <br>\r\n(a + b - c)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)  (a + b + c)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)  (a - b - c)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)  (a - b + c)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)  (a + b - c)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A man's eye level is 1.7m above the horizontal ground and 13m from a vertical pole. If the pole is 8.3m high, calculate, correct to the nearest degree, the angle of elevation of the top of the pole from his eyes.","options":["33<sup>o<\/sup>","32<sup>o<\/sup>","27<sup>o<\/sup>","26<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A chord subtends an angle of 120<sup>o<\/sup> at the centre of a circle of radius 3.5cm. Find the perimeter of the minor sector containing the chord, [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["14\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)cm","12\\(\\frac{5}{6}\\)cm","8\\(\\frac{1}{7}\\)cm","7\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"In parallelogram PQRS, QR is produced to M such that |QR| = |RM|. What fraction of the area of PQMS is the area of PRMS?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"In a cumulative frequency graph, the lower quartile is 18 years while the 60th percentile is 48 years. What percentage of the distribution is at most 18 years or greater than 48 years?","options":["15%","35%","65%","85%",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If a number is selected at random from each of the sets p = {1, 2, 3} and Q = {2, 3, 5}, find the probability that the sum of the numbers is prime","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{9}\\)","1\\(\\frac{4}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{9}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"If log 5.957 = 0.7750, find log \\(3 \\sqrt{0.0005957}\\)","options":["4.1986","2.9250","1.5917","1.2853",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The probability of an event P happening is \\(\\frac{1}{5}\\) and that of event Q is \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\). If the events are independent, what is the probability that neither of them happens?","options":["\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{20}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Each exterior angle of a polygon is 30<sup>o<\/sup>. Calculate the sum of the interior angles","options":["540<sup>o<\/sup>","720<sup>o<\/sup>","1080<sup>o<\/sup>","1800<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Find the number of term in the Arithmetic Progression(A.P) 2, -9, -20,...-141.","options":["11","12","13","14",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"In what modulus is it true that 9 + 8 = 5?","options":["mod 10","mod 11","mod 12","mod 13",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The radii of the base of two cylindrical tins, P and Q are r and 2r respectively. If the water level in p is 10cm high, would be the height of the same quantity of water in Q?","options":["2.5cm","5.0cm","7.5cm","20.0cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Multiply 2.7 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup> by 6.3 x 10<sup>6<\/sup> and leave your answers in standard form","options":["1.7 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>","1.70 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>","1.701 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>","17.01 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If 9<sup>(2 - x)<\/sup> = 3, find x","options":["1","\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","2","\\(\\frac{5}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"In what number base is the addition 465 + 24 + 225 = 1050?","options":["ten","nine","eight","seven",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{1\\frac{7}{8} \\times 2\\frac{2}{5}}{6\\frac{3}{4} \\div \\frac{3}{4}}\\)","options":["9","4\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","2","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If Un = n(n<sup>2<\/sup> + 1), evaluate U5 - U4","options":["18","56","62","80",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If \\(\\sqrt{50} - K\\sqrt{8} = \\frac{2}{\\sqrt{2}}\\), find K","options":["-2","-1","1","2",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A sales boy gave a change of N68 instead of N72. Calculate his percentage error","options":["4%","5\\(\\frac{5}{9}\\)%","5\\(\\frac{15}{17}\\)%","7%",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Four oranges sell for Nx and three mangoes sell for Ny. Olu bought 24 oranges and 12 mangoes. How much did he pay in terms of x and y?","options":["N94x + 6y)","N(6x + 4y)","N(24x + 12y)","N(12x + 24y)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Simplify: \\(\\frac{x^2 - y^2}{(x + y)^2} + \\frac{(x - y)^2}{(3x + 3y)}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x - y}{3}\\)","x + y","\\(\\frac{3}{x - y}\\)","x - y",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Solve the inequality: \\(\\frac{2x - 5}{2} < (2 - x)\\)","options":["x > 0","x < \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","x > 2\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","x < 2\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If x = 64 and y = 27, evaluate: \\(\\frac{x^{\\frac{1}{2}} - y^{\\frac{1}{3}}}{y - x^{\\frac{2}{3}}}\\)","options":["2\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","1","\\(\\frac{5}{11}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{43}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)x + 2y = 3 and \\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)x and \\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)x - 2y = 1, find (x + y)","options":["3","2","1","5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given that p<sup>\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)<\/sup> = \\(\\frac{3\\sqrt{q}}{r}\\), make q the subject of the equation","options":["q = p\\(\\sqrt{r}\\)","q = p<sup>3<\/sup>r","q = pr<sup>3<\/sup>","q = pr<sup>\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A chord is 2cm from the centre of a circle. If the radius of the circle is 5cm, find the length of the chord","options":["2\\(\\sqrt{21}\\)cm","\\(\\sqrt{42}\\)cm","2\\(\\sqrt{19}\\)cm","\\(\\sqrt{21}\\)cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A cube and cuboid have the same base area. The volume of the cube is 64cm<sup>3<\/sup> while that of the cuboid is 80cm<sup>3<\/sup>. Find the height of the cuboid","options":["1cm","3cm","5cm","6cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If sin x = \\(\\frac{5}{13}\\) and 0<sup>o<\/sup> \\(\\leq\\) x \\(\\leq\\) 90<sup>o<\/sup>, find the value of (cos x - tan x)","options":["\\(\\frac{7}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{12}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{79}{156}\\)","\\(\\frac{209}{156}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"An object is 6m away from the base of a mast. The angle of depression of the object from the top pf the mast is 50<sup>o<\/sup>, Find, correct to 2 decimal places, the height of the mast","options":["8.60m","7.51m","7.15m","1.19m",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The bearing of Y from X is 060<sup>o<\/sup> and the bearing of Z from Y = 060<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the bearing of X from Z","options":["300<sup>o<\/sup>","240<sup>o<\/sup>","180<sup>o<\/sup>","120<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Which of the following  is not a probability of Mary scoring 85% in a mathematics test?","options":["0.15","0.57","0.94","1.01",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If 2 log x (3\\(\\frac{3}{8}\\)) = 6, find the value of x","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If p = (y : 2y \\(\\geq\\) 6) and Q = (y : y -3 \\(\\geq\\) 4), where y is an integer, find p\\(\\cap\\)Q","options":["{3, 4}","{3, 7}","{3, 4, 5, 6, 7}","{4, 5, 6}",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Find the values of k in the equation 6k<sup>2<\/sup> = 5k + 6","options":["{\\(\\frac{-2}{3}, \\frac{-3}{2}\\)}","{\\(\\frac{-2}{3}, \\frac{3}{2}\\)}","{\\(\\frac{2}{3}, \\frac{-3}{2}\\)}","{\\(\\frac{2}{3}, \\frac{3}{2}\\)}",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"If y varies directly s the square root of (x + 1) and y = 6 when x = 3, find x when y = 9","options":["8","7","6","5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The graph of the relation y = x2 + 2x + k passes through the point (2, 0). Find the values of k","options":["zero","-2","-4","-8",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"What is the locus of the point X which moves relative to two fixed points P and M on a plane such that < PXM = 30<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["thebisector of the straight line joining P and M","an arc of a circle with PM as a chord","the bisector of angle PXM","a circle centre X and radius PM",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"When a number is subtracted from 2, the result equals 2 less than one-fifth of the number. Find the number","options":["11","\\(\\frac{15}{2}\\)","5","\\(\\frac{5}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Express \\(\\frac{2}{x + 3} - \\frac{1}{x - 2}\\) as a simple fraction","options":["\\(\\frac{x - 7}{x^2 + x - 6}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 1}{x^2 + x - 6}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 2}{x^2 + x - 6}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 27}{x^2 + x - 6}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"An interior angle of a regular polygon is 5 times each exterior angle. How many sides has the polygon?","options":["15","12","9","6",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given that P = x<sup>2<\/sup> + 4x  - 2, Q = 2x - 1 and Q - p = 2, find x","options":["-2","-1","1","2",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A pyramid has a rectangular base with dimensions 12m by 8m. If its height is 14m, calculate the volume","options":["322m<sup>3<\/sup>","448m<sup>3<\/sup>","632m<sup>2<\/sup>","840m<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The slant height of a cone is 5cm and the radius of its base is 3cm. Find, correct to the nearest whole number, the volume of the cone. ( Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\))","options":["48cm<sup>3<\/sup>","47cm<sup>3<\/sup>","38cm<sup>3<\/sup>","12cm<sup>3<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The distance between two towns is 50km. It is represented on a map by 5cm. Find the scale used","options":["1: 1,000,000","1: 500,000","1: 100,000","1: 10,000",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Given that (x + 2)(x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x + 2) + 2(x + 2)(x - 1) = (x + 2) M, find M","options":["(x + 2)<sup>2<\/sup>","x(x + 2)","xv + 2","x<sup>2<\/sup> - x",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"An open cone with base radius 28cm and perpendicular height 96cm was stretched to form sector of a circle. calculate the arc of the sector (Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\))","options":["8800cm<sup>2<\/sup>","8448cm<sup>2<\/sup>","4400cm<sup>2<\/sup>","4224cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Express 302.10495 correct to five significant figures","options":["302.10","302.11","302.105","302.1049",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Simplify; \\(\\frac{3\\sqrt{5} \\times 4\\sqrt{6}}{2 \\sqrt{2} \\times 3\\sqrt{2}}\\)","options":["\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{5}\\)","2\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","2\\(\\sqrt{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In 1995, the enrollment of two schools X and Y were 1,050 and 1,190 respectively. Find the ration of the enrollments of X and Y","options":["50:11","15:17","13:55","12:11",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Convert 35<sub>10<\/sub> to number in base 2","options":["1011","10011","100011","11001",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The n<sup>th<\/sup> term of a sequence is T<sub>n<\/sub> = 5 + (n - 1)<sup>2<\/sup>. Evaluate T<sub>4<\/sub> - T<sub>6<\/sub>","options":["30","16","-16","-30",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Mr. Manu travelled from Accra to Pamfokromb a distance of 720km in 8 hours. What will be his speed in m\/s?","options":["25m\/s","150m\/s","250m\/s","500m\/s",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If N2,500.00 amounted to N3,50.00 in 4 years at simple interest, find the rate at which the interest was charged","options":["5%","7\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)%","8%","10%",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Solve for x in the equation; \\(\\frac{1}{x} + \\frac{2}{3x} = \\frac{1}{3}\\)","options":["5","4","3","1",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Simplify: \\(\\frac{54k^2 - 6}{3k + 1}\\)","options":["6(1 - 3k<sup>2<\/sup>)","6(3k<sup>2<\/sup> - 1)","6(3k - 1)","6(1 - 3k)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Make p the subject of the relation: q = \\(\\frac{3p}{r} + \\frac{s}{2}\\)","options":["p = \\(\\frac{2q - rs}{6}\\)","p = 2qr - sr - 3","p = \\(\\frac{2qr - s}{6}\\)","p = \\(\\frac{2qr - rs}{6}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If x + y = 2y - x + 1 = 5, find the value of x","options":["3","2","1","-1",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The sum of 12 and one third of n is 1 more than twice n. Express the statement in the form of an equation","options":["12n - 6 = 0","3n - 12 = 0","2n - 35 = 0","5n - 33 = 0",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Solve the inequality: \\(\\frac{-m}{2} - \\frac{5}{4} \\geq \\frac{5m}{12} - \\frac{7}{6}\\)","options":["m \\(\\leq \\frac{5}{4}\\)","m \\(\\geq \\frac{5}{4}\\)","m \\(\\leq - \\frac{1}{11}\\)","m \\(\\geq - \\frac{1}{11}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The curved surface area of a cylindrical tin is 704cm<sup>2<\/sup>. If the radius of its base is 8cm, find the height. [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]`","options":["14cm","9cm","8cm","7cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The lengths of the minor and major arcs 54cm and 126cm respectively. Calculate the angle of the major sector","options":["360<sup>o<\/sup>","252<sup>o<\/sup>","246<sup>o<\/sup>","234<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"In \\(\\bigtriangleup\\) XYZ, \/XY\/ = 8cm, \/YZ\/ = 10cm and \/XZ\/ = 6cm. Which of these relation is true?","options":["\/XY\/ + \/YZ\/ = \/XZ\/","\/XY\/ - \/YZ\/ = \/XZ\/","\/XY\/<sup>2<\/sup> = \/Y\/<sup>2<\/sup> - \/XY\/<sup>2<\/sup>","\/YZ\/<sup>2<\/sup> = \/XZ\/<sup>2<\/sup> - \/XY\/<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If cos(x + 40)<sup>o<\/sup> = 0.0872, what is the value of x?","options":["85<sup>o<\/sup>","75<sup>o<\/sup>","65<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"A kite flies on a taut string of length 50m inclined at tan angle 54<sup>o<\/sup> to the horizontal ground. The height of the kite above the ground is","options":["50 tan 30<sup>o<\/sup>","50 sin 54<sup>o<\/sup>","50 tan 54<sup>o<\/sup>","50 sin 36<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Given that the mean of the scores 15, 21, 17, 26, 18 and 29 is 21, calculate the standard deviation of the scores","options":["\\(\\sqrt{10}\\)","4","5","\\(\\sqrt{30}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"A bag contains 4 red and 6 black balls of the same size. If the balls are shuffled briskly and two balls are drawn one after the other without replacement, find the probability of picking balls of different colours","options":["\\(\\frac{8}{15}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{25}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{15}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{15}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Which of these statements about y = 8\\(\\sqrt{m}\\) is correct?","options":["log y = log 8 x log \\(\\sqrt{m}\\)","log y = 3 log 2 x \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) log m","log y = 3 log 2 - \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) log m","log y = 3 log 2 + \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) log m",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If x + 0.4y = 3 and y = \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)x, find the value of (x + y)","options":["1\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","2\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","3\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)","5",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Express 3 - [\\(\\frac{x - y}{y}\\)] as a single fraction","options":["\\(\\frac{3xy}{y}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 4y}{y}\\)","\\(\\frac{4y - x}{y}\\)","3 - \\(\\frac{x - y}{y}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If p = {prime factors of 210} and Q = {prime less than 10}, find p \\(\\cap\\) Q","options":["{1,2, 3}","{2, 3, 5}","{1, 3, 5,7}","{2,3,5,7}",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Alfred spent \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\) of his money on food, \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) on clothing and save the rest. If he saved N72,20.00, how much did he spend on food?","options":["N43,200.00","N43,000.00","N42,200.00","N40,000.00",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Solve (\\(\\frac{27}{125}\\))<sup>-\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)<\/sup> x (\\(\\frac{4}{9}\\))<sup>\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)<\/sup>","options":["\\(\\frac{10}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{12}{125}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The sum of the interior angles of regular polygon is 1800<sup>o<\/sup>. How many sides has the polygon?","options":["16","12","10","8",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Find the coefficient of m in the expression of (\\(\\frac{m}{2} - 1 \\frac{1}{2}\\)) (m + \\(\\frac{2}{3}\\))","options":["-\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","- \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","-1","-1\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The volume of a cuboid is 54cm<sup>3<\/sup>. If the length, width and height of the cuboid are in the ratio 2:1:2 respectively, find its total surface area","options":["108cm<sup>2<\/sup>","90cm<sup>2<\/sup>","80cm<sup>2<\/sup>","72cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"A side and a diagonal of a rhombus are 10cm and 12cm respectively, Find its area","options":["20cm<sup>2<\/sup>","24cm<sup>2<\/sup>","48cm<sup>2<\/sup>","96cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Factorise completely: 32x<sup>2<\/sup>y - 48x<sup>3<\/sup>y<sup>3<\/sup>","options":["16x<sup>2<\/sup>y(2 - 3xy<sup>2<\/sup>)","8xy(4x - 6x<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>2<\/sup>)","8x<sup>2<\/sup>y(4 - 6xy<sup>2<\/sup>)","16xy(2x - 3x<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>2<\/sup>)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If x and y are variables and k is a constant, which of the following describes an inverse relationship between x and y?","options":["y = kx","y = \\(\\frac{k}{x}\\)","y = k\\(\\sqrt{x}\\)","y = x + k",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If x and y are variables and k is a constant, which of the following describes an inverse relationship between x and y?","options":["y = kx","y = \\(\\frac{k}{x}\\)","y = k\\(\\sqrt{x}\\)","y = x + k",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"If N112.00 exchanges for D14.95, calculate the value of D1.00 in naira","options":["0.13","7.49","8.00","13.00",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Solve for x in the equation; \\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)(2x - 1) = \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)(5x - 3)","options":["zero","1","2","3",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Given that cos x<sup>o<\/sup> = \\(\\frac{1}{r}\\), express tan x<sup><\/sup> in terms of r","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{r}}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{r}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{r^2 + 1}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{r^2 - 1}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Solve the equation; 3x - 2y = 7, x + 2y = -3","options":["x = 1, y = -2","x = 1, y = 3","x = -2, y = -1","x = 4, y = -3",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"If a number is chosen at random from the set {x: 4 \\(\\leq x \\leq 45\\)}. Find the probability that it is a multiple of 3 or a multiple of 4","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{12}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"One of the factors of (mn - nq - n2 + mq) is (m - n). The other factor is","options":["(n - q)","(q - n)","(n + q)","(q - m)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A cylindrical container has a base radius of 14cm and height 18cm. How many litres of liquid can it hold?  correct to the nearest litre [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["11","14","16","18",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A regular polygon of n sides has each exterior angle to 45<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the value of n","options":["6","8","12","15",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Esther was facing S 20<sup>o<\/sup> W. She turned 90<sup>o<\/sup> in the clock wise direction. What direction is she facing?","options":["N 70<sup>o<\/sup> W","S 70<sup>o<\/sup> W","N 20<sup>o<\/sup> W","S 20<sup>o<\/sup> E",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The cross section section of a uniform prism is a right-angled triangle with sides 3cm. 4cm and 5cm. If its length is 10cm. Calculate the total surface area","options":["142cm<sup>2<\/sup>","132cm<sup>2<\/sup>","122cm<sup>2<\/sup>","112cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"From the equation whose roots are x = \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) and -\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","options":["6x<sup>2<\/sup> - x + 2 = 0","6x<sup>2<\/sup> - x - 2 = 0","6x<sup>2<\/sup> + x + 2 = 0","6x<sup>2<\/sup> + x - 2 = 0",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{\\log \\sqrt{27}}{\\log \\sqrt{81}}\\)","options":["3","2","\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Which of these angles can be constructed using ruler and a pair of compasses only?","options":["115<sup>o<\/sup>","125<sup>o<\/sup>","135<sup>o<\/sup>","145<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The perimeter of a sector of a circle of radius 4cm is (\\(\\pi + 8\\))cm. Calculate the anle of the sector","options":["45<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","75<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The length of a piece of stick is 1.75m. A girl measured it as 1.80m. Find the percentage error","options":["\\(\\frac{28}{7}\\)%","\\(\\frac{29}{7}\\)%","5%","\\(\\frac{20}{7}\\)%",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"What is the value of 3 in the number 42.7531?","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{10000}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{1000}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{100}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{10}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The height of a cylinder is equal to its radius. If the volume is 0.216 \\(\\pi m^3\\) Calculate the radius.","options":["0.46m","0.60m","0.87m","1.80m",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The height of a cylinder is equal to its radius. If the volume is 0.216 \\(\\pi m^3\\) Calculate the radius.","options":["0.46m","0.60m","0.87m","1.80m",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"What is the value of 3 in the number 42.7531?","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{10000}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{1000}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{100}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{10}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Factorize the expression: am + bn - an - bm","options":["(a - b)(m + n)","(a - b)(m - n)","(a + b)(m - n)","(a + b)(m + n)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{m}{n} + \\frac{(m - 1)}{5n} = \\frac{(m - 2)}{10n}\\) where n \\(\\neq\\) 0","options":["\\(\\frac{m - 3}{10n}\\)","\\(\\frac{11m}{10n}\\)","\\(\\frac{m + 1}{10n}\\)","\\(\\frac{11m + 4}{10n}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"If \\(\\sqrt{72} + \\sqrt{32} - 3 \\sqrt{18} = x \\sqrt{8}\\), Find the value of x","options":["1","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"G varies directly as the square of H, If G is 4 when H is 3, find H when G = 100","options":["15","25","75","225",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Given that n(p) = 19, m(P \\(\\cup\\) Q) = 38 and n(P \\(\\cap\\) Q) = 7, Find n(C)","options":["26","31","36","50",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"What must be added to (2x - 3y) to get (x 0 2y)?","options":["5y - x","y - x","x - 5x","x - y",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Simplify 1\\(\\frac{3}{4} - (2 \\frac{1}{3} + 4)\\)","options":["3\\(\\frac{5}{12}\\)","2\\(\\frac{7}{12}\\)","-4 \\(\\frac{7}{12}\\)","-5 \\(\\frac{7}{12}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Find the smaller value of x that satisfies the equation x<sub>2<\/sub> + 7x + 10 = 0","options":["-5","-2","2","5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The perpendicular bisectors of the sides of an acute-angled triangle are drawn. Which of these statements is correct? They intersect","options":["on one of the vertices","at a midpoint of a side","inside the triangle","outside the triangle",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A rectangular garden measures 18.6m by 12.5m. Calculate, correct to three significant figures, the area of the garden","options":["230m<sup>2<\/sup>","231m<sup>2<\/sup>","232m<sup>2<\/sup>","233m<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"John pours 96 litres of red oil into a rectangular container with length 220cm and breadth 40cm. Calculate, correct to the nearest cm, the height of the oil in the container","options":["11cm","18cm","21cm","34cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"John pours 96 litres of red oil into a rectangular container with length 220cm and breadth 40cm. Calculate, correct to the nearest cm, the height of the oil in the container","options":["11cm","18cm","21cm","34cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"in a quiz competition, a student answers n questions correctly and was given D(n + 50) for each question correctly answered. If he gets D600.00 altogether, how many questions did he answer correctly?","options":["18","15","12","10",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"If 27<sup>x<\/sup> = 9<sup>y<\/sup>. Find the value of \\(\\frac{x}{y}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","3",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"a boy looks through a window of a building and sees a mango fruit on the ground 50m away from the foot of the building. If the window is 9m from the ground, calculate, correct to the nearest degree, the angle of depression of the mango from the window","options":["9<sup>o<\/sup>","10<sup>o<\/sup>","11<sup>o<\/sup>","12<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Simplify 0.000215 x 0.000028 and express your answer in standard form","options":["6.03 x 10<sup>9<\/sup>","6.02 x 10<sup>9<\/sup>","6.03 x 10<sup>-9<\/sup>","6.02 x 10<sup>-9<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Factorize: x + y - ax = ay","options":["(x - y)(1 - a)","(x + y)(1 + a)","(x + y)(1 - a)","(x - y)(1 + a)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"A car uses one litre of petrol for every 14km. If one of petrol cost N63.00, how far can the car go with N900.00 worth of petrol?","options":["420km","405km","210km","200km",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Correct 0.002473 to 3 significant figure","options":["0.002","0.0024","0.00247","0.0025",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Simplify 1\\(\\frac{1}{2} + 2\\frac{1}{3} \\times \\frac{3}{4} - \\frac{1}{2}\\)","options":["-2\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","-2\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","2\\(\\frac{1}{8}\\)","2\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The sum of 2 consecutive whole numbers is \\(\\frac{5}{6}\\) of their product, find the numbers","options":["3, 4","1, 2","2, 3","0, 1",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"A casting is made up of Copper and Zinc. If 65% of the casting is Zinc and there are 147g of Copper. What is the mass of the casting?","options":["320g","420g","520g","620g",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Given that P = {x : 1 \\(\\leq x \\leq 6\\)}, and Q = {x : 2 \\(\\leq x \\leq 10\\)} where x is an integer. Find n(P \\(\\cap\\))","options":["4","6","8","10",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The sum of 6 and one-third of x is one more than twice x, find x","options":["x = 7","x = 5","x = 3","x = 2",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Given that  = {x: -2 < x \\(\\leq\\) 9}, where x is an integer what is n(T)?","options":["9","10","11","12",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Solve the inequality: 3(x + 1) \\(\\leq\\) 5(x + 2) + 15","options":["x \\(\\geq\\) -14","x \\(\\leq\\) - 14","x \\(\\geq\\) -11","x \\(\\leq\\) - 11",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"An empty rectangular tank is 250cm long and 120cm wide. If 180 litres of water is poured into the tank. Calculate the height of the water","options":["6.0cm","5.5cm","5.0cm","4.5cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Given that \\(\\frac{5^{n +3}}{25^{2n -2}}\\) = 5<sup>o<\/sup>, find n","options":["n = 1","n = 2","n = 3","n = 5",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} \\text{No. of pets} & 0 & 1 & 2 & 3 & 4 \\\\ \\hline \\text{No. of students} & 8 & 4 & 5 & 10 & 3\\end{array}\\) The table shows the number of pets kept by 30 students in a class. If a student is picked at random ftom the class. What is the probability that he\/she kept more than one pet?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Simplify 2\\(\\sqrt{3}\\) - \\(\\frac{6}{\\sqrt{3}} + \\frac{3}{\\sqrt{27}}\\)","options":["1","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\sqrt{3}\\)","2\\(\\sqrt{3} - 5\\frac{2}{3}\\)","6\\(\\sqrt{3}\\) - 17",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If sin 3y = cos 2y and 0<sup>o<\/sup> \\(\\leq\\) 90<sup>o<\/sup>, find the value of y","options":["18<sup>o<\/sup>","36<sup>o<\/sup>","54<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"A rectangle has length xcm and width (x - 1)cm. If the perimeter is 16cm. Find the value of x","options":["3\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)cm","4cm","4\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)cm","5cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Given that tan x = 1, where 0<sup>o<\/sup> \\(\\geq\\) x 90<sup>o<\/sup>, evaluate \\(\\frac{1 - \\sin^2 x}{\\cos x}\\)","options":["2\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{2}}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"What is the length of a rectangular garden whose perimeter is 32cm and area 39cm<sup>2<\/sup>?","options":["25cm","18cm","13cm","9cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{2}{2 + x} + \\frac{2}{2 - x}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{4}{4 - x^3}\\)","\\(\\frac{8}{4 - x^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{4x}{4 - x^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{8 - 4x}{4 - x^2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The sum of the exterior of an n-sided convex polygon is half the sum of its interior angle. find n","options":["6","8","9","12",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If y = \\(\\frac{y(2\\sqrt{x^2 + m})}{3N}\\), make x the subject of the formular","options":["\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{9y^2 N^2 - 2m}}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{9y^2 N^2 - 4m}}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{9y^2 N^2 - 3m}}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{9y^2 N - 3m}}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The nth term of the sequence -2, 4, -8, 16.... is given by","options":["T<sub>n<\/sub> = 2<sup>n<\/sup>","T<sub>n<\/sub> = (-2)<sup>n<\/sup>","T<sup>n<\/sup> = (-2n)","T<sub>n<\/sub> = n<sup><\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"How many times, correct to the nearest whole number, will a man run round  circular track of diameter 100m to cover a distance of 1000m?","options":["3","4","5","6",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Bola sold an article for N6,900.00 and made a profit of 15%. If he sold it for N6,600.00 he would make a","options":["profit of 13%","loss of 12%","loss of 10%","loss of 5%",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The mean age of R men in a club is 50 years, Two men aged 55 and 63, left the club and the mean age reduced by 1 year. Find the value of R","options":["18","20","22","28",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} x & 0 & 2 & 4 & 6\\\\ \\hline y & 1 & 2 & 3 & 4\\end{array}\\). <br>\r\nThe table is for the relation y = mx + c where m and c are constants. What is the equation of the line described in the tablet?","options":["y = 2x","y = x + 1","y = x","y = \\(\\frac{1}{2}x + 1\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"What is the value of x when y = 5?","options":["8","9","10","11",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The subtraction below is in base seven. Find the missing number.<br>\r\n 5 1 6 2<sub>seven<\/sub><br>\r\n-2 6 4 4<sub>seven<\/sub><br>\r\n--------<br>\r\n 2 * 1 5<br>\r\n--------","options":["2","3","4","5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If the sum of the roots of the equation (x - p)(2x - 1) - 0 is 1, find the value of x","options":["1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","-\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","-1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If x<sup>2<\/sup> + kx + \\(\\frac{16}{9}\\) is a perfect square, find the value of x","options":["\\(\\frac{8}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"If x km\/h = y m\/s, then y =","options":["\\(\\frac{7}{18}\\)x","\\(\\frac{11}{20}\\)x","\\(\\frac{4}{15}\\)x","\\(\\frac{5}{18}\\)x",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The mean of the numbers 2, 5, 2x and 7 is less than or equal to 5. Find the range of the values of x","options":["x \\(\\leq\\) 3","x \\(\\geq\\) 3","x < 3","x > 3",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"In an athletic composition, the probability that an athlete wins a 100m race is \\(\\frac{1}{8}\\) and the probability that he wins in high jump is \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\). What is the probability that he wins only one of the events?","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{32}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{16}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Simplify: (3\\(\\frac{1}{2} + 4\\frac{1}{3}) \\div (\\frac{5}{6} - \\frac{2}{3}\\))","options":["1\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","8\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","35","47",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"In a particular year, the exchange rate of naira (N) varies directly with the Dollars{$}. If N1122 is equivalent to $8, find the Naira equivalent of $36","options":["N8976","N5049","N140.25","N31.17",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If log 2 = x, log 3 = y and log 7 = z, find, in terms of x, y and z, the value of log (\\(\\frac{28}{3}\\))","options":["2x + y - z","2x + x - y","x + y - 2x","x + x - y",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Arrange the following numbers in descending orders of magnitude: 22<sub>three<\/sub>, 34<sub>five<\/sub>, 21<sub>six<\/sub>","options":["21<sub>six<\/sub>, 22<sub>three<\/sub>, 34<sub>five<\/sub>,","21<sub>six<\/sub>, 34<sub>five<\/sub>, 22<sub>three<\/sub>","22<sub>three<\/sub>, 34<sub>five<\/sub>,  21<sub>six<\/sub>","34<sub>five<\/sub>,  21<sub>six<\/sub>, 22<sub>three<\/sub>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Find the value to which N3000.00 will amount in 5 years at 6% per annum simple interest","options":["N3,900.00","N3,750.00","N3,600.00","N3,300",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Express the square root of 0.000144 in the standard form","options":["1.2 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup>","1.2 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","1.2 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","1.2 x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Two sets are disjoint if","options":["they are both empty","their union is an empty set","their intersection is an empty set","one of them is a subset of the other",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{3}{2x} - \\frac{2}{3x} = 4\\), solve for x","options":["\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{24}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{24}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If (2x + 3)<sup>3<\/sup> = 125, find the value of x","options":["1","2","3","4",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Factorize x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x - 3xy completely","options":["(x - 2)(3x - y)","(x - 3y)(x - 2)","(x - 3y)(x - 3y)","(3x + y)(x - 2)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The diameter of a bicycle wheel is 42cm. If the wheel makes 16 complete revolution, what will be the total distance covered by the wheel? [Take \\(\\pi \\frac{22}{7}\\)","options":["672cm","1056cm","2112cm","4224cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The interior angles of a pentagon are (2<sup>x<\/sup> + 5)<sup>o<\/sup>, (x + 20)<sup>o<\/sup>, x<sup>o<\/sup>, (3x - 20)<sup>o<\/sup> and (x + 15)<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the value of x","options":["80<sup>o<\/sup>","70<sup>o<\/sup>","65<sup>o<\/sup>","40<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If M and N are two fixed points in a plane. Find the locus L = [P : PM = PN]","options":["a line equal to MN","line parallel to MN","Perpendicular bisector of MN","A circle centre P, radius MN",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Given that sin 60<sup>o<\/sup> = \\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\) and cos 60<sup>o<\/sup> = \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\), evaluate \\(\\frac{1 - sin 60^o}{1 + cos 60^o}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{2 + \\sqrt{3}}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1 - \\sqrt{3}}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1 + \\sqrt{3}}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2 - \\sqrt{3}}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"In an examination, Kofi scored x% in Physics, 50% in Chemistry and 70% in Biology. If his mean score for the three subjects was 55%, find x","options":["40","45","55","60",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"What is the median of the following scores: 22 35 41 63 74 82","options":["82","52","49","22",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Express 2.7864 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup> to 2 significant figures","options":["0.28","0.27","0.0028","0.0027",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If 9<sup>2x<\/sup> = \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)(27<sup>x<\/sup>), find x","options":["2","1","-1","-2",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If 85% of x is N3230, what is the value of x?","options":["N2745.50","N3714.50","N3800.00","N4845.00",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The capacity of a water tank is 1,800 litres. If the tank is in form of a cuboid with base 600cm by 150 cm. Find the height of the tank","options":["2cm","20cm","200cm","2000cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"An arc of a circle subtends an angle of 60<sup>o<\/sup> at the centre. If the radius of the circle is 3cm, find , in terms of \\(\\pi\\), the length of the arc","options":["\\(\\pi\\)cm","2\\(\\pi\\)cm","3\\(\\pi\\)cm","6\\(\\pi\\)cm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"solve \\(\\frac{2x + 1}{6} - \\frac{3x - 1}{4}\\) = 0","options":["1","\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","-\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","-1",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If a positive integer, list the values of x which satisfy the equation 3x - 4 < 6 and x - 1 > 0","options":["{1, 2, 3}","{2, 3}","{2, 3, 4}","{2, 3, 4, 5}",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If c and k are the roots of 6 - x - x<sup>2<\/sup> = 0, find c + k","options":["2","1","-1","-3",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Each of the interior angles of a regular polygon is 140<sup>o<\/sup>. Calculate the sum of all the interior angles of the polygon","options":["1080<sup>o<\/sup>","1260<sup>o<\/sup>","1800<sup>o<\/sup>","2160<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A bucket holds 10 litres of water. How many buckets of water will fill a reservoir of size 8m x 7m x 5m.(1 litre = 1000cm<sup>3<\/sup>)`","options":["28","280","2800","28000",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A box contains black, white and red identical balls. The probability of picking a black ball at random from the box is \\(\\frac{3}{10}\\) and the probability of picking a white ball at random is \\(\\frac{2}{5}\\). If there are 30 balls in the box, how many of them are red?","options":["3","7","9","12",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Simplify; \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\sqrt{32} - \\sqrt{18}  \\sqrt{2}\\)","options":["zero","\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","2\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","4\\(\\sqrt{2}\\0",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The angles of triangle are (x + 10)<sup>o<\/sup>, (2x - 40)<sup>o<\/sup> and (3x - 90)<sup>o<\/sup>. Which of the following accurately describes the triangle?","options":["it is a scalene triangle","it is right angled isosceles triangle","t is an equilateral triangle","It is an isosceles triangle but not right angled",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Simplify (x - 3y)<sup>2<\/sup> - (x + 3y)<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["2(x + 3y)","(2x - 3y)","-12xy","6xy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Find the quadratic equation whose roots are -\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) and 3","options":["2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x + 3 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x - 3 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x + 3 = 0","3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x - 3 = 0",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"If x% of 240 equals 12, find x","options":["x = 1","x = 3","x = 5","x = 7",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(\\frac{(3.2)^2 - (4.8)^2}{3.2 + 1.8}\\)","options":["-0.08","-1.60","-10.24","-12.80",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\sqrt{50} + \\frac{10}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)","options":["10","10\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","20","20\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"P naira invested for 4 years  invested for 4 years at r% simple interest per annum yields 0.36 p naira interest. Find the value of r","options":["1\\(\\frac{1}{9}\\)","1\\(\\frac{4}{9}\\)","9","11",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A trader bought 100 tubers at 5 for N350.00. She sold them in sets of 4 for N290.00. Find her gain percent.","options":["3.6%","3.5%","3.5%","2.55",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If p-2g + 1 = g + 3p and p - 2 = 0, find g","options":["-2","-1","1","2",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{\\frac{1}{x} + \\frac{1}{y}}{x + y}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{x + y}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{xy}\\)","x + y","xy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Simplify 3\\(\\sqrt{27x^3y^9}\\)","options":["9xy<sup>3<\/sup>","3xy<sup>6<\/sup>","3xy<sup>3<\/sup>","9y<sup>3<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given that x = 2 and y = -\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\), evaluate \\(\\frac{x^2y - 2xy}{5}\\)","options":["zero","\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","1","2",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Factorize 5y<sup>2<\/sup> + 2ay - 3a<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["(a - y)(5y - 3a)","(y - a)(5y - 3a)","(y - a)(5y + 3a)","(y + a)(5y  3a)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If 4y is 9 greater than the sum of y and 3x, by how much is greater than x?","options":["3","6","9","12",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If p = \\(\\frac{3}{5} \\sqrt{\\frac{q}{r}}\\), express q in terms of p and r","options":["\\(\\frac{9}{25} pr^2\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{25} p^2r\\)","\\(\\frac{25}{9} p^2r\\)","\\(\\frac{25}{9} pr^2\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Simplify: \\(\\frac{2x^2 - 5x - 12}{4x^2 - 9}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x + 4}{2x + 3}\\)","\\(\\frac{x + 4}{2x - 3}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 4}{2x + 3}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 4}{2x - 3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"PQR is a sector of a circle centre O, radius 4cm. If PQR = 30<sup>o<\/sup>, find, correct to 3 significant figures, the area of sector PQR. [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["4.19cm<sup>2<\/sup>","8.38cm<sup>2<\/sup>","10.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","20.9cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If the volume of a cube is 343cm<sup>3<\/sup>, find the length of its side","options":["3cm","6cm","7cm","96cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The angles of a quadrilateral are (x + 10)<sup>o<\/sup>, 2y<sup>o<\/sup>, 90<sup>o<\/sup> and (100 - y)<sup>o<\/sup>, Find y in terms of x","options":["y = 160 + x","y = 100 + x","y = 160 - x","y = x - 100",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If x<sup>o<\/sup> is obtuse, which of the following is true?","options":["x . 90","180 < x < 270","x < 90","90 < x < 180",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If tan x = 1, evaluate sin x + cos x, leaving your answer in the surd form","options":["2\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2} \\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)","2",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If cos (x + 25)<sup>o<\/sup> = sin 45<sup>o<\/sup>, find the value of x","options":["20","30","45","60",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If 2<sup>n<\/sup> = 128, find the value of (2<sup>n - 1<\/sup>)(5<sup>n - 1<\/sup>)","options":["5(10<sup>6<\/sup>)","2(10<sup>6<\/sup>)","5(10<sup>5<\/sup>)","2(10<sup>5<\/sup>)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If x \\(\\alpha\\) (45 + \\(\\frac{1}{2}y\\)), which of the following is true>?","options":["x varies directly as y","x varies inversely as y","x is partly constant and partly varies as y","x vries jointly as 45 and directly as y",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{\\log \\sqrt{8}}{\\log 4 - \\log 2}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2} \\log 2\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\log 2\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A train travels 60km in M minutes. If its average speed is 400km per hour, find the value of M","options":["15","12","10","9",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"An arc of a circle, radius 14cm, is 18.33cm long. Calculate to the nearest degree, the angle which the arc subtends at the centre of the circle. [T = \\(\\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["11<sup>o<\/sup>","20<sup>o<\/sup>","22<sup>o<\/sup>","75<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"What is the length of an edge of a cube whose total surface area is X cm<sup>2<\/sup> and whose total surface area is \\(\\frac{X}{2}\\)cm<sup>3<\/sup>?","options":["3","6","9","12",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"XY is a chord of circle centre O and radius 7cm. The chord XY which is 8cm long subtends an angle of 120<sup>o<\/sup> at the centre of the circle. Calculate the perimeter of the minor segment. [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["14.67cm","22.67cm","29.33cm","37.33cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If p = \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) and \\(\\frac{1}{p - 1} = \\frac{2}{p + x}\\), find the value of x","options":["-2\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","-1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","2\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Find the quadratic equation whose roots are c and -c","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> - c<sup>2<\/sup> = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2cx = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2cx + c<sup>2<\/sup> = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2cx + c<sup>2<\/sup> = 0",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Solve the inequality 1 - 2x < - \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","options":["x < \\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","x < -\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","x > \\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","x >  -\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given the sets A = [2, 4, 6, 8] and B = [2, 3, 5, 9]. If a number is selected at random from set B, what is the probability that the number is prime?","options":["1","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given the sets A = [2, 4, 6, 8] and B = [2, 3, 5, 9]. If a number is picked at random from each of the two sets, what is the probability that their difference is odd?","options":["1","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","zero",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given the sets A = [2, 4, 6, 8] and B = [2, 3, 5, 9]. If a number is picked at random from each of the two sets, what is the probability that their difference is 6 or 7?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{256}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{16}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Find the mean deviation of these numbers 10, 12, 14, 15, 17, 19.","options":["2.5","2.6","2.7","2.8",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"In the diagram, PQRS is a rhombus. \/PR\/ = 10cm and \/QS\/ = 24cm. Calculate the perimeter of the rhombus","options":["34cm","52cm","56cm","96cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"In the diagram, find the size of the angle marked a<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["60<sup>o<\/sup>","80<sup>o<\/sup>","120<sup>o<\/sup>","160<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Twenty girls and y boys sat on an examination. The mean marks obtained by the girls and boys were 52 and 57 respectively. if the total score for both girls and boys was 2950, find y.","options":["51","48","30","25","18"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A sector of angle 120\u00b0 is cut out from a circle of radius 13.5cm. what area of the circle is remaining ? (\u03c0 = \\(\\frac{22}{7}\\))","options":["14.1cm<sup>2<\/sup>","95.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","190.9cm<sup>2<\/sup>","381.9cm<sup>2<\/sup>","763.7cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Two ladders of length 5m and 7m lean against a pole and make angles 45\u00b0 and 60\u00b0 with the ground respectively. What is their distance apart on the pole correct to two decimal places?","options":["9.60m","6.06m","2.54m","2.53m","2.00m"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The chances of Usman and Dele passing a Mathematics test are 12 and 13 respectively. What is the probability that neither of them passes the test?","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{15}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{15}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"x varies directly as y and inversely as z. when x = 5, y = 2 and z = 1. What is the value of x when y = 5 and z = 2?","options":["2.5","5","6.25","6.52","7.5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Find the mean deviation of 20, 25, 21, 27, 28, 29, to the nearest whole number","options":["2","3","4","5","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Calculate the area of a parallelogram whose diagonals are of length 8cm and 12cm and intersect at an angle of 135\u00b0","options":["271.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","135.8cm<sup>2<\/sup>","96.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","48.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","33.9cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The ratio of the base area of a hollow cone to that of its curved surface is 1:4. If its base radius is 7cm, calculate the slant height of the cone","options":["7cm","22cm","28cm","49cm","154cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Increase 135 in the ratio 3:5","options":["225","216","143","140","140"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Given that x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> + k = 60 and x = \\(\\sqrt{10}\\) when y = , find the value of k.","options":["56","34","32","-34","-56"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Find y if sin y = cos 48\u00b0","options":["21\u00b0","24\u00b0","42\u00b0","48\u00b0","102\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Simplify the expression: Log<sub>4<\/sub>16 + log<sub>3<\/sub>27 + log<sub>8<\/sub>4096","options":["-9","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{9}\\)","3","9"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The radii of two similar cylindrical jugs are in the ratio 3:7. Calculate the ratio of their volumes","options":["1 : 04","3 : 07","9 : 49","0.086111111","27 : 343"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A man travels at a rate of 25m\/sec. If he travels for 10\u00bdhrs, how many kilometres has he covered?","options":["262.5","945","970","995","1822.9"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The ages of Abu, Segun, Kofi and Funmi are 17 years, (2x -13) years, 14 years and 16 years respectively. What is the value of x if their mean ages is 17.5 years?","options":["18","23","25","36","70"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"2 bags of sugar at N<sub>x<\/sub> per bag are mixed with 3 bags of sugar at N<sub>y<\/sub> per bag. What is the cost in N of the mixture per bag?","options":["\\(\\frac{(2x + 3y)}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{(x + y)}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{x}{2} +\\frac{y}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{(x + y)}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{(3x + 2y)}{5}\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The ages of 10 students in a class are; 15, 16, 15.5, 17, 14.9, 14.5, 14.1, 15.1, 14.8. find the range of their ages.","options":["6.1","4.8","2.9","2.1","1.9"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If the 3rd and the 5th terms of an A.P are 6 and 10 respectively, find the 1st term and the common difference respectively.","options":["1, 2","2, 2","2, 3","3, 2","3,3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A pair of shoes was sold for N2,250.00 at a loss of 10%. What was the cost price?","options":["N750.00","N2,500.00","N2,538.00","N3,288.00","N4,038.00"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Find the coefficient of xy in the expansion of (x - 4y)(3x + 2y)","options":["14","12","10","-10","-12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Which of the following angular inequalities defines an obtuse angle?","options":["0\u00b0 < x < 90\u00b0","0\u00b0 \u2264 x > 180\u00b0","90\u00b0 < x < 180\u00b0","90\u00b0 \u2264 x < 180\u00b0","90\u00b0 > x < 180\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If y + \\(\\frac{1}{y}\\) = 9, evaluate y<sup>2<\/sup> +  \\(\\frac{1}{y^2}\\)","options":["27","38","54","63","79"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If N25,000.00 is kept in a bank at the rate of 2% simple interest, how much will it amount to at the end of 5 years?","options":["N2,500.00","N5,000.00","N12,500.00","N27,500.00","N125,000.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Construct a quadratic equation whose roots are -\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\) and 7","options":["3x<sup>2<\/sup> + 11x + 21 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 11x + 21 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x \u2013 21 = 0","3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x - 21 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x \u2013 21 = 0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A chord XY of a circle with centre O and radius 5.32cm has \u2220XOY = 140\u00b0. What is the length of the chord to the nearest centimetre?","options":["10cm","6cm","5cm","3cm","1cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Rationalize the expression \\(\\frac{(7 - \\sqrt{3})}{(13 - \\sqrt{3})}\\)","options":["(44 + 3\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)) \u00f7 83","(44 + 2\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)) \u00f7 83","(44 - 3\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)) \u00f7 83","(44 - 4\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)) \u00f7 83","(44 - 2\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)) \u00f7 83"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"In proving the congruence of two triangles, which of the following is not important?","options":["two sides and the included angles","two angles and a side","three sides","three angles","right angle, hypotenuse and another side"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Bello chooses a number randomly from 1 to 10. What is the probability that it is either odd or prime?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{10}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If tan \u03b1 = \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) and tan \u03b2 = \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) and both \u03b1 and \u03b2 are acute, find tan (\u03b1 + \u03b2).","options":["0.015","1","10","39.81","45"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Multiply (3\\(\\sqrt{a}\\) - 4a) by (4a + 3\\(\\sqrt{a}\\))","options":["9a + 16a<sup>2<\/sup>","9a \u2013 16a<sup>2<\/sup>","3a + 16a<sup>2<\/sup>","3a - 16a<sup>2<\/sup>","a - 16a<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The median of a distribution can be estimated from","options":["Barchart","Cumulative frequency curve","Frequency polygon","Pictorial","Pie chart"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If A = \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)h (a + b), make \u2018a\u2019 the subject of the formula","options":["(2A \u2013 2bh) \u00f7 b","(2A \u2013 bh) \u00f7 h","(2A \u2013 bh) \u00f7 b","(A \u2013 2bh) \u00f7 h","(2A \u2013 h) \u00f7 bh"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The graph of cumulative frequency distribution is known as","options":["an ogive","a histogram","a frequency polygon","relative frequency","none"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"T varies inversely as the square root of F when T = 7, F = 2\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\). Find T when F = \\(\\frac{27}{9}\\)","options":["1.5","6.3","6.3","12.6","21"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Evaluate (2<sup>5<\/sup> \u00d7 4<sup>-2<\/sup>) \u00f7 (2<sup>-3<\/sup> \u00d7 2<sup>6<\/sup>)","options":["9","8","3","\\(\\frac{8}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"If 5x - 3 = 4x - 7, what is the value 6x?","options":["24","6","4","-4","-24"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"which of the following properties is\/are common to parallelograms and rectangles?<br>\r\nI. all angles are right angles<br>\r\nII. the diagonals are equals. <br>\r\nIII. the opposite sides are equal and parallel.","options":["I and II","I and III","II and III","I","III"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"P = {x:(x - 2)(x + 3) (x - 4)(x + 5) = 0}. The elements in P are","options":["-5,-2, 3, 4","-5, -3, 2, 4","-5, -3, -2,4","-4, -3, -2, 5","2, 3, 4, 5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Find the value of log\\(_{\\sqrt{3}}\\) 81","options":["81","16","8","3","\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Evaluate \\((111_{two})^2\\) and leave your answer in base 2","options":["\\(111001_{two}\\)","\\(110001_{two}\\)","\\(101001_{two}\\)","\\(10010_{two}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Find the LCM of \\(2^{3}\\times 3\\times 5^{2}, 2\\times 3^{2}\\times 5 \\hspace{1mm}and \\hspace{1mm}2^{2}\\times 3^{2}\\times 5\\)","options":["\\(2^{2}\\times 3^{3}\\times 5^{2}\\)","\\(2^{3}\\times 3^{23}\\times 5\\)","\\(2^{2}\\times 3^{2}\\times 5^{2}\\)","\\(2^{3}\\times 3^{3}\\times 5^{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Simplify \\((0.3\\times 10^{5})\\div (0.4\\times 10^{7})\\)leaving your answer in standard form","options":["\\(7.5\\times 10^{-4}\\)","\\(7.5\\times 10^{-3}\\)","\\(7.5\\times 10^{-2}\\)","\\(7.5\\times 10^{-1}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If \\(p\\propto \\frac{1}{q}\\), which of the following is true?","options":["\\(\\propto p^{2}\\)","\\(p\\propto \\frac{1}{q^{2}}\\)","\\(q\\propto \\sqrt{p}\\)","\\(q\\propto \\frac{1}{p}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Simplify \\(3\\sqrt{45}-12\\sqrt{5}+16\\sqrt{20}\\)leaving your answer in surd form","options":["\\(29\\sqrt{5}\\)","\\(14\\sqrt{15}\\)","\\(12\\sqrt{15}\\)","\\(11\\sqrt{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Which of the following is true for the set \\(P = \\{-3.2\\leq x< 5\\}\\) where x is an integer","options":["least value of x is -3.2","least value of x is -3","greatest value of x is 4.9","greatest value of x is 5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Simplify\\(\\frac{3x^{3}}{(3x)^{3}}\\)","options":["1","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{27}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"N140,000 is shared between ABU, Kayode and Uche. Abu has twice as much as Kayode, and Kayode has twice as much as Uche. What is Kayode's share?","options":["N80,000","N40,000","N20,000","N10,000",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"I am x years old and my brother is 3 years older how old was my brother last year","options":["(x - 4) years","(x + 2) years","(3x - 1) years","(3x + 1) years",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"For what value of x is the expression \\(\\frac{2x-1}{x+3}\\)not defined?","options":["3","2","1\/2","-3",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If x =3, y = 2 and z = 4 what is the value of \\(3x^{2}-2y+z\\)","options":["17","27","35","71",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Solve the simultaneous equation: x+y=2 and 3x-2y=1","options":["x=2 and y=1","x=1 and y=1","x=1 and y=2","x=-1 and y=1",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If \\(8^{x+1}=\\frac{1}{4}\\), find x","options":["\\(-\\frac{5}{3}\\)","-1","\\(-\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The area of a square field is 110.25m<sup>2<\/sup>. Find the cost of fencing it round at N75.00 per meter square","options":["N1,575.00","N3,150.00","N4,734.30","N8,268.75",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A sector of a circle of radius 14cm containing an angle 60<sup>o<\/sup> is folded to form a cone. Calculate the radius of the base of the cone.","options":["\\(5\\frac{1}{2}cm\\)","\\(4\\frac{2}{3}cm\\)","\\(3\\frac{1}{2}cm\\)","\\(2\\frac{1}{3}cm\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Evaluate(111<sub>two<\/sub>)<sup>2<\/sup> and leave your answer in base 2.","options":["111001<sub>two<\/sub>","110001<sub>two<\/sub>","101001<sub>two<\/sub>","10010<sub>two<\/sub>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Find the LCM of 2<sup>3<\/sup> x 3 x 5<sup>2<\/sup>, 2 x 3<sup>2<\/sup> x 5 and 2<sup>3<\/sup> x 3<sup>3<\/sup> x 5","options":["2<sup>2<\/sup> x 3<sup>3<\/sup> x 5<sup>2<\/sup>","2<sup>3<\/sup> x 3<sup>3<\/sup> x 5","2<sup>2<\/sup> x 3<sup>2<\/sup> x 5<sup>2<\/sup>","2<sup>3<\/sup> x 3<sup>3<\/sup> x 5<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Simplify(0.3 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>) \\(\\div\\) (0.4 \\(\\times\\) 10<sup>7<\/sup>), leaving you answer in the standard form.","options":["7.5 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup>","7.5 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","7.5 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","7.5 x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If p \\(\\alpha \\frac{I}{Q}\\) which of the following is true?","options":["q \\(\\alpha p^2\\)","q \\(\\alpha \\frac{1}{p^2}\\)","q \\(\\alpha \\sqrt{p}\\)","q \\(\\alpha \\frac{1}{p}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Simplify 3\\(\\sqrt{45} - 12\\sqrt{15} + 16\\sqrt{20}\\), leaving your answer in surd form","options":["29\\(\\sqrt{5}\\)","14\\(\\sqrt{15}\\)","12\\(\\sqrt{15}\\)","11\\(\\sqrt{15}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Which of the following statement is true for the ste P = {-3.2 \\(\\leq\\) x < 5} where x is an integer?","options":["least value of x is -3.2","least value of x is -3","greatest value of x is 4.9","greatest value of x is 5",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{3x^3}{(3x)^3}\\)","options":["1","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{27}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"N140,000 is shared between Abu, Kayode and Uche. Abu has twice as much as Kayode and Kayode has twice as much as Uche. What is Kayode'sshare?","options":["N80,000","N40,000","N2,000","10,000",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"I am x years old and my brother is 3 years older. How old was my brother last year?","options":["(x - 4)years","(x + 2) years","(3x - 10years","(3x + 1)years",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"For what value of x is the expression \\(\\frac{2x - 1}{x + 3}\\) not defined?","options":["3","2","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","-3",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If x = 3, Y = 2 and z = 4, what is the value of 3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2y + z?","options":["17","27","35","71",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Solve the simultaneous equations x + y = 2 and 3x - 2y = 1","options":["x = 2 and y = 1","x = 1 and y = 1","x = 1 and y = 2","x = -1 and y = 1",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If 8<sup>x-1<\/sup> = \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\), find x","options":["-\\(\\frac{-5}{3}\\)","-1","-\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A chord of length 6cm is drawn in a circle of radius 5cm. Find the distance of the chord from the centre of the circle.","options":["2.5cm","3.0cm","3.5cm","4.0cm",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The area of a square field is 110.25m<sup>2<\/sup>. Find the cost of fencing it round at N75.00 per metre","options":["N1,575.00","N3,150.00","N4,734.30","N8,268.75",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A sector of a circle of radius 14cm containing an angle 60<sup>o<\/sup> is folded to form a cone. Calculate the radius of the base of the cone","options":["5\\(\\frac{1}{2}cm\\)","4\\(\\frac{2}{3}cm\\)","3\\(\\frac{1}{2}cm\\)","2\\(\\frac{1}{3}cm\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Find the volume of a solid cylinder with base radius 10cm and height 14cm.","options":["220<sup>3<\/sup>","880cm<sup>3<\/sup>>","1400cm<sup>3<\/sup>","4400cm<sup>3<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Each of the interior angle of a regular polygon is 162<sup>o<\/sup>. How many sides has the polygon?","options":["8","12","16","20",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"In a , < PQR = < PRQ = 45<sup>o<\/sup>. which of the following statements is\/are correct?  i. \\(\\bigtriangleup\\)PQR is an equalateral triangle  ii. \\(\\bigtriangleup\\)PQR is an isosceles triangle  iii. \\(\\bigtriangleup\\)PQR is a right-angled triangle","options":["ii only","i and ii only","ii and iii only","i and ii only",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The table above gives the distribution of the marks of a number of students in a test.<br>\r\n\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} Mark &1 & 2 & 3 & 4 & 5 & 6 \\\\ \\hline Frequency & 5 & 3 & 6 & 4 & 2 & 5\\end{array}\\), find the mode of the distribution.","options":["2","3","5","6",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If the probability of an event occurring is x, what is the probability of the event not occurring?","options":["1 - x","x - 1","0","\\(\\frac{1}{x}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The table shows the ages(in years) of twenty children chosen at random from a community. What is the mean age? \\(\\begin{array}{c|c} Age(years) & 1 & 2 & 3 & 4 & 5 \\\\ \\hline {\\text {Number of children}} & 2 & 3 & 5 & 6 & 4 \\end{array}\\)","options":["4.46 years","3.35 years","3.30years","3.00 years",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The table shows the ages(in years) of twenty children chosen at random from a community. What is the median of the distribution? \\(\\begin{array}{c|c} Age(years) & 1 & 2 & 3 & 4 & 5 \\\\ \\hline {\\text {Number of children}} & 2 & 3 & 5 & 6 & 4 \\end{array}\\)","options":["3.5 years","3.0 years","2.5 years","2.0 years",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Divide the sum of 8, 6, 7, 2, 0, 4, 7, 2, 3, by their mean","options":["9","8","7","6",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Q is 32 km away from P on a bearing 042<sup>o<\/sup> and R is 25km from P on a bearing of 132<sup>o<\/sup>. Calculate the bearing of R from Q.","options":["122<sup>o<\/sup>","184<sup>o<\/sup>","190<sup>o<\/sup>","226<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The bearing of a point P from another point Q is 310<sup>o<\/sup>. If |PQ| = 200m, how far west of Q is P?","options":["128.6m","153.2m","167.8m","187.9m",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Find the value of a if log<sub>10<\/sub> a<sup>2<\/sup> + log<sub>10<\/sub>a<sup>2<\/sup> = 0.9030","options":["4.0","2.0","1.6","0.0",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A messenger was paid N2.50 an hour during the normal working hours and 4.00 n hour during overtime. If he received N31.00 for 10 hours work, how many hours are for overtime?","options":["2","3","4","6",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"At what rate per cent per annum will N520.00 yield a simple interest of N39.00 in three years?","options":["4%","3\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)%","3%","2\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)%",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"PQR is an equilateral triangle with sides 2\\(\\sqrt{3cm}\\). calculate its height","options":["1.7cm","3.0cm","3.2cm","3.9cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Which of the following is a factor of 2 - x - x<sup>2<\/sup>?","options":["1 - x","1 + x","x - 1","2 - x",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"make w the subject of the relation \\(\\frac{a + bc}{wd + f}\\) = g","options":["\\(\\frac{a + bc - fg}{dg}\\)","\\(\\frac{a - bc + fg}{dg}\\)","\\(\\frac{a + bc - f}{dg}\\)","\\(\\frac{a + bc - dg}{dg}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"For what range of values of x is 4x - 3(2x - 1) > 1?","options":["x > -1","x > 1","x < 1","x < -1",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Find the smallest value of k such that 2<sup>2<\/sup> x 3<sup>2<\/sup> 5 x k is a perfect square","options":["3","5","15","30",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Expand the expression(3a - xy)(3a + xy)","options":["9a<sup>2<\/sup> - x<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>2<\/sup>","9a<sup>2<\/sup> + x<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>2<\/sup>","9a<sup>2<\/sup> - xy","9a<sup>2<\/sup> + x<sup>2<\/sup>y",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{4}{2x} - \\frac{2x + x}{x}\\)","options":["-1","-2x","2x","\\(\\frac{2 - x}{2x}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Two circles have radii 16cm and 23cm. What is the difference between their circumference? take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)","options":["422.92cm","149.92cm","44.00cm","43.96cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The volume of a cylinder is 1200cm<sup>3<\/sup> and the area of its base is 1500cm<sup>2<\/sup>. Find the height of the cylinder.","options":["80.00cm","8.00cm","0.80cm","0.08cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"If the ratio x:y = 3:5 and y:z = 4:7, find the ratio x:y:z","options":["15 : 28 : 84","12 : 20 : 35","3 : 5 : 4","5 : 4 : 7",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"In the diagram, O is the centre of the circle and < PQR = 106<sup>o<\/sup>, find the value of y","options":["16","37","74","127",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Find the product of 0.0409 and 0.0021 leaving your answer in the standard form","options":["8.6 x 10<sup>-6<\/sup>","8.6 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>","8.6 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup>","8.6 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Convert 42<sub>5<\/sub> to base three numeral","options":["201<sub>3<\/sub>","210<sub>3<\/sub>","211<sub>3<\/sub>","343<sub>3<\/sub>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Evaluate (0.13)\\(^3\\)correct to three significant figures","options":["0.00219","0.00220","0.00300","0.00390",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Simplify: 11011\\(_2\\)  - 1101\\(_2\\)","options":["101000\\(_2\\)","1100\\(_2\\)","1110\\(_2\\)","1011\\(_2\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{25 \\frac{2}{3} \\div 25 \\frac{1}{6}}{( \\frac{1}{5})^{-\\frac{7}{6}} \\times ( \\frac{1}{5})^{\\frac{1}{6}}}\\)","options":["25","\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","1","\\(\\frac{1}{25}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{x - 4}{4} - \\frac{x - 3}{6}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x - 18}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 6}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 18}{24}\\)","\\(\\frac{x - 6}{24}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Given that y = 1 - \\(\\frac{2x}{4x - 3}\\), find the value of x for which y is undefined","options":["3","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{-3}{4}\\)","-3",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"P is a point on the same plane with a fixed point A. If P moves such that it is always equidistant from A, the locus of P is","options":["a straight line joining A and P","the perpendicular bisector of AP","a circle with centre A","the triangle with centre P",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A fair coin is tossed three times. Find the probability of getting two heads and one tail.","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{8}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If 30% of y is equal to x, what in terms of x, is 30% of 3y?","options":["\\(\\frac{x}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{x}{3}\\)","x","3x",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A baker used 40% of a 50kg bag of flour. If \\(\\frac{1}{8}\\) of the amount used was for the cake, how many kilogram of flour was used for the cake?","options":["2\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","6\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","15\\(\\frac{3}{8}\\)","17\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If tan y = 0.404, where y is acute, find cos 2y","options":["0.035","0.719","0.808","0.927",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The ratio of boys to girls in a class is 5:3. Find the probability of selecting at random, a girl from the class","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} x & 1 & 4 & p \\\\ \\hline y & 0.5 & 1 & 2.5\\end{array}\\). The table above satisfies the relation  y = k\\(\\sqrt{x}\\), where k is a positive constant. Find the value of K.","options":["0.5","1","1.5","2",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"\\(\\begin{array}{c|c} x & 1 & 4 & p \\\\ \\hline y & 0.5 & 1 & 2.5\\end{array}\\). The table below satisfies the relation  y - k\\(\\sqrt{x}\\), where k is a positive constant. Find the value of P,","options":["2","4","10","25",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"What must be added to x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x to make it a perfect square?","options":["\\(\\frac{9}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{2}\\)","6","9",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Given that (2x - 1)(x + 5) = 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - mx - 5, what is the value of m","options":["11","5","-9","-10",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"What is the place value of 9 in the number 3.0492?","options":["\\(\\frac{9}{10000}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{1000}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{100}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{10}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If the simple interest on a sum of money invested at 3% per annum for 2\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) years is N123, find the principal.","options":["N676.50","N820","N1,640","N4,920",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A machine valued at N20,000 depreciates by 10% every year. What will be the value of the machine at the end of two years?","options":["N16,200","N1,4,200","12,000","8000.",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If 2x + y = 10, and y \\(\\neq\\) 0, which of the following is not a possible value of x?","options":["4","5","8","10",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If x + y = 12 and 3x - y = 20, find the value of 2x - y","options":["8","10","12","15",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If log<sub>a<\/sub>270 - log<sub>a<\/sub>10 + log<sub>a<\/sub> \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) = 2, what is the value of a?","options":["3","4","5","6",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"a conical water-jug is 7cm in diameter and 6cm deep. find the volume of water it can hold. [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["22cm<sup>2<\/sup>","44cm<sup>3<\/sup>","77cm<sup>3<\/sup>","308<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If p = [\\(\\frac{Q(R - T)}{15}\\)]\\(^ \\frac{1}{3}\\), make T the subject of the relation","options":["T = R + \\(\\frac{P^3}{15Q}\\)","T = R - \\(\\frac{15P^3}{Q}\\)","T = R + \\(\\frac{P^3}{15Q}\\)","T = 15R - \\(\\frac{Q}{P^3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A seller allows 20% discount for cash payment on the marked price of his goods. What is the ratio of the cash payment to the marked price","options":["1:4","1:5","3:4","4:5",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The wheel of a tractor has a diameter 1.4m. What distance does it cover in 100 complete revolutions? [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["140m","220m","280m","440m",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"If p = {1, 3, 5, 7, 9} and Q = {2, 4, 6, 8, 10} are subsets of a universal set. U = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10}. What are the elements of P<sup>1<\/sup> \\(\\cap\\) Q<sup>1<\/sup>?","options":["{1, 3, 5, 7, 9}","[2, 4, 6, 8, 10}","\\(\\varnothing\\)","{1, 2, 6, 8, 10}",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The values of three angles at a point are 3y - 45<sup>o<\/sup>, y + 25<sup>o<\/sup> and y<sup>o<\/sup> . Find the value of y.","options":["40<sup>o<\/sup>","58<sup>o<\/sup>","68<sup>o<\/sup>","76<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A rectangular carpet 2.5m long and 2.4m wide covers 5% of a rectangular floor. Calculate the area of the floor","options":["30m<sup>2<\/sup>","57m<sup>2<\/sup>","120m<sup>2<\/sup>","225m<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a measure of centre tendency?","options":["mean","mode","range","median",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The temperature in a chemical plant was -5<sup>o<\/sup>C at 2.00 am. The temperature fell by 6<sup>o<\/sup>C and then rose again by 7<sup>o<\/sup>C. What was the final temperature?","options":["-6<sup>o<\/sup>C","-4<sup>o<\/sup>C","4<sup>o<\/sup>C","8<sup>o<\/sup>C",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{20}{5\\sqrt{28} - 2 \\sqrt{63}}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{5\\sqrt{7}}{7}\\)","\\(\\frac{5\\sqrt{5}}{7}\\)","\\(\\frac{7\\sqrt{5}}{7}\\)","\\(\\frac{7\\sqrt{7}}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A ladder 16m long leans against an electric pole. If the ladder makes an angle of 65<sup>o<\/sup> with the ground, how far up the electric pole does its top reach","options":["6.8m","14.5m","17.7m","34.3m",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Correct 0.04945 to two significant figures","options":["0.040","0.049","0.050","0.49",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{5}{\\sqrt{3}}-\\frac{3}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{6}(5\\sqrt{3}-3\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}(15\\sqrt{3}-6\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}(3\\sqrt{2}-\\sqrt{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}(10\\sqrt{3}-9\\sqrt{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Evaluate, correct to the nearest whole number \\(7\\frac{1}{2}-\\left(2\\frac{1}{2}+3\\right)\\div\\frac{33}{2}\\)","options":["33","8","7","o",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Simplify the expression \\(log_{10}18 - log_{10}2.88+log_{10}16\\)","options":["31.12","3.112","2","1",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Find the equation whose roots are 2 and \\(-3\\frac{1}{2}\\)","options":["2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 3x + 14 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 5x + 7 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 5x - 7 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 3x - 14 = 0",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A man bought 220 mangoes at N5x. He sold each for 3x kobo and made a gain of N8. Find the value of x","options":["2","5","6","10",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A fair die is tossed once, what is the probability of obtaining neither 5 or 2","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Convert 101101<sub>two<\/sub> to a number in base ten","options":["61","46","45","44",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Solve the equation \\(2^7 = 8^{5-x}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{8}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{15}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"expand (2x-3y)(x-5y)","options":["\\(2x^2 + 13xy - 15y^2\\)","\\(2x^2 - 13xy - 15y^2\\)","\\(2x^2 + 13xy + 15y^2\\)","\\(2x^2 - 13xy + 15y^2\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Make f the subject of the relation \\(v = u + ft\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{v-u}{t}\\)","\\(\\frac{u-v}{t}\\)","\\(t(v+u\\)","\\(\\frac{v}{u}-t\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The lengths of the adjacent sides of a right - angled triangle are xcm, (x-1)cm. If the length of the hypotenuse is \\(\\sqrt{13}cm\\), find the value of x","options":["2","3","4","5",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The probability that John and James pass an examination are 3\/4 and 3\/5 respectively, find the probability f both boys failing the examination","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{20}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{20}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"What is the diameter of a circle of area 77cm<sup>2<\/sup> [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{2}}{7}cm\\)","\\(3\\frac{1}{2}cm\\)","7cm","\\(7\\sqrt{2}cm\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Solve the equation 2x - 3y = 22; 3x + 2y = 7","options":["-5","-4","4","5",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Solve the equation \\(\\frac{2y-1}{3} - \\frac{3y-1}{4} = 1\\)","options":["-8","-13","13","19",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If \\(log_9x= 1.5\\),find x","options":["36","27","24.5","13.5",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A sequence is given by \\(2\\frac{1}{2}, 5, 7\\frac{1}{2}, .....\\) if the nth term is 25, find n","options":["9","10","12","15",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Given that the root of an the equation \\(2x^2 + (k+2)x+k=0\\) is 2, find the value of k","options":["-4","-2","-1","\\(-\\frac{1}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Find the mean of the numbers 1, 3, 4, 8, 8, 4 and 7","options":["4","5","6","7",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"What is the total surface area of a closed cylinder of height 10cm and diameter 7cm? [Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["77cm<sup>2<\/sup>","227cm<sup>2<\/sup>","297cm<sup>2<\/sup>","374cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"An arc of a circle of radius 14cm subtends angle 300<sup>o<\/sup> at the center. Find the perimeter of the sector formed by the arc","options":["14.67cm","42.67cm","101.33cm","543.33cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"which of the following statements describes the locus of a point R which moves in a plane such that its equidistant from two intersecting lines?","options":["the bisector of the angle formed by the lines","the point of intersection of the two lines","A cone, with two intersecting lines as slant height","A circle, with the point of intersection of the two lines as the center",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"P = {3, 9, 11, 13} and Q = {3, 7, 9, 15} are subset of the universal set \u03be = {1, 3, 7, 9, 11, 13, 15} find P<sup>I<\/sup> \u2229 Q<sup>I<\/sup>","options":["{3, 9}","{5, 7, 9}","{1}","{1, 11}",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A train moving at a uniform speed covers 36km in 21 minutes. How long does it take to cover 60km?","options":["35 mins","40 mins","45 mins","90 mins",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The salary of a man was increased in the ratio 40:47. calculate the percentage increase in the salary","options":["85.1%","58.5%","17.5%","14.9%",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A regular polygon has 9 sides. What is the size of one of its exterior angles?","options":["20<sup>o<\/sup>","40<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup>","140<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Simplify: \\(\\frac{2}{3xy} - \\frac{3}{yz}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{2-x}{12xyz}\\)","\\(\\frac{2z-3x}{12xyz}\\)","\\(\\frac{4z-3x}{12xyz}\\)","\\(\\frac{8z-9x}{12xyz}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The total surface area of the walls of a room 7m long, 5m wide and xm high is 96m<sup>2<\/sup>. Find the value of x","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","2","4","8",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"For what values of y is the expression \\(\\frac{6y-1}{y^2 - y-6}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{6}, \\frac{1}{4}\\)","3, -2","-3, 2","0,1",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The angle of elevation of the top of a cliff 15 meters high from a landmark is 60<sup>o<\/sup>. How far is the landmark from the foot of the cliff? Leave your answer in surd form","options":["\\(15\\sqrt{3}m\\)","\\(15\\sqrt{2}m\\)","\\(10\\sqrt{3}m\\)","\\(5\\sqrt{3}m\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"XOY is a real sector of a circle center O of radius 3.5cm which subtends an angle of 144<sup>o<\/sup> at the center. Calculate, in term of \u03d6, the area of the sector","options":["1.4\u03d6cm<sup>2<\/sup>","2.8\u03d6cm<sup>2<\/sup>","4.9\u03d6cm<sup>2<\/sup>","9.8\u03d6cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A rectangular packet has inner dimension 16cm by 12cm by 6cm. How many cubes of sugar of side 2cm can be neatly packed into the packet?","options":["90","144","150","288",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If \\(y \\alpha \\frac{1}{x^2}\\) and \\(y = 1\\frac{1}{4}\\) when x = 4, find the value of y when \\(x = \\frac{1}{2}\\)","options":["\\(2\\frac{1}{2}\\)","5","10","80",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Ladi sold  a car for N84,000 at a loss of 4%. How much did ladi buy the car","options":["80,500","80,640","87,360","87,500",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The monthly salary of a man increased from N2,700 to N3,200. Find the percentage increase","options":["10%","15%","15.6%","18.5%",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The diagonals of a rhombus are 6cm and 8cm. Find the area of the rhombus.","options":["96cm<sup>2<\/sup>","48cm<sup>2<\/sup>","24cm<sup>2<\/sup>","0.14cm<sup>2<\/sup>","12cm2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Mohammed is 8 years older than Joy now. In five years\u2019 time he will be twice as old as Joy. How old is Joy now?","options":["1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)years","3years","4\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)years","6 years","8 years"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If (x - a) is a factor of bx - ax + x<sup>2<\/sup> - ab, what is the other factor?","options":["(x + b)","(b - a)","(x - a)","(a + b)","(a - b)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Simplify (6 - x - x<sup>2<\/sup>) \u00f7 (x<sup>2<\/sup> - 4)","options":["(3 + x) \u00f7 (x + 2)","(x - 3) \u00f7 (x - 2)","(x - 3) \u00f7 (x + 3)","(3 - x) \u00f7 (x + 2)","(3 - x) \u00f7 (x - 2)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Find the absolute mean deviation of the sample 10, 12, 14, 11, 13.","options":["14.6","14","12","6.2","1.2"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"In \u0394 ABC, A = 60\u00b0, C = 90\u00b0 and AC = 12m. Find the Length of the hypotenuse.","options":["24m","14m","12m","7m","6m"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"For what value(s) of x is the expression (x<sup>2<\/sup> + 15x + 50) \u00f7 (x - 5) not defined","options":["-5, -10","-10","-5","5","10, 5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Evaluate log 18 + log<sup>6<\/sup> - log16\\(^{\\frac{1}{2}}\\)","options":["log 3","log 9","log 20","3 log 2","3 log 3"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A bag contains 4 blue and 8 red identical balls. If two balls are picked at random with replacement, what is the probability of picking two balls of different colours?","options":["1","\\(\\frac{13}{26}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{9}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A car dealer sells a car and makes a profit of 15%. If the car costs N320,000.00, how much did he sell the car?","options":["N272,000.00","N296,000.00","N300,000.00","N368,000.00","N400,000.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If A(I,2,3,...,10) ; B = (-5,-4,.....,-1) ; C = (-1, 0, 1, 2,....5) List all the elements in (B \u222a C) \u2229 A","options":["(-1,2,...5)","(-1,1,....5)","(1,2,..5)","(2,3,...10)","(1,2,...10)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"What is the positive difference between the squares of 2.5 and 2.1 to 1 significant figures?","options":["\u2013 2.0","\u2013 184","-1.84","2","18.4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Find the value of 2a - b if a + b = 8 and 4a - b = 22","options":["2","4","6","8","10"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A flagpole is placed at the top of a tower. The angles of elevation of the bottom and top of the flagpole from a point on the ground 10m away are 40\u00b0 and 50\u00b0 respectively. Find the length of the flagpole.","options":["1.8m","3.5m","8.4m","11.9m","17.3m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Find the Iength of a diagonal of a square whose area is 288cm<sup>2<\/sup>.","options":["24cm","48cm","95cm","100cm","124cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Solve for x in the quadratic equation. 2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 12x + 10 = 0","options":["x = -5, -1","x = -5,1","x = -3, -2","x = 3, 2","x = 6, 5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A surveyor measured the length of a obtained 42.55 metres. If his measurement was more than the actual length and the percentage error of his measurement was 8%, calculate the actual length of the land","options":["39.40 metres","46.20 metres","46.25 metres","46.50 metres","48.25 metres"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If x + \\(\\frac{1}{x}\\) = 8, find x<sup>2<\/sup> + \\(\\frac{1}{x^2}\\)","options":["64","62","32","16","4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Evaluate 0.0025 \u00d7 2.5 \u00d7 102 to 2 significant figures.","options":["0.625 \u00d7 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","0.63 \u00d7 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","6.25 \u00d7 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","6.3 \u00d7 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","6.3 \u00d7 10<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"What is the Value Of 11101\\(_{two}\\)+ 10011\\(_{two}\\) - 10001\\(_{two}\\)","options":["10001\\(_{two}\\)","10011\\(_{two}\\)","10111\\(_{two}\\)","11111\\(_{two}\\)","111111\\(_{two}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A ship sails 6km from a port on a bearing 070\u00b0 and then 8km on a bearing of 040\u00b0. Find the distance from the port.","options":["7.21km","13.53km","16.86km","44.57km","67.17km"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Calculate without using tables Tan 45\u00b0 + Cos 60\u00b0","options":["\\(\\sqrt{\\frac{3}{2}}\\) - 1","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{\\frac{3}{2}}\\) + 1","2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A is at 50\u00b0N and B is at 10\u00b0N, If A and B are on the same longitude, find the distance AS. Correct your answer to Four significant figures. (Earth radius = 6400km)","options":["6468km","5469km","4470km","3470km","2488km"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If a = {x : 1 < x < 9} ; b = {x : 0 < x < 9} ; C = {x : 2 x < 9} and a, b, c U, what are the elements in U?","options":["U = {-1 < x < 9}","U = {0 < x < 9}","U = {1 < x < 9}","U = {1 < x < 10}","{2 < x < 10}"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If log 3 = 0.4771 and log 2 = 0.3010, what is the value of log 12?","options":["0.0432","0.4322","1.0791","1.2552","1.5225"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If 7 is subtracted from twice a certain number x, the result is at most 5. What is the range of the number?","options":["x < 2","x < 3","x < 4","x < 5","x < 6"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Find the standard deviation of the numbers 6, 9, 10, 8 and 7","options":["1.4","2","2.4","5","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Simplify P<sup>-6<\/sup> \u00d7 P<sup>3<\/sup> \u00d7 P<sup>2<\/sup> \u00f7 P<sup>4<\/sup> \u00d7 P<sup>0<\/sup>","options":["p<sup>5<\/sup>","p<sup>4<\/sup>","p<sup>3<\/sup>","p<sup>-3<\/sup>","p<sup>-5<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"3 - 7, 8 - 12, 13 - 17, 18 - 22. Which of the following is\/are true? <br>\r\nI. The class Interval is 4 <br>\r\nII. The class boundaries are 2.5, 7.5, 12.5, 18.5, 22.5 <br>\r\nIII. The mid-marks are 5, 10, 15, and 20","options":["I only","II only","III only","I and II only","II and III only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"T varies directly as D and inversely as A. Given that T = 6, D = 3, and A = 2, find A when T = 3 and D = 6.","options":["4","6","8","12","24"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A chord 20cm long subtends an angle of 60\u00b0 at the circumference of a circle, what is the diameter of the circle the nearest cm?","options":["12cm","20cm","23cm","60cm","80cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If 25a<sup>2<\/sup>  = 5<sup>-1<\/sup>  \u00d7 125. Find the value of a?","options":["a = -1","a = 1","a = \u00b11","a = \u00b15","a = 25"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The parallel sides of a trapezium are 13cm and 7cm. If the area of the trapezium is 50cm2, find the perpendicular distance between the parallel sides.","options":["5cm","6cm","7cm","10cm","12cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Two fair dice are tossed together once. What is the probability of getting a total of at least 9 from the outcome?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{18}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If 2x : ( x + 1) = 3 : 2, what is the value of x?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","1","1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","3","3\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"If y<sup>2<\/sup>+ 14y + k is a perfect square, then k =","options":["4","7","28","49","196"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"1. Evaluate \\( 202^2_{three} - 112^2_{three}\\)","options":["21120","21121","21112","21011",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If \\(y = 23_{five} + 101_{three}\\), find y, leaving your answer in base two","options":["1110","10111","11101","111100",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given that sin (5x - 28)<sup>o<\/sup> = cos (3x - 50)<sup>o<\/sup>,0 < x < 90<sup>o<\/sup>, find the value of x","options":["14<sup>o<\/sup>","21<sup>o<\/sup>","32<sup>o<\/sup>","39<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Solve for t in the equation \\(\\frac{3}{4}t+\\frac{1}{3}(21-t)\\) = 11,","options":["\\(\\frac{9}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{5}\\)","5","\\(9\\frac{3}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A school girl spends \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\) of her pocket money on books and \\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) on dress. What fraction remains?","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"There are m boys and 12 girls in a class. What is the probability of selecting at random a girl from the class?","options":["\\(\\frac{m}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{12}{m}\\)","\\(\\frac{12}{m+12}\\)","\\(\\frac{12}{m-12}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Simplify \\(7\\frac{1}{2}-\\left(2\\frac{1}{2}+3\\right)\\div16\\frac{1}{2}\\)and correct your answer to the nearest whole number","options":["33","8","7","o",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given that x + y = 7 and 3x-y = 5, evaluate \\(\\frac{y}{2}-3\\).","options":["-1","1","3","4",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If \\(\\left(\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{(2-y)}\\), find y.","options":["-2","\\(-\\frac{1}{2}\\).","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","2",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Calculate the total surface area of a cupboard which measures 12cm by 10cm by 8cm","options":["1920cm<sup>2<\/sup>","592cm<sup>2<\/sup>","296cm<sup>2<\/sup>","148cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{x}{a+1}+\\frac{y}{b}\\) 1. Make y the subject of the relation","options":["\\(\\frac{b(a-x+1)}{a+1}\\)","\\(\\frac{a+1}{b(a-x+1)}\\)","\\(\\frac{a(b-x+1)}{b+1}\\)","\\(\\frac{b}{a(b-x+1)}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"lf \\(log^p_p= r\\), express p in terms of q and r","options":["p =qr","p =r<sup>q<\/sup>","\\(p = \\frac{r}{q}\\)","p=q<sup>r<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the next two terms of the sequence<br>\r\n1, 5, 14, 30, 50 ....,. ,","options":["61,110","67,116","81,140","91, 140",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Each interior angle of a regular polygon is 108<sup>o<\/sup>. How many sides has it?","options":["5","7","9","14",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Solve the equation 10-3x-x<sup>2<\/sup> = 0","options":["x=2 or-5","x= -2 or 5","x = 1 or 10","x = 2 or 5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find, correct to two decimal places, the mean of<br>\r\n9, 13, 16, 17, 19, 23, 24.","options":["23.00","17.29","16.50","16.33",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Factorise 27p<sup>2<\/sup>x<sup>2<\/sup> - 48y<sup>2<\/sup>.","options":["9(3px - 4y)<sup>2<\/sup>","3(3px - 4y)(3px - 4y)","9(px - 4y)(3p x + 4y)","3(3px -4y)(3px +4y)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"What is the volume of a solid cylinder of diameter 7cm and height 7cm? (Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\))","options":["38.5cm<sup>3<\/sup>","77cm<sup>3<\/sup>","269.5cm<sup>3<\/sup>","1078cm<sup>3<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the sum of the roots of the equation 2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 3x - 9 = 0","options":["-18","-6","\\(-\\frac{9}{2}\\)","\\(-\\frac{3}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given that \u03be = {1, 2, 3, . . . . . . ,10}, P= (x : x is prime) and Q = {y : y is odd}, find P<sup>l<\/sup>\u2229Q","options":["{2}","{1,9}","{315.7}","{4, 6, 8, 10}",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the mean deviation of 6, 7, 8, 9, 10","options":["1.2","1.5","2","8",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A point X is on the bearing 342<sup>o<\/sup> from a point Y. What is the bearing of Y from X?","options":["342<sup>o<\/sup>","252<sup>o<\/sup>","198<sup>o<\/sup>","162<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the average of the first four prime numbers greater than10","options":["20","19","17","15",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given that \\(\\sqrt{128}+\\sqrt{18}-\\sqrt{k}\\), find K,","options":["8","16","32","48",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the range of values of x for which\\(\\frac{x+2}{4}-\\frac{x+1}{3}>\\frac{1}{2}\\)","options":["x > 4","x > -4","x < 4","x < -4",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A boy walks 800m in 20 minutes. Calculate his average speed in km per hour","options":["2.4","4","16","24",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{2}{a+b}-\\frac{1}{a-b}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{a+b}\\)","\\(\\frac{a-3b}{a^2-b^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{3a-b}{a^2 \u2013 b^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{a-3b}{a^2+b^2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Which of the following quadratic equations has \\(-\\frac{1}{2}\\) and \\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)  as its roots?","options":["8x<sup>2<\/sup> + 11x - 3 = 0","8x<sup>2<\/sup> -11x \u2013 3 = 0","8x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x -3 = 0","8x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x \u2013 3 = 0",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The locus of a point which moves in a plane such that it is equidistant from two fixed points X and Y is","options":["the perpendicular bisector of the line segment X Y","a line parallel to the line segment XY","a circle with XY as diameter","the line perpendicular to the line segment XY",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given that \\(P\\propto \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{r}}\\) and p = 3 when r = 16, find the value of r when p =-5","options":["48","64","72","324",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Which of the following is\/are true?  In a plane, the locus of points I. Equidistant from a straight line is a circle radius d where d is the distance between the point and the straight line.<br>\r\nII Equidistant from two given points P and Q is a circle of radius |PQ|. III Equidistant from two points is the perpendicular bisector of the line joining the two points.","options":["I only","II only","III only","I, II and III",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The sides of two cubes are in the ratio 215. What is the ratio of their volumes?","options":["4:5","8: 15","6:125","8:125",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Given that p = 2, q = -5 and r = - 4, evaluate 3p<sup>2<\/sup> - q<sup>2<\/sup> - r<sup>3<\/sup>","options":["101","77","51","-27",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A Cooperative Society, charges an interest of 5<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>% per annum on any amount borrowed by its members. If a member borrows N125,000, how much does he pay back after one year?","options":["N136875","N131,875","N126750","N126250",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A bag contains 3 red and 2 white identical balls. lf 2 balls are picked at random from the bag, one after the other and with replacement, find the probability that they are of different colours","options":["\\(\\frac{36}{625}\\)","\\(\\frac{16}{625}\\)","\\(\\frac{12}{25}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{25}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the surface area of a sphere whose radius is 3.5cm, correct your answer to one decimal place (\u03c0 = \\(\\frac{22}{5}\\))","options":["12.8cm<sup>2<\/sup>","25.7cm<sup>2<\/sup>","77.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","154.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","179.7cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Two angles of a triangle are 450 each and its longest side is 12cm. Find the length of one of the other sides","options":["12cm","9\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)cm","6\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)cm","6cm","3\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The nth term of a sequence is given as 4 x 3(3 - n). Calculate the third term.","options":["12","32","4","3","1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If y varies inversely as x<sup>2<\/sup>, how does x vary with y?","options":["x varies inversely as y<sup>2<\/sup>","x varies inversely as \\(\\sqrt{y}\\)","x varies directly as y<sup>2<\/sup>","x varies directly as \\(\\sqrt{y}\\)","x varies directly as y"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(1011_{two}\\) + \\(1101_{two}\\) + \\(1001_{two}\\) - \\(111_{two}\\)","options":["10001\\(_{two}\\)","11001\\(_{two}\\)","110001\\(_{two}\\)","10010\\(_{two}\\)","10001\\(_{two}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the area of a triangle ABC such that a = 16cm, b = 14cm, c = 12cm, leave your answer in surd form","options":["5\\(\\sqrt{15}\\)cm<sup>2<\/sup>","7\\(\\sqrt{15}\\)cm<sup>2<\/sup>","21\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)cm<sup>2<\/sup>","21\\(\\sqrt{5}\\)cm<sup>2<\/sup>","21\\(\\sqrt{15}\\)cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If the first term of an AP is 1.2 and the common difference is also 2, what is the mean of the first five terms?","options":["2","4","6","8","10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The angle subtended by a diameter of a circle at the circumference is a\/an","options":["acute angle","obtuse angle","reflex angle","right angle","supplementary angle"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Calculate (0.05 \u00d7 0.025) \u00f7 (4.25 \u00d7 3.35) and express your answer in standard form","options":["8.7796 \u00d7 10<sup>5<\/sup>","8.7796 \u00d7 10<sup>4<\/sup>","8.7796 \u00d7 10<sup>3<\/sup>","8.7796 \u00d7 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","8.7796 \u00d7 10<sup>-5<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The expression 4x<sup>2<\/sup> - 4 has the following as its factors EXCEPT","options":["x - 1","x + 1","x<sup>2<\/sup> -1","4x + 1","4x - 4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Simplify (216\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\))<sup>-2<\/sup>","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{36}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Divide the LCM of 15abc and 20a<sup>2<\/sup>bc by their HCF","options":["10a","12a","5abc","12a<sup>2<\/sup>bc","60a<sup>2<\/sup>bc"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The first term of an A.P is equal to thrice the common difference, what is the sixth term of the A.P, if the common difference is 8?","options":["64","48","43","24","11"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Solve the equation: \\(\\frac{3}{[2(x - 2)]} - \\frac{2}{[3(2 - x)]} = 0\\)","options":["3","2","\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","-3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A car travels at an average speed of 75km\/h. Find its speed in metres per second.","options":["270m\/s","208m\/s","27.0m\/s","20.8m\/s","2.08m\/s"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"What must be added to b<sup>2<\/sup>-3ab to make it a perfect square?","options":["-3a","-\\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{9a}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{9^2}{4}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A sales boy gave a change of N75.00 to a buyer instead of N80.00, calculate his percentage error, correct to one decimal place?","options":["6.00%","6.20%","6.30%","6.60%","6.70%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Evaluate (Log<sub>13<\/sub> - log<sub>5<\/sub>) \u00f7 X(log<sub>5<\/sub>-log<sub>13<\/sub>) without using tables","options":["X","\u2013x","X-1","\u2013X<sup>-1<\/sup>","-1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The roots of a quadratic equation in x, are -m and 2n. Fine equation.","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> - x(2n-m) \u2013 2mn = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + x(2n - m) - 2mn = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + x(m - 2n) + 2mn = 0","X<sup>2<\/sup> + x (m + 2n ) + 2mn = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - x (m - 2n) - 2mn = 0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The bearing of Y from X is 0850. What is the bearing of X from Y?","options":["005\u00b0","095\u00b0","185\u00b0","265\u00b0","275\u00b0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Four pupils have an average age of 12years and two other pupils of average age of 10.5years are added. What is the average age of the six pupils?","options":["10.5yrs.","11yrs.","11.5 yrs.","12yrs.","12.5yrs."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A bag contains p dozens of bananas and 3q of these proved to be bad. If I buy one third of the goods ones, how many do I get?","options":["P -3q","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) (p - 3q)","3q","4p - q","12p - 3q"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If log<sub>10<\/sub><sup>2<\/sup> = 0.3010 and log<sub>10<\/sub><sup>3<\/sup> = 0.4771, simplify: (Log<sub>10<\/sub><sup>8<\/sup>-log<sub>9<\/sub><sup>2<\/sup>) \u00f7 (Log<sub>10<\/sub><sup>9<\/sup> - log<sub>10<\/sub><sup>2<\/sup>)","options":["4","3","0.0784","-4","-0.0784"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find the value of t such that the expression \\(\\frac{1}{t}\\) + \\(\\frac{4}{3}\\) - \\(\\frac{5}{6t}\\) + 1 is equal to zero","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","- \\(\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"One of the interior angles of a regular polygon is 120\u00b0. Find the number of sides of the polygon","options":["3","4","6","9","12"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If cos x = 4\/5, 0\u00b0 \\( \\leq \\) x \\( \\leq \\) 90\u00b0, find the value of (1 + tan x)\/(1 - tan x)","options":["9","7","4","\\(\\frac{7}{16}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{25}\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Evaluate ut - \\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)ft<sup>2<\/sup>  when t = 5, u = -20 and f = 10","options":["225","72","-75","-125","-225"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Express the quotient of 0.422 and 0.004 in standard form","options":["1.055 \u00d7 10<sup>2<\/sup>","10.55 \u00d7 10<sup>1<\/sup>","105 \u00d7 10<sup>0<\/sup>","10.55 \u00d7 10<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.055 \u00d7 10<sup>-2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The 4th term of a G.P is 3 and its first term is 81. What is its common ratio?","options":["3","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","-\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","-3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"If the mean of the following set of data, 2, 3,3,3, 2,4 4 and 3 is divided by its mode, the result is:","options":["1","2","3","5","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The diagonals of a rhombus are 16cm and 30cm long. What is the perimeter of the rhombus","options":["68cm","72cm","80cm","88cm","92cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A bag Contains 2 red, 3 blue and 4 green identical balls. If two balls are picked at random one after the other without replacement, what is the probability that both are green?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{16}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{9}\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A man is 40m from the foot of a cliff of height 23m. Calculate the angle of elevation of the top of the cliff from the man","options":["50\u00b0 54\u2032","35\u00b0 06\u2032","30\u00b0 00\u2032","290 90\u2032","29\u00b0 54\u2032"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Express the product of 0.007 and 0.057 to two significant figures","options":["0.0004","0.00039","0.004","0.0039","0.04"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Find x if (x - 2)<sup>2<\/sup>  = 1\\(\\frac{7}{9}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\) or \\(\\frac{2}{7}\\)","3\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) or \\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","3\\(\\frac{7}{9}\\) or \\(\\frac{2}{7}\\)","3\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\) or \\(\\frac{7}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{7}\\) or \\(\\frac{2}{9}\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\left(\\frac{3}{4} - \\frac{1}{3}\\right)\\times 4\\frac{1}{3}\\div 3\\frac{1}{4}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{16}\\)","\\(\\frac{8}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{16}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A student bought 3 notebooks and 1 pen for N35. After misplacing these items, she again bought 2 notebooks and 2 pens, all of the same type for<br>\r\nN30. What is the cost of a pen?","options":["N5.00","N7.50","N10.00","N15.00",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{4}{a-3}-\\frac{1}{a+3}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{3a+11}{(a-3)(a-2)}\\)","\\(\\frac{3a+11}{(a+3)(a-2)}\\)","\\(\\frac{3a+11}{(a+3)(a+2)}\\)","\\(\\frac{3a+11}{(a-3)(a+2)}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{4\\sqrt{18}}{\\sqrt{8}}\\)","options":["2","3","6","12",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Three men, Bedu, Bakre and Kofi shared' N500 in the ratio 3:2: x respectively. If Bedu\u2019s share is<br>\r\nN15O, find the value of x","options":["1","4","5","6",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\left(1\\frac{2}{3}\\right)^2\\left(\\frac{2}{3}\\right)^2\\)","options":["\\(2\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(1\\frac{1}{3}\\)","1","\\(\\frac{3}{7}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Find the value of x which satisfies the equation<br>\r\n5(x-7)=7-2x","options":["x =2","x=4","x=6","x = 14",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(\\frac{log8}{log\\left(\\frac{1}{4}\\right)}\\)","options":["-2","\\(\\frac{-3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","4",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A pyramid of volume 120cm<sup>3<\/sup> has a rectangular base which measures 5cm by 6cm. Calculate the height of the pyramid","options":["5cm","9cm","12cm","15cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"PQRS is a cyclic quadrilateral. If \u2220QPS = 75<sup>o<\/sup>, what is the size of \u2220QRS?","options":["180<sup>o<\/sup>","150<sup>o<\/sup>","105<sup>o<\/sup>","75<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Find the value of x in the equation 3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 8x - 3 = 0","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{3},-3\\)","\\(-\\frac{1}{3},-3\\)","\\(-\\frac{1}{3},3\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3},3\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given, that \\(4P4_5 = 119_{10}\\), find the value of P","options":["3.4","4.3","5.9","6.2",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A ladder, 6m long, leans against a vertical wall at an angle 53<sup>o<\/sup> to the horizontal. How high up the wall does the ladder reach?","options":["3.611m","4.521m","4.792m","7.962m",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The four interior angles of a quadrilateral are (x + 20) <sup>o<\/sup>, (x+ 10) <sup>o<\/sup> (2x - 45) <sup>o<\/sup> and (x - 25) <sup>o<\/sup>. Find the value of x","options":["60","80","100","360",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Out of 60 members of an Association, 15 are Doctors and 9 are Lawyers. If a member is selected at random from the Association, what is the probability that the member is neither a Doctor Nor a Lawyer","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{20}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Find the values of x for which \\( \\frac{1}{2x^2 - 13x +15} \\) is not defined,","options":["5 or \\( \\frac{3}{2} \\)","1 or \\( \\frac{15}{13} \\)","2 or 15","13 or 15",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Evaluate \\((111_{two})^2=-(101_{two})^2\\)","options":["10<sub>two<\/sub>","100<sub>two<\/sub>","1100<sub>two<\/sub>","11000<sub>two<\/sub>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given that x \u2245 0.01202 correct to 3 significant figures, which of the following cannot be the actual<br>\r\nvalue of x?","options":["0.01014","0.01021","0.01015","0.01016",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{3^{(1-n)}}{9^{-2n}}=\\frac{1}{9}\\) find n","options":["\\(-\\frac{3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","-1","-3",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Which of the following is\/are not the interior angle(s) of a regular polygon? I.108<sup>o<\/sup> II. 116<sup>o<\/sup> III. 120<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["I only","II only","III only","I and III only",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"If \\(P = \\sqrt{QR\\left(1+\\frac{3t}{R}\\right)}\\) make R the subject of the formula","options":["\\(R = \\frac{3QT}{P^2 - Q}\\)","\\(R = \\frac{P^2 \u2013 3t}{Q+1}\\)","\\(R = \\frac{P^2-3t}{Q-1}\\)","\\(R = \\frac{P^2-3QT}{P^2-Q}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"<i>Use the Venn diagram to answer Question below<\/i><br>\r\nFind Q<sup>l<\/sup>\u2229R","options":["(e)","(c, h)","(c, g, h)","(c, e, g, h)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The square root of a number is 2k. What is half of the number","options":["\\(\\sqrt{\\frac{k}{2}}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{k}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}k^2\\)","2k<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Given that p varies as the square of q and q varies inversely as the square root of r. How does p vary with r?","options":["p varies as the square of r","p varies as the square root of r","p varies inversely as the square of r","p varies inversely as r",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The probabilities of a boy passing English and Mathematics test are x and y respectively. Find the probability of the boy failing both tests","options":["1-(x-y)+xy","1-(x+y)-xy","1-(x+y)+xy","1 - (x - y) + x",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The locus of points equidistant from two intersecting straight lines PQ and PR is","options":["a circle centre P radius Q.","a circle centre P radius PR","the point of intersection of the perpendicular bisectors of PQ and PR","the bisector of angle QPR",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Find the equation whose roots are \\(-\\frac{2}{3}\\) and 3","options":["3x<sup>2<\/sup>+11x-6=0","3x<sup>2<\/sup>+7x+6=0","3x<sup>2<\/sup>-11x-6=0","3x<sup>2<\/sup>-7x-6=0",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Evaluate Cos 45<sup>o<\/sup> Cos 30<sup>o<\/sup> - Sin 45<sup>o<\/sup> Sin 30<sup>o<\/sup> leaving the answer in surd form","options":["\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{2}-1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}-\\sqrt{2}}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{6}-\\sqrt{2}}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{6}-\\sqrt{2}}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"In constructing an angle, Olu draws line OX. With centre O and a convenient radius, he draws an arc intersecting OX at P. With centres P and the same radius, he draws an arc intersecting the first arc at Q and finally joins OQ. What is the size of angle POQ so constructed?","options":["90<sup>o<\/sup>","75<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A right circular cone is such that its radius r is twice its height h. Find its volume in terms of h","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\pi h^2\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{12}\\pi h^3\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{3}\\pi h^2\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{3}\\pi h^3\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A man made a loss of 15% by selling an article for N595. Find the cost price of the article","options":["N600.00","N684.25","N700.00","N892.50",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a measure of dispersion?","options":["Range","Mean deviation","Mean","Standard deviation",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The ratio of the circumference to the diameter of a circle is approximately of a circle is approximately equal to","options":["2.5","3.14","4.83","6.52","7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Two similar cylindrical cans have heights of 7cm and 21cm, if the smaller holds 250g of sugar, how many kg of sugar will the larger one hold?","options":["0.75","1.5","2.25","3.5","6.75"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A right pyramid is on a square base of side 4cm. The slanting side of the pyramid is \\(2\\sqrt{3}\\). Calculate the volume of the pyramid","options":["\\(5\\frac{1}{3}cm^3\\)","\\(10\\frac{2}{3}cm^3\\)","\\(16cm^3\\)","\\(32cm^3\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The height of a night circular cone is 4cm. The radius of its base is 3cm. Find the curve surface area","options":["\\(9\\pi cm^2\\)","\\(15\\pi cm^2\\)","\\(16\\pi cm^2\\)","\\(20\\pi cm^2\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Simplify \\(5\\frac{1}{4}\\div \\left(1\\frac{2}{3}- \\frac{1}{2}\\right)\\)","options":["\\(1\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(3\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(4\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(8\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Find the value of x in 0.5x + 2.6 = 5x + 0.35","options":["0.5","2","2.6","5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If \\(M5_{ten} = 1001011_{two}\\) find the value of M","options":["5","6","7","8",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The length, in cm, of the sides of a right angled triangle are x, (x+2) and (x+1) where x > 0. Find , in cm, the length  of its hypotenuse","options":["4","5","13","17",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If log2 = 0.3010 and log2<sup>y<\/sup> = 1.8062, find; correct to the nearest whole number, the value of y","options":["6","5","4","-5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Points X, Y and Z are located in the same horizontal plane such that Y is 12 km north of X and Z is on a bearing of 270\u00b0 from X. If |XZ| = 6km, calculate, correct to one decimal place, lYZl","options":["18km","13.4km","13km","10.4km",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The ratio of the number of men to the number of women in a 20 member committee is 3:1. How many women must be added to the 20-member committee so as to make the ratio of men to women 3:2?","options":["2","5","7","9",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If (x + 3) varies directly as y and x = 3 when y = 12, what is the value of x when y = 8?","options":["1","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(-\\frac{}{}\\)","-1",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Find the nth term of the sequence 4, 10, 16 ,...","options":["2(3n- 1)","2(2 + 3 <sup>n-1<\/sup>)","2 <sup>n<\/sup> + 2","2(3n+2)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If (-3, -4) is a point on the line y = mx + 2 find the value of m.","options":["-2","\\(\\frac{7}{4}\\)","2","\\(\\frac{8}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"For what values of x is the expression \\(\\frac{3x-2}{4x^2+9x-9}\\) undefined?","options":["\\(\\frac{-3}{4} \\hspace{1mm}or \\hspace{1mm}3\\)","\\(\\frac{-2}{3} \\hspace{1mm}or \\hspace{1mm}-3\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3} \\hspace{1mm}or \\hspace{1mm}3\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{4} \\hspace{1mm}or \\hspace{1mm}-3\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{1}{1-x} + \\frac{2}{1+x}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x+3}{1-x^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{x-3}{1+x^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{3-x}{1-x^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{3-x}{1+x^2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The lengths of the parallel sides of a trapezium are 9 cm and 12 cm. lf the area of the trapezium is 105 cm<sup>2<\/sup>, find the perpendicular distance between the parallel sides.","options":["5cm","7cm","10cm","15cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The base diameter of a cone is 14cm, and its volume is 462 cm<sup>3<\/sup>. Find its height. [Taken \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["3.5cm","5cm","7cm","9cm",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A number is selected at random from the set Y = {18, 19, 2O, . . . 28, 29). Find the probability that the number is prime","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{11}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{2^{\\frac{1}{2}}\\times 8^{\\frac{1}{2}}}{4}\\)","options":["1","2","4","16",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The angle of depression of a point Q from a vertical tower PR, 30m high, is 40<sup>o<\/sup>. If the foot P of the tower is on the same horizontal level as Q, find, correct to 2 decimal places, |PQ|.","options":["35.75m","25.00m","22.98m","19.28",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The volume of a cylinder of radius 14cm is 210cm<sup>3<\/sup>. What is the curved surface area of the cylinder?","options":["15cm<sup>2<\/sup>","30cm<sup>2<\/sup>","616cm<sup>2<\/sup>","1262cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Simplify \\(2\\sqrt{3} + 10\\sqrt{3} - \\frac{6}{-3}\\)","options":["\\(7\\sqrt{3}\\)","\\(10\\sqrt{3}\\)","\\(14\\sqrt{3}\\)","\\(18\\sqrt{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Factorize m(2a-b)-2n(b-2a)","options":["(2a-b)(2n-m)","(2a+b)(m-2n)","(2a-b)(m+2n)","(2a-b)(m-2n)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If q oranges are sold for t Naira, how many oranges can be bought for p naira?","options":["\\(\\frac{p}{2}t\\)","\\(\\frac{qt}{p}\\)","\\(\\frac{q}{pt}\\)","\\(\\frac{pq}{t}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Calculate and correct to two significant figures, the percentage error in approximating 0.375 to 0.4","options":["2.0","2.5","6.6","6.7",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"To arrive on schedule, a train is to cover a distance of 60km at 72km\/hr. If it starts 10 minutes late, at what speed must it move to arrive on schedule?","options":["60km\/hr","80km\/hr","90km\/hr","108km\/hr",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given that \\(p = x-\\frac{1}{x} and\\hspace{1mm}q = x^2 +  \\frac{1}{x^2}\\) express q in terms of p.","options":["(p<sup>2<\/sup> + 2)","(p - 2) <sup>2<\/sup>","(p + 2) <sup>2<\/sup>","(p<sup>2<\/sup> - 2)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The number of goals scored by a school team in<br>\r\n10 netball matches are as follows: 3, 5, 7, 7, 8,<br>\r\n8, 5, 11, 11, 12. Find the probability that in a match, the school team will score at most 8 goals.","options":["\\(\\frac{7}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a rational number?","options":["-5","\\(\\sqrt{4}\\)","\\(3\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{90}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Given that the universal set U={14,15,16,17,18,19,20}, J {16,19,20) and K= (14,15,18), find (J' \u2229 K')1.","options":["{17}","{16, 17, 19, 20}","{1, 4, 15, 17, 18}","{14, 15, 16, 18, 19, 20}","{14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20}"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Evaluate 1.25 \u00d7 102 \u00d7 0.125 \u00d7 103 \u00d7 12.5 \u00d7 10<sup>-4<\/sup> leaving your answer in standard form","options":["1.995 \u00d7 10<sup>3<\/sup>","1.95 \u00d7 10<sup>2<\/sup>","1.95 \u00d7 10<sup>1<\/sup>","1.95 \u00d7 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","1.95 \u00d7 10<sup>-3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"What is the volume of a cube if the diagonal of one of the sides is \\(\\sqrt{50}\\)cm?","options":["7.07cm\\(^3\\)","50.0cm\\(^3\\)","125.0cm\\(^3\\)","353.4cm\\(^3\\)","625.0cm\\(^3\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A cone was developed from a sector of a circle with radius10cm and an angle at the centre of 108\u00b0. What is the radius of the cone?","options":["9.0cm","8.5cm","7.2cm","4.3cm","3.0cm"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If , sT = \\(\\sqrt{\\frac{[(a + T)T]}{a}}\\) what does T equal?","options":["T = (a<sup>2<\/sup>s<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 1)","T = (a<sup>2<\/sup>s<sup>2<\/sup>\u2013 1) \u00f7 a","T = a \u00f7 (a<sup>2<\/sup> - s<sup>2<\/sup>)","T = a \u00f7 (a<sup>2<\/sup>s<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 1)","T = (as \u2013 1)<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"What is the total surface area of a cuboid whose dimensions are 12cm \u00d7 8cm \u00d7 3cm?","options":["312cm\\(^2\\)","96cm\\(^2\\)","36cm\\(^2\\)","24cm\\(^2\\)","12cm\\(^2\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If sin 30\u00b0 = 0.5, what is the cosine of its complement?","options":["-0.866","-0.5","0.0.5","0.866","1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A petrol attendant recorded the number of vehicles that bought petrol from him for -3 hours and recorded 12 cars and 27 buses. What is the probability that the next vehicle will be a bus?","options":["\\(\\frac{4}{39}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{6}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{13}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Two parallel chords of a circle are respectively 46cm and 40cm long. If the radius of the circle is 25cm and the centre of the circle lies between the two chords, what is the distance between the chords?","options":["7cm","15cm","22cm","26cm","30cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The angle of elevation of the top (T) of a palm tree from a point (R) on the ground is 30\u00b0. The distance from R to the base (B) of the palm tree is 120m. What is the distance between T and R?","options":["60m","60\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)m","80\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)m","120\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)m","240m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{t}{1}\\) = \\(\\sqrt{(\\frac{4\\pi^2}{g}})\\), what is the value of g when I = 4.5; t = 5 secs","options":["3.20 ms<sup>2<\/sup>","11.31 ms<sup>2<\/sup>","32.00 ms<sup>2<\/sup>","56.57 ms<sup>2<\/sup>","160.00 ms<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The probability that a student will pass a mathematics test is \u2157. If 3 students are chosen at random, what is the probability that at least 2 of them will pass the test?","options":["\\(\\frac{27}{125}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{25}\\)","\\(\\frac{72}{125}\\)","\\(\\frac{76}{125}\\)","\\(\\frac{81}{125}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"What is the total surface area of a cylinder with radius 2cm and height 1.5cm, correct to 2 significant figures?","options":["440cm\\(^2\\)","220cm\\(^2\\)","88cm\\(^2\\)","44cm\\(^2\\)","22cm\\(^2\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A wire was shaped to form a square of area 81cm<sup>2<\/sup>. An equilateral triangle was formed by the same wire,What is the length of a side of the triangle formed?","options":["3cm","6cm","9cm","12cm","27cm"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"One bag contains 4 white balls and 2 black balls. Another bag contains 3 white balls and 5 black balls, if one ball is drawn from each bag, what is the probability that both are white?","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{24}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{24}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A quadratic equation with roots -1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) and \\(\\frac{1}{4}\\) is","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> + 3x + 4 = 0","8x<sup>2<\/sup> + 10x + 3 = 0","8x<sup>2<\/sup> +12x \u2013 3 = 0","8x<sup>2<\/sup> + 10x-3.= 0","8x<sup>2<\/sup> + 12x + 3 = 0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"What are the factors of 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - xy - 3y<sup>2<\/sup> ?","options":["(2x + 3y)(x + y)<sup>2<\/sup>","(2x + 3y)(x + y)","(2x + 3y)(x - y)","(2x 3y)(x + y)","(2x - 3y)(x - y)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"If sin \u03b8 = \\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\) and 0 < \u03b8 < 180\u00b0, what is cos \u03b8 ?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Three sets of rice x, y and z are sold for N15.00, N35.00 and N60.00 respectively per kg. It they are mixed in the ratio of 1: 3 : 2, what is the cast per kg of the mixture?","options":["N45.00","N42.50","N40.00","N35.50","N25.80"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"When a shirt is sold for N12000.00, a loss of 20% is recorded. How much should it be sold for to gain 20%?","options":["N4800.00","N400","N1800.00","N1500.00","N960.00"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"What must be added to 3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x to make it a perfect square?","options":["\\(\\frac{36}{25}\\)","\\(\\frac{25}{36}\\)","-\\(\\frac{25}{36}\\)","-\\(\\frac{5}{6}\\)","-\\(\\frac{6}{5}\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Twice a number, x, is added to 5, the result is at least 11. What is the range of values of x?","options":["x > 3","x \u2265 3","x \u2264 3","x < 3","x \u2264 -3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Simplify [1 \u00f7 (x + 1)] - [2 \u00f7 (x - 1)] + [3 \u00f7 (x<sup>2<\/sup> - 1)]","options":["- 3x \u00f7 (x<sup>2<\/sup> - 1)","- x \u00f7 (x<sup>2<\/sup> -1)","x \u00f7 (x<sup>2<\/sup> - 1)","(x + 1) \u00f7 (x<sup>2<\/sup> - 1)","(x + 4) \u00f7 (x<sup>2<\/sup> - 1)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The mean heights of 3 groups of students consisting of 20, 16 and 14 students are 1.67m, 1.50m and 1.40m Respectively. What is the mean height of all the students?","options":["1.52m","1.53m","1.54","1.55m","1.56m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The mean and the range of the set of numbers: 1.20, 1.00, 0.90, 1.40, 0.80, 0.80, 1.20 and 1.10 are p and respectively. What is the value of p \u00f7 q","options":["1.11","65","1.85","2.45","3.85"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A girl on top of a storey building 36m high dropped a N10.00 note on the ground below. If the angle of depression of the N10.00 note is 35\u00b0, how far is the money from the girl?","options":["20.64m","29.48m","44.49m","49.55m","62.76m"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"After what length of time will N2400.00 yield an interest of N60.00 at 1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)% per annum?","options":["2\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\) years","1\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)  years","1\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) years","1 years","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\) year"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Solve the equation: \\(\\frac{1}{3}x\\) + \\(\\frac{2}{5}\\) = \\(\\frac{3}{4}x\\) - \\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{17}{30}\\)","\\(\\frac{65}{102}\\)","\\(\\frac{25}{34}\\)","\\(\\frac{102}{75}\\)","\\(\\frac{34}{25}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"An amount of money is shared among P,Q and R such that for every 3P gets, Q gets 2 and for every 1Q gets, R gets 4. Find P: Q : R","options":["3 : 1 : 4","3 : 2 : 1","3 : 2 : 4","3 : 3 : 4","3 : 2 : 8"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Simplify 2a<sup>2<\/sup> -4ab - 6a<sup>2<\/sup> - 10ab + 5ab - 5a<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["-9(a + b)","9(a + b)","-9a (a + b)","9a(a - b)","9b(a + b)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A boy leaves station X on a bearing of 035\u00b0 to station y which is 21km away. He then travels to another station Z on a bearing of 125\u00b0. If Z is directly East of X, what is the distance from X to his present position?","options":["3.0km","12.04km","17.2km","34.18km","36.61km"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The length, breadth and height of a cuboid are 8cm, 7\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)cm and 6\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\) cm respectively. What Is its volume in m<sup>3<\/sup> (leave your answer in standard form)?","options":["3.9 \u00d7 10<sup>-1<\/sup>m<sup>3<\/sup>","3.9 \u00d7 10<sup>-2<\/sup>m<sup>3<\/sup>","3.9 \u00d7 10<sup>-3<\/sup>m<sup>3<\/sup>","3.9 \u00d7 10<sup>-4<\/sup>m<sup>3<\/sup>","3.9 \u00d7 10<sup>-5<\/sup>m<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Which of the following correctly expresses 48 as a product of prime factors?","options":["3 x 4 x 4","2 x 3 x 8","2 x 2 x 2 x 3 x 4","2 x 2 x 2 x 2 x 3",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Evaluate \\((20_{three})^2 - (11_{three})^2\\) in base three","options":["101","121","202","2020",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(log_{10}5 + log_{10}20\\)","options":["2","3","4","5",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In a class of 80 students, every students studies Economics pr geography or both. If 65 students study Economics and 50 study Geography, how many study both subjects?","options":["15","30","35","45",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If N varies directly as M and N = 8 when M = 20 find M when N = 7","options":["13","15","\\(17\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(18\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Express 0.0462 in standard form","options":["0.460 x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>","0.462 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","4.62 x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>","4.62 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In a bag of oranges, the ratio of the good ones to the bad ones is 5:4. If the number of bad oranges in the bag is 36, how many oranges are there in the altogether","options":["81","72","54","45",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A boy estimated his transport fare for a journey  as N190 instead of N200. Find the percentage error in his estimate","options":["95%","47.5%","5.26%","5%",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(5\\frac{2}{5}\\times \\left(\\frac{2}{3}\\right)^2\\div\\left(1\\frac{1}{2}\\right)^{-1}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{8}{25}\\)","\\(\\frac{12}{25}\\)","\\(3\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(4\\frac{1}{8}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The nth term of a sequence is \\(2^{2n-1}\\). Which term of the sequence is \\(2^9?\\)","options":["3rd","4th","5th","6th",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(\\frac{1}{2}+\\frac{3}{4}of\\frac{2}{5}\\div 1\\frac{3}{5}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{15}{16}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{16}\\)","\\(\\frac{49}{50}\\)","\\(3\\frac{1}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A man is four times as old as his son. The difference between their ages is 36 years Find the sum of their ages","options":["45 years","48 years","60 years","74 years",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given that y = px + q and y = 5 when x = 3, while y = 4 when x = 2, find the value of p and q.","options":["p = 1, q = 3","p = 1, q = 2","p = -2, q = 3","p = 3, q = -2",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(\\frac{x^2 + x - 2}{2x^2 + x -3}\\) when x = -1","options":["-2","-1","\\(-\\frac{1}{2}\\)","1",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Factorize \\(6x^2 + 7x - 20\\)","options":["(6x - 5)(x + 4)","2(3x-5)(x+2)","(3x+4)(2x-5)","(3x-4)(2x+5)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{2x-1}{3}-\\frac{x+3}{2}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x+3}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{x+8}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{x-11}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{x-4}{6}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If \\(\\frac{y-3}{2}<\\frac{2y-1}{3}\\), which of the following is true?","options":["y > 7","y < -7","y > -7","y < 7",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"if \\(\\frac{4m+3n}{4m-3n}=\\frac{5}{2}\\), find the ratio m:n","options":["7:4","4:3","3:4","4:7",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If \\(2x^2 + kx - 14 = (x+2)(2x-7)\\), find the value of K","options":["-3","5","9","11",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"which of the following is not quadratic expression?","options":["\\(y = 2x^2 - 5x\\)","\\(y=x(x-5)\\)","\\(y = x^2 - 5\\)","y = 5(x-1)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The graph of the curve \\(y = 2x^2 - 5x - 1\\) and a straight line PQ were drawn to solve the equation \\(2x^2 - 5x + 2 = 0\\)<br>\r\nWhat is the equation of the straight line pQ?","options":["y = -1","y = 1","y = 3","y = -3",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Subtract (-y + 3x + 5z) from (4y - x - 2z)","options":["5y - 4x - 7z","3y + 2x + 3z","-5y + 4x + 7z","2x - 5y + 3z",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If \\(y \\propto \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{x}}\\) x = 16 when y = 2, find x when y = 24","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If 2x : (x +1) = 3:2, what is the value of x?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","1","\\(1\\frac{1}{2}\\)","3",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The bearing S40<sup>o<\/sup>E is the same as","options":["040<sup>o<\/sup>","050<sup>o<\/sup>","130<sup>o<\/sup>","140<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Three observation posts P,Q and R are such that Q is due east of P and R is due north of Q. If |PQ| = 5km and |PR| = 10km, find |QR|","options":["5.0km","7.5km","7.6km","8.7km",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Express 25<sup>o<\/sup> 45<sup>l<\/sup> in decimal (Hint 1<sup>o<\/sup> = 60<sup>l<\/sup>)","options":["25.75<sup>o<\/sup>","25.55<sup>o<\/sup>","25.45<sup>o<\/sup>","25.15<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"<i>A box contains 5 red, 3 green and 4 blue balls. A boy is allowed to take away two balls from the box. Use this information to answer Questions below.<\/i><br>\r\nWhat is the probability that the two balls are red","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{33}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{36}\\)","\\(\\frac{103}{132}\\)","\\(\\frac{31}{36}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"<i>A box contains 5 red, 3 green and 4 blue balls. A boy is allowed to take away two balls from the box. Use this information to answer Questions below.<\/i><br>\r\nWhat is the probability that one is green and the other is blue?","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{11}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{8}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{11}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If the probability that an event will occur is p and the probability that it will not occur is q, which of the following is true?","options":["p-q=1","q-p=0","p+q=1","p+q=0",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Which of the following is not the the size of an exterior angle of a regular polygon?","options":["15<sup>o<\/sup>","18<sup>o<\/sup>","20<sup>o<\/sup>","21<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A sector of a circle radius 14cm subtends an  angle 135<sup>o<\/sup> at the center of the circle. What is the perimeter of the sector? Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)","options":["47cm","81cm","88cm","231cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A solid cylinder of radius 7cm is 10cm long. Find its total surface area","options":["\\(70\\pi cm^2\\)","\\(189\\pi cm^2\\)","\\(210\\pi cm^2\\)","\\(238\\pi cm^2\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The variance of a given distribution is 25. What is the standard deviation?","options":["125","75","25","5",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given that P = {b, d, e, f} and Q = {a, c, f, g} are subsets of the universal set U = {a,b, c, d, e, f, g}. Find P<sup>I<\/sup> \u2229 Q","options":["{a,c}","{a, c, d, g}","{c, d, g}","{a, c, g}",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If s = \\(\\sqrt{(\\frac{a^2}{x^2} - \\frac{b^2}{x^2})}\\)what does y equal?","options":["\\(\\sqrt{[(b^2 - a^2)] \\div (s^2 - x^2)}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{[(b^2 - a^2) \\div (s^2 \\times 2)]}\\)","\\(\\sqrt{[x^2 - a^2 - b^2] \\div s}\\)","\\( [x^2 - a^2 - b^2] \\div s \\)","\\(\\sqrt{[(b^2 \\times 2) \\div (s^2 \\times 2 - a^2)]}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Mr Aborowa bought a car for N200,000.00 and later sold it for N170,000.00. What is the percentage loss?","options":["117.60%","117.60%","117.60%","17.65%","17.65%"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Find the 19th term of the A.P. \\(\\frac{5}{6}\\), \\(\\frac{8}{6}\\), \\(\\frac{11}{6}\\).................","options":["7\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","9","9\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","9\\(\\frac{5}{6}\\)","10"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Simplify 27\\(^{-\\frac{1}{3}}\\) \\(\\times\\) 64\\(^{-\\frac{1}{3}}\\) \\(\\times\\) 4\\(^{\\frac{1}{3}}\\)","options":["48","12","\\(\\frac{4}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{12}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{48}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The bearing of a point Y from point x is 150\u00b0. What is the bearing of X from Y?","options":["330\u00b0","240\u00b0","150\u00b0","120\u00b0","30\u00b0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If the mean of 3, 5, 8, k, 14 and 17 is 11, what is the value of k","options":["58","38","19","11","967"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"From the kip of a storey-buliding, the angle of depression of a mango on a tree 20 m away from the base of the storey-building is 68\u00b0. if the mango is 4.5 m above the ground, what is the height of the storey-building to the nearest metre?","options":["55m","54m","50m","49m","45m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The mean age of 12 boys involved survey is 19 years, 3 months. lf the-age of one of the boys is 22 years, what is the mean age of the other-boys?","options":["10.5 years","19.0 years","35.4 years","264.0 years","423.5 years"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If cos x = - \\( \\frac{5}{13}\\) where 180\u00b0 < X < 270\u00b0, what lathe value of tan x -sin x ?","options":["\\(\\frac{111}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{321}{65}\\)","\\(\\frac{214}{65}\\)","\\(\\frac{112}{13}\\)","\\(\\frac{131}{65}\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Given that (3 - y) \u00f7 2x = (6y + 7) \u00f7 (4x - 5), find the value of x when y = 2","options":["\\(\\frac{64}{5}\\)","6","\\(\\frac{5}{34}\\)","\\(\\frac{-5}{34}\\)","\\(\\frac{-64}{5}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"An arc of a circle subtends an angle of 75\u00b0 at the centre of the circle. If the diameter of the circle is 7cm, what Is the length of the arc? (take \u03c0 = 3.142)","options":["4.58 cm","8.02 cm","16.04 cm","32.08 cm","34 cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If n{A} = 6, n{B} = 5 and n{A \u2229 B} = 2, find n{A \u222a B}","options":["7","8","9","13","15"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If 3 boys shared x oranges among themselves in the ratio 3:5:8, and smallest share was 45 oranges, find the value of x","options":["75","120","165","195","240"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Find the value of k such that \\(t^2\\) + kt + \\(\\frac{25}{4}\\) is a perfect square","options":["5","3","\\(\\frac{5}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The angle of elevation of the top T of a pole from a point X on the horizontal ground is 32\u00b0, if X is 68 m away from the foot F of the pole, calculate the height FT of the pole, correct to one decimal place.","options":["128.3m","108.8m","80.2m","57.7m","42.5m"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If the volume of a cube is (8 x 103)cm\\(^3\\), what is the surface area the cube?","options":["2,400 cm\\(^3\\)","1,600 cm\\(^3\\)","120 cm\\(^3\\)","24 cm\\(^3\\)","16 cm\\(^3\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A chord is drawn 12cm away from the centre of a circle of radius 13cm. What is the length of the chord?","options":["169.00 cm","144.00 cm","25.00 cm","17.69 cm","10.00 cm"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A bottle of malt costs three times as much as a bottle of Mirinda. If 5 bottles of malt and 4 bottles of Mirinda cost N380.00 altogether, how much does a bottle of malt cost?","options":["N90.00","N80.000","N60,000","N40,000","N20,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Two beads are drawn at random, one after the other, with replacement, from a box containing 5 red and 7 white identical beads. What is the probability that the beads are the same colour","options":["\\(\\frac{119}{144}\\)","\\(\\frac{95}{144}\\)","\\(\\frac{37}{72}\\)","\\(\\frac{49}{144}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\sqrt{6a} \\times \\sqrt{576a^6}\\)","options":["\u00b1 16a2","\u00b1 16a","\u00b1 14a2","\u00b1 12a2","\u00b1 12a"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Find the value of x in the equation: 9x = 729","options":["81","27","18","9","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In an acute angle-triangle XYZ, XZ = 9cm, YZ = 11cm and \u2220XZY = 35\u00b0 Calculate \u2220YXZ, correct to the nearest degree.","options":["57\u00b0","45\u00b0","33\u00b0","16\u00b0","89\u00b0"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The surface area of a sphere is 616m2. what is the volume of-the sphere (correct to two significant figures)? (take \u03c0 = 3.142)","options":["14 cm\\(^3\\)","210 cm\\(^3\\)","1,400 cm\\(^3\\)","2,100 cm\\(^3\\)","4,300 cm\\(^3\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"51 women wore coloured shoes to a party, out of which 21 wore purple and 9 wore white. if a woman is selected at Random. What is the probability that she is wearing neither a purple shoe nor a white shoe?","options":["\\(\\frac{10}{17}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{20}{51}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{17}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{51}\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The radius of a sphere is 21cm. If s and v represent the curved surface area and volume respectively, what is s : v? (take \u03c0 = 3.142)","options":["1:03","1:07","3:01","3:07","7:01"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A trader sold an article for N4,600.00 thereby making a profit of 15%. Calculate the cost price of the article","options":["N3450.00","N3910.00","N4000.00","N5290.00","N6900.00"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The first term of a G.P is 7. Find its 4th term, if its common ratio is 3.","options":["567","280","189","63","21"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Express 0.03785 in standard form correct to 3 significant figures.","options":["3 \u00d7 10\\(^{-2}\\)","3.78 \u00d7 10\\(^{-2}\\)","3.79 \u00d7 10\\(^{-2}\\)","3.79 \u00d7 10\\(^{-1}\\)","3.78 \u00d7 10\\(^{-2}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Convert 101.011<sub>2<\/sub> to base 10","options":["63","43","10","\\(\\frac{77}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{53}{8}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Solve the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x - 10 = 0","options":["-2 or -5","-3 or -10","5 or -2","2 or 5","3 or 10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Evaluate (\\(\\frac{1}{343}\\))\\(^{\\frac{1}{3}}\\) + (64)\\(^{-\\frac{1}{3}}\\) - \\(\\frac{4}{9}\\)\\(^{-\\frac{1}{2}}\\)","options":["-\\(\\frac{17}{36}\\)","-\\(\\frac{3}{28}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{28}\\)","\\(\\frac{17}{36}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If sin \u03b8 = 4\/5 where 0\u00b0 \u2220 \u03b8 \u2220 900, what is the value of cos \u03b8 + tan \u03b8?","options":["\\(\\frac{14}{15}\\)","\\(\\frac{15}{29}\\)","\\(\\frac{13}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{144}{15}\\)","\\(\\frac{24}{5}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The lengths of the sides of a triangle are 15m, 21m, and 28cm. What is the size of the angle facing the side 21m (correct to one decimal place)?","options":["85.7\u00b0","47.5\u00b0","41.5\u00b0","41.4\u00b0","38.2\u00b0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"If t varies inversely as the cube of s, and t = 24, when s = 3, find t when s = 2","options":["8","24","27","81","648"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Two fair coins are kissed at the same time. what is the probability of gutting widest a head?","options":["1","\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Express \\(\\frac{7}{19}\\) as a percentage, correct to one decimal place","options":["2.7%","3.7%","27.1%","36.8%",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Express 398753 correct to three significant figures","options":["398000","398700","398800","399000",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"simplify \\(\\frac{10}{\\sqrt{32}}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{4}\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{16}\\sqrt{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{16}{5}\\sqrt{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Find the missing number in the addition of the following numbers, in base seven<br>\r\n\\(\\begin{matrix}<br>\r\n4 & 3 & 2 & 1\\\\ <br>\r\n1 & 2 & 3 & 4\\\\ <br>\r\n* & * & * & *\\\\<br>\r\n1&2&3&4&1<br>\r\n\\end{matrix}\\)","options":["3453","5556","6016","13453",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"What fraction must be subtracted from the sum of \\(2\\frac{1}{6}\\) and \\(3\\frac{1}{4}\\)?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(1\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(1\\frac{1}{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\left(\\frac{16}{81}\\right)^{-\\frac{3}{4}}\\times \\sqrt{\\frac{100}{81}}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{80}{243}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{64}\\)","\\(\\frac{25}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{15}{4}\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Which of the following numbers is perfect cube?","options":["350","504","950","1728",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"If \\(104_x = 68\\), find the value of x","options":["5","7","8","9",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The ages of three men are in the ratio 3:4:5. If the difference between the ages of the oldest and youngest is 18 years, find the sum of the ages of the three men","options":["45 years","72 years","108 years","216 years",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given that \\(log_4X = -3,\\) find x.","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{81}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{64}\\)","64","81",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given that the logarithm of a number is 1.8732, find, correct to 2 significant figures the square root of the mumber","options":["0.29","0.75","0.86","0.93",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A car moves at an average speed of 30kmh<sup>-1<\/sup> how long does it take to cover 200 meters?","options":["2.4 sec","24 sec","144 sec","240 sec",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A man bought a television set on hire purchase for N25,000, out of which he paid N10,000, if he is allowed to pay the balance in eight equal installments, find the value of each installment.","options":["N1250","N1578","N1875","N3125",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"<i>A tree is 8km due south of a building. Kofi is standing 8km west of the tree. Use this information to answer the question below <\/i><br>\r\nHow far is kofi from the building?","options":["4\u221a2km","8km","8\u221a2km","16km",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"<i>A tree is 8km due south of a building. Kofi is standing 8km west of the tree. Use this information to answer the question below <\/i><br>\r\nFind the bearing of kofi from the building","options":["315<sup>o<\/sup>","270<sup>o<\/sup>","225<sup>o<\/sup>","135<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Which of the following bearings is equivalent to S50<sup>o<\/sup>W?","options":["040<sup>o<\/sup>","130<sup>o<\/sup>","220<sup>o<\/sup>","230<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Calculate the standard deviation of the following marks; 2, 3, 6, 2, 5, 0, 4, 2","options":["1.5","1.7","1.8","1.9",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The probabilities that Kodjo and Adoga pass an examination are \\(frac{3}{4} \\hspace{1mm} and \\hspace{1mm}\\frac{3}{5}\\) respectively. Find the probability of both boys failing the examination\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{10}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{20}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Which of the following statement is not true about triangle? I.Each diagonal cuts the rectangle into two congruent triangles. II. A rectangle has four lines of symmetry III. A The diagonals intersect at right angles","options":["I and II only","III only","II only","II and III only",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Each side of a regular convex polygon subtends an angle of 30<sup>o<\/sup> at its center. Calculate each interior angle","options":["75<sup>o<\/sup>","150<sup>o<\/sup>","160<sup>o<\/sup>","68<sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"If the interior angles of hexagon are \\(107^{\\circ}, 2x^{\\circ}, 150^{\\circ}, 95^{\\circ}, (2x-15)^{\\circ} and 123^{\\circ}\\). Find X","options":["\\(57\\frac{1}{2}^{\\circ}\\)","\\(65^{\\circ}\\)","\\(106^{\\circ}\\)","\\(120^{\\circ}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given that \\(x = \\frac{1}{2}and \\hspace{1mm} y = 4 \\hspace{1mm} evaluate \\hspace{1mm} 3x^2y+xy^2\\)","options":["-5","-1","4","11",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given that \\(27^{(1+x)}=9,)\\ find x","options":["-3","\\(\\frac{-1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{3}\\)","2",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"If x varies inversely as y and \\(x = \\frac{2}{3}\\) when y = 9, find the value of y when \\(x=\\frac{3}{4}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{18}\\)","\\(\\frac{8}{81}\\)","\\(\\frac{9}{2}\\)","8",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given that (2x + 7) is a factor of \\(2x^2 + 3x - 14\\), find the other factor","options":["x + 2","2 - x","x - 2","x + 1",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{1}{x-3}-\\frac{3(x-1)}{x^2 - 9}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x-1}{x-3}\\)","\\(\\frac{-2}{x+3}\\)","\\(\\frac{x-1}{x+3}\\)","\\(\\frac{4x}{x^2-9}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"For an inequality for a distance of meters which is more than 18m, but not more than 23m","options":["18 \u2264 d \u2264 23","8 < d \u2264 23","18 \u2264 d < 23","d < 18 or d > 23",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Find the equation whose roots are -8 and 5","options":["\\(X^2 + 13X + 40=0\\)","\\(X^2 - 13X - 40=0\\)","\\(X^2 - 13X +40=0\\)","\\(X^2 + 13X - 40=0\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Make t the subject of formula \\(k = m\\sqrt{\\frac{t-p}{r}}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{rk^2 + p}{m^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{rk^2+pm^2}{m^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{rk^2-p}{m^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{rk^2-p^2}{m^2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Solve the equation \\(3y^2 = 27y\\)","options":["y = o or 3","y = 0 or 9","y = -3 or 3","y = 3 or 9",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Find the value of X such that the expression \\(\\frac{1}{x}+\\frac{4}{3x}-\\frac{5}{6x}+1\\) equals zero","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{-3}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{-7}{6}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Given that p varies directly as q while q varies inversely as r, which of the following statements is true?","options":["r varies directly as p","p varies inversely as r","p varies directly as r","q varies inversely as p",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A bicycle wheel of radius 42cm is rolled over a distance 66 meters. How many revolutions does it make?[Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["2.5","5","25","50",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The height for a pyramid on  square base is 15cm. if the volume is 80cm^3, find the area of the square base.","options":["8cm<sup>2<\/sup>","9.6cm<sup>2<\/sup>","16cm<sup>2<\/sup>","25cm<sup>2<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A tap leaks at the rate of 2cm<sup>3<\/sup> per seconds. How long will it take the tap to fill a container of 45 liters capacity? (1 liters = 1000cm<sup>3<\/sup>)","options":["8 hours","16hr 15min","4hr 25min","3hr",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The length of the parallel sides of a trapezium are 5cm and 7cm. If its area is 120cm<sup>2<\/sup>, find the perpendicular distance between the parallel sides","options":["5.0cm","6.9cm","10.0cm","20.0cm",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The arc of a circle 50 cm long, subtends angle of 75<sup>o<\/sup> at the center of the circle. Find correct to 3 significant figures, the radius of the circle. Take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)","options":["8.74cm","38.2cm","61.2cm","76.4cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The area of a circle is 38.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>. Find its diameter [take \\(\\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)]","options":["22cm","14cm","7cm","6cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Solve the equation 3 + 5x - 2x<sup>2<\/sup> = 0","options":["\\(-\\frac{1}{2},-3\\)","2, 3","-2, 3","\\(-\\frac{1}{2},3\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"If the simple interest on N2000 after 9 months is N60, at what rate per annum is the interest charged?","options":["\\(2\\frac{1}{4}\\%\\)","\\(4\\%\\)","\\(5\\%\\)","\\(6\\%\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The side of a rhombus is 10cm long, correct to the nearest whole number. Between what limits should the perimeter P lie?","options":["39cm \u2264 P \u226441cm","38cm \u2264 P < 42cm","38.5 \u2264 P \u2264 41.5cm","38.5 \u2264 P \u2264 40cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Simplify \\(log_8 2 - log_7 2 + log_7 4 \\)","options":["zero","\\(2log_10 2\\)","\\(3log_10 2\\)","\\(4log_10 2\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"If \\(K\\sqrt{28}+\\sqrt{63}-\\sqrt{7}=0, find \\hspace{1mm} K\\)","options":["-2","-1","1","2",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"From a set \\(A = [3, \\sqrt{2}, 2\\sqrt{3}, \\sqrt{9}, \\sqrt{7}]\\), a number is selected at random. Find the probability that is a rational number","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"<i>The pie chart illustrate the amount of private time a student spends in a week studying various subjects. use it to answer the question below<\/i><br><br>\r\nIf he sends \\(2\\frac{1}{2}\\) hours  week on science, find the total number of hours he studies in a week","options":["\\(3\\frac{1}{3}\\) hours","5 hours","8 hours","12 hours",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A group of 11 people can speak either English or French or Both. Seven can speak English and six can speak French. What is the probability that a person chosen at random can speak both English and french","options":["\\(\\frac{2}{11}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{11}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{11}\\)","\\(\\frac{11}{13}\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The interior angle of a regular polygon is twice the exterior angle. How many sides has the polygon?","options":["5","6","8","9",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Which of the following figures have one line of symmetry only? I. Isosceles triangle II. Rhombus III. Kite","options":["I and II only","II and III only","I and III only","I, II, and III",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Given that m = -3 and n = 2 find the value of \\(\\frac{3n^2 - 2m^3}{m}\\)","options":["-22","-14","14","22",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{2-18m^2}{1+3m}\\)","options":["\\(2(1+3m)\\)","\\(2(1+3m^2)\\)","\\(2(1-3m)\\)","\\(2(1-3m^2)\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Given that \\(81\\times 2^{2n-2} = K, find \\sqrt{K}\\)","options":["\\(4.5\\times 2^{n}\\)","\\(4.5\\times 2^{2n}\\)","\\(9\\times 2^{n-1}\\)","\\(9\\times 2^{2n}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{4}{x+1}-\\frac{3}{x-1}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{x+7}{x^2 - 1}\\)","\\(\\frac{x-7}{x^2 + 1}\\)","\\(\\frac{x-7}{x^2 - 1}\\)","\\(\\frac{x-11}{x^2 - 1}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"If y varies inversely as x<sup>2<\/sup>, how does x vary with y?","options":["x varies inversely as y<sup>2<\/sup>","x varies inversely as <sqrt>y<\/sqrt>","x varies directly as y<sup>2<\/sup>","x varies directly as <sqrt>y<\/sqrt>",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"If \\(tan x = \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}, find cos x - sin x\\)such that \\(0^o \\le x \\ge 90^o\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}+1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{\\sqrt{3}+1}\\)","\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}-1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{\\sqrt{3}-1}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"From the top of a cliff 20m high, a boat can be sighted at sea 75m from the foot of the cliff. Calculate the angle of depression of the boat from the top of the cliff","options":["14.9 <sup>o<\/sup>","15.5 <sup>o<\/sup>","74.5 <sup>o<\/sup>","75.1 <sup>o<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The height of a pyramid on square base is 15cm. If the volume is 80cm<sup>3<\/sup>, find the length of the side of the base","options":["3.3cm","5.3cm","4.0cm","8.0cm",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Simplify 3.72 x 0.025 and express your answer in the standard form","options":["\\(9.3\\times 10^3\\)","\\(9.3\\times 10^2\\)","\\(9.3\\times 10^{-2}\\)","\\(9.3\\times 10^{-3}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Two numbers 24 and 31 are equal in value when converted to base ten. Find the equation connecting x and y","options":["2x = 3(y - 1)","4x - y = 1","3y + 2x = 3","3y = 2 (x + 3)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A car travel at x km per hour for 1 hour and at y k per hour for 2 hours. Find its average speed","options":["\\(\\frac{2x + 2y}{3}kmh^{-1}\\)","\\(\\frac{x + y}{3}kmh^{-1}\\)","\\(\\frac{x + 2y}{3}kmh^{-1}\\)","\\(\\frac{2x + y}{3}kmh^{-1}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The height and base if a triangle are in ratio 1:3 respectively. If the area of the triangle is 216cm<sup>2<\/sup>, find the length of the base.","options":["24cm","36cm","72cm","144cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Water flows from a tap into cylindrical container at the rate 5\u03c0cm<sup>3<\/sup> per second. If the radius of the container is 3cm, calculate the level of water in the container at the end of 9 seconds.","options":["2cm","5cm","8cm","15cm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Amina had m mangoes. she ate 3 and shared the remainder equally with her brother Uche. Each had at least 10. Which of the following inequalities represents the statements above.","options":["\\(\\frac{m}{2}-3\\le 10\\)","\\(\\frac{m}{2}-3\\ge 10\\)","\\(\\frac{m-3}{2}\\ge10\\)","\\(\\frac{m-3}{2}\\le10\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"If \\(x^2 +15x + 50 = ax^2 + bx + c = 0\\). Which of the following statement is not true?","options":["x = -5","x = 10","x + 10 = 0","bc = 750",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The root of a quadratic equation in x, are -m and 2n. Find the equation","options":["\\(x^2 + x(m - 2n)-2mn=0\\)","\\(x^2 - x(m - 2n)-2mn=0\\)","\\(x^2 - x(m - 2n)+2mn=0\\)","\\(x^2 + x(m - 2n)+2mn=0\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A survey shows that 28% of all the men in a village wear a size 9 shoes. What i the probability that a man selected t random in the village wears size 9 shoes?","options":["\\(\\frac{7}{25}\\)","\\(\\frac{41}{50}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","1",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Solve the inequality 2x + 3 < 5x","options":["\\(x>1\\)","\\(x<\\frac{3}{7}\\)","\\(x>\\frac{3}{7}\\)","\\(x>-1\\)",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The sides of a right angle triangle in ascending order of magnitude are 8cm, (x-2)cm and x cm. Find x","options":["16","17","34","90",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Find the root of the equation 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x - 2 = 0","options":["x = -2 or 1\/2","x = -2 or1","x = -2 or 2","x = -1 or 2","x = -1\/2 or 2"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"What value of k makes the given expression a perfect square ? m<sup>2<\/sup> - 8m + k = 0","options":["2","4","8","16","64"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"If log<sub>10<\/sub>q = 2.7078, what is q?","options":["5102","849.9","510.2","84.99","51.02"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Cos x is negative and sin x is negative.Which of the following is true of x?","options":["O<sup>o<\/sup> < x < 90<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup> < x <180<sup>o<\/sup>","180<sup>o<\/sup> < x < 270<sup>o<\/sup>","270<sup>o<\/sup> < x <360<sup>o<\/sup>","-90<sup>o<\/sup> < x <90<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Simplify 0.663954 + 0.003 giving your answer correct to two signifiicant figures","options":["213.18","213.00","213","210","21"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"If log<sub>10<\/sub>a = 4; what is a?","options":["0.4","40","400","1000","10000"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A student measured the length of a room and obtained the  measurement of 3.99. If the percentage error of is measurement was 5% and his own measurement was smaller than the length , what is the length of the room?","options":["3.78m","3.80m","4.18m","4.20","4.788m"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"When an aeroplane is 800m above the ground, its angle of elevation from a point P on the ground is 30<sup>o<\/sup>. How far is the plane from P by line of sight?","options":["400m","800m","1500m","1600m","1700m"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The nth term of a sequence is represented by 3 x 2<sup>(2-n)<\/sup>. Write down the first three terms of the sequence","options":["<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>, 3, 6","6, 3, <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>, 3, <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>, 3, <sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>, 0, 6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Find the number whose logarithm to base 10 is 2.6025","options":["0.0004","4.004","40.04","400.4","4004"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A piece of cloth was measured as 6.10m. If the actual length of the cloth is 6.35, find the percentage error, correct to 2 decimal places","options":["3.05%","3.95%","15.00%","25.00%","39.30%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{8^{\\frac{2}{3}}*27^{\\frac{-1}{3}}}{64^{\\frac{1}{3}}}\\)","options":["-3","\\(\\frac{1}{9}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{27}{8}\\)","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Solve the equation 5x<sup>2<\/sup> - 4x - 1 = 0","options":["-1, 1\/5","-1, -1\/5","1, 1\/5","1, -1\/5","-1, 5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"p and q are two positive numbers such that p > 2q. Which one of the following statements is not true?","options":["-p < -2q","-p > -2q","-q < 2p","q < 1\/2p","p<sup>2<\/sup> > 2q<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">For what value of x is the expression <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">x - 5<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x - 3<\/sup><\/span><\/div> not defined?<\/div>","options":["3, 1","-1, -3","-1, 3","3, -2","1, -3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Make S the subject of the formula: \\(V = \\frac{K}{\\sqrt{T-S}}\\)","options":["\\(T-\\frac{K^2}{V^2} = S\\)","\\(T+\\frac{K^2}{V^2} = S\\)","\\(T-\\frac{K^2}{V} = S\\)","\\(T-\\frac{K}{V} = S\\)","\\(T-\\frac{K}{V^2} = S\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Find the equation whose roots are \\(\\frac{2}{3}and \\frac{-1}{4}\\)","options":["\\(12x^2+11x+2=0\\)","\\(12x^2-11x+2=0\\)","\\(x^2-\\frac{11}{12}x+2=0\\)","\\(x^2+\\frac{11}{12}x-2=0\\)","\\(12x^2+11x+2=0\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Find (X-Y) if 4x - 3y = 7 and 3x - 2y = 5","options":["4","3","2","-2","-3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"solve the inequality \\((Y-3)<\\frac{y}{3}\\)","options":["y > -9","y < 3","y > 4","y < 9","y > 0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"If h(m+n) = m(h+r) find h in terms of m, n and r","options":["\\(h=\\frac{mr}{2m+n}\\)","\\(h=\\frac{mr}{n+m}\\)","\\(h=\\frac{m+n}{n}\\)","\\(h=\\frac{m+n}{m}\\)","\\(h=\\frac{mr}{n}\\)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Given that \\(\\frac{6x-y}{x+2y}=2\\), find the value of \\(\\frac{x}{y}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{3}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{8}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{8}{5}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The radius of a geographical globe is 60cm. Find the length of the parallel of latitude 60<sup>o<\/sup>N","options":["\\(66\\pi cm\\)","\\(60\\pi cm\\)","\\(30\\pi cm\\)","\\(15\\pi cm\\)","\\(6\\pi cm\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Express as a single fraction: \\(\\frac{x}{x-2}-\\frac{x+2}{x+3}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{2x^2 - 3x - 4}{(x-2)(x+3)}\\)","\\(\\frac{2x^2 + 3x - 4}{(x-2)(x+3)}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{(x-2)(x+3)}\\)","\\(\\frac{ 3x + 4}{(x-2)(x+3)}\\)","\\(\\frac{3x - 4}{(x-2)(x+3)}\\)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The following numbers represent at a set of scores for a class of 32 students, where the maximum score possible was 12, 6, 5, 9, 4, 4, 8, 7, 5, 6, 3, 2, 5, 4, 6, 9, 10, 4, 3, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 7, 4, 2, 1, 8, 7, 7, 6, 11. What is the percentage of the class, correct to the nearest whole number, scored above 6?","options":["34%","35%","37%","38%","50%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A die with faces numbered 1 to 6 is rolled once. What is the probability of obtaining  4?","options":["\\(\\frac{1}{36}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{6}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A box contain 2 white and 3 blue identical balls. If two balls are picked at random, one after the other, without replacement, what is the probability of picking two balls of different colours?","options":["\\(\\frac{5}{25}\\)","\\(\\frac{7}{20}\\)","\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)","\\(\\frac{2}{3}\\)","\\(\\frac{5}{6}\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In \\(sin(X+30)^o=cos40^o\\),find X","options":["10<sup>o<\/sup>","20<sup>o<\/sup>","50<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Find the value of X if \\(cos x = \\frac{5}{8}for 0^o\\le X\\le 180^o\\)","options":["141.3<sup>o<\/sup>","128.7<sup>o<\/sup>","51.3<sup>o<\/sup>","48.7<sup>o<\/sup>","38.7<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A ladder 5cm long long rest against a wall such that its foot makes an angle 30<sup>o<\/sup> with the horizontal. How far is the foot of the ladder from the wall?","options":["\\(\\frac{5\\sqrt{2}}{3}m\\)","\\(2\\frac{1}{2}m\\)","\\(\\frac{5\\sqrt{3}}{2}m\\)","\\(\\frac{10\\sqrt{3}}{3}m\\)","\\(10\\sqrt{3}m\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A chord of circle of radius 26cm is 10cm from the center of the circle. calculate the length of the chord","options":["16cm","27.86cm","32cm","48cm","55.72cm"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Two chords PQ and RS of a circle intersected at right angles at a point inside the circle. If \u2220QPR = 35<sup>o<\/sup>,find \u2220PQS","options":["35<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>","55<sup>o<\/sup>","70<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"If the exterior angles of quadrilateral are y<sup>o<\/sup>, (y + 5)<sup>o<\/sup>, (y + 10)<sup>o<\/sup> and (y + 25)<sup>o<\/sup>, find y","options":["10<sup>o<\/sup>","20<sup>o<\/sup>","40<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","80<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The length of an arc of a circle of radius 5cm is 4cm. Find the area of the sector","options":["\\(1\\frac{3}{5}cm^2\\)","2cm<sup>2<\/sup>","8cm<sup>2<\/sup>","10cm<sup>2<\/sup>","20cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In \\(\\triangle PQR\\). T is a point on QR such that \\(\\angle QPT = 39^o and \\angle PTR = 83^o. Calculate \\angle PQT\\)","options":["\\(34^o\\)","\\(44^o\\)","\\(45^o\\)","\\(97^o\\)","\\(107^o\\)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The diagonal and one side of a square are x and y units respectively. Find an expression for y in terms of x","options":["\\(y=\\frac{x}{2}\\)","\\(y\\frac{x}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)","\\(y=\\sqrt{x}\\)","\\(y=\\sqrt{\\frac{x}{2}}\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Find the curved surface area of a cone of radius 3cm and slant height 7cm (\\(take \\pi = \\frac{22}{7}\\)","options":["\\(22cm^2\\)","\\(44cm^2\\)","\\(66cm^2\\)","\\(132cm^2\\)","\\(198cm^2\\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Three of the angles of a hexagon are each X<sup>o<\/sup>. The others are each 3X<sup>o<\/sup>. Find X","options":["30<sup>o<\/sup>","40<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","80<sup>o<\/sup>","120<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(\\sqrt{20}\\times (\\sqrt{5})^3\\)","options":["10","20","25","50",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"If P = {3, 7, 11, 13} and Q = {2, 4, 8, 16}, which of the following is correct","options":["\\((P\\cap Q)^l={2, 3, 4, 13}\\)","\\(n(P\\cup Q)=4\\)","\\(P\\cup Q = \\emptyset\\)","\\(P\\cap Q = \\emptyset\\)",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"It is observed that \\(1 + 3 = 2^2, 1 + 3 + 5 = 3^2, 1 + 3 + 5 + 7 = 4^2. \\\\If \\hspace{1mm}1 + 3 + 5 + 7 + 9 + 11 + 13 + 15 = P^2 find\\hspace{1mm}P\\)","options":["6","7","8","9",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Evaluate \\(3.0\\times 10^1 - 2.8\\times 10^{-1}\\)leaving  the answer in standard form","options":["\\(2\\times 10^{-1}\\)","\\(2\\times 10^{2}\\)","\\(2.972 \\times 10^{1}\\)","\\(2.972 \\times 10^{2}\\)",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A trader makes a loss of 15% when selling an article. Find the ratio, selling price : cost price","options":["3:20","3:17","17:20","20:23",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The side of a square is increased from 20cm to 21cm. Calculate the percentage increase in its area","options":["2.5%","9.3%","10.0%","10.25%",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Arrange in ascending order of magnitude \\(26_8, 36_7, and 25_9\\)","options":["\\(25_9 26_8 36_7\\)","\\(26_8 25_9 36_7\\)","\\(36_7 26_8 25_9\\)","\\(36_7 25_9 26_8\\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Express (0.0425 \/ 2.5)   as a fraction","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">17<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">10,000<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">17<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">1,000<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">17<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">250<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">17<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">100<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">17<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">10<\/span><\/div><\/div>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"If P = {3, 5, 6} and Q = {4, 5, 6} then P\u2229Q equals","options":["{3, 4}","{4, 5}","{4, 6}","{5, 6}","{3, 5}"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"A and B are two sets. The number of elements in A\u222aB is 49, the number in A is 22 and number in B is 34. How many elements are in A \u2229 E?","options":["105","27","15","12","7"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"A student found the approximate value of 0.02548 correct to two places of decimal instead of two significant figures. Find the percentage error.","options":["0%","131\/3%","15 5\/13%","2\/3%","20%"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Simplify log<sub>3<\/sub>9 + log<sub>3<\/sub>15 - log<sub>3<\/sub>5","options":["log<sub>3<\/sub>19","log<sub>3<\/sub>","3","1","o"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Solve me equation: 2\/3 (x + 5) = 1\/4(5x - 3)","options":["1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>","1<sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>23<\/sub>","3","4<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>","7"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Which of the following equations has its roots as 4and 5?","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> + 4x - 20 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + x + 20 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - x + 20 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + x - 20 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - x - 20 = 0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Solve the equations: 4x -y = 11 5x + 2y = 4","options":["x = 6, y = 13","x = -2, y = -3","x = -2, y = 3","x = 2, y = -3","x = 2, y = 3."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Make q the subject of the relation t = <span class=\"roota\"><span class=\"n-root\"><\/span>\u221a<\/span><span class=\"rootb\"><sup>pq<\/sup>\/<sub>r<\/sub><\/span> \u00a0- r<sup>2<\/sup><\/div>","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\">q = <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">rt<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">p - r<sup>3<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\">q = <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">t<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">p - r<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\">q = <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">rt<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">p - r<sup>3<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\">q = <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">p - r<sup>3<\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">rt<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","Q = rt<sup>2<\/sup>(p - r<sup>3<\/sup> )"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"P varies inversely as the square of W. When W = 4, P = 9. Find the value of P when W = 9","options":["729\/16","6","4","16\/9","4\/3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Two points P and Q are on longitude 67<sup>o<\/sup>W. Their latitudes differ by 90<sup>o<\/sup>. Calculate their distance apart in terms of \u03c0. (Take radius of the earth = 6400km).","options":["6400\u03c0km","6400km\/\u03c0","3200\u03c0km","3200km","3200km\/\u03c0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The cross-section of a prism is a right-angled triangle 3cm by 4cm by 5cm. The height of the prism is 8cm. Calculate its volume","options":["48cm<sup>3<\/sup>","6Ocm<sup>3<\/sup>","96cm<sup>3<\/sup>","120cm<sup>3<\/sup>","24Ocm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Find the radius of a circle in which an arc of length 44cm subtends angle 200\u00b0 at the centre of the circle. [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["3.9cm","12.6cm","25.2cm","38.4cm","124.5cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Which of the following is not necessarily sufficient for the construction of a Q triangle?","options":["Three sides","Two sides and an included angle","Two sides and a right angle","Two sides and an angle","Two angles and a side."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Which of the following statements is\/are true when two straight lines intersect?<br>\r\nI. Adjacent angles are equal II. Vertically opposite angles are equal III. Adjacent angles are supplementary","options":["II  only","I and III only","II and III only","I, II and III","I and II"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The interior angles of a pentagon are 126<sup>o<\/sup>, 114<sup>o<\/sup>, y, 92<sup>o<\/sup> and 83<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the value of y.","options":["85<sup>o<\/sup>","95<sup>o<\/sup>","105<sup>o<\/sup>","115<sup>o<\/sup>","125<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Solve the inequality 3x - 8 \u2265 5x","options":["x \u2264 4","x \u2265 1","x \u2264 -4","x \u2264 -1","x < 2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Divide 3.6721 by 4","options":["0.9180","1.4180","1.168O","1.1680","1.9180"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The eleventh term of an AP, is 25 and its first term is -3. Find its common difference.","options":["1<sup>9<\/sup>\/<sub>10<\/sub>","2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>","2<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub>","2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","2<sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Find the common ratio in the GP: log 3, log 9, log 81 ..........","options":["1","2","3","6","9"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Find the value oft for which 64\/27 = (3\/4)<sup>t-1<\/sup>","options":["-4","-2","1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","2","4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Given that 1\/2 log<sub>10<\/sub> P = 1, find the value Of P","options":["10<sup>4<\/sup>","10<sup>3<\/sup>","10<sup>2<\/sup>","10<sup>1<\/sup>","10<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"If two triangles are similar, which of the following is true? Their","options":["corresponding sides are equal","corresponding angles are equal","corresponding altitudes are equal","areas are equal","perimeters are equal"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Which of the following is not necessarily true of a<br>\r\nrectangle?","options":["The diagonals are equal","The diagonals bisect each other","The diagonals are perpendicular","Each diagonal divides the area of the rectangle equally","Each diagonal divides the rectangle into two congruent triangles"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Express the true bearing of 250<sup>o<\/sup> as a compass bearing","options":["N2O<sup>o<\/sup>E","S20<sup>o<\/sup>E","N20<sup>o<\/sup>W","S7O<sup>o<\/sup>W","S70<sup>o<\/sup>E"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"lf sin \u03b8= 1\/2, find all the values of \u03b8 between 0<sup>o<\/sup> and 360<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["120<sup>o<\/sup>,240<sup>o<\/sup>","120<sup>o<\/sup>180<sup>o<\/sup>","210<sup>o<\/sup>,300<sup>o<\/sup>","210<sup>o<\/sup>,33O<sup>o<\/sup>","300<sup>o<\/sup>,360<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"Cos 65<sup>o<\/sup> has the same value as","options":["Sin 65<sup>o<\/sup>","Cos 25<sup>o<\/sup>","Cos 115<sup>o<\/sup>","Cos 205<sup>o<\/sup>","Cos 295<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"What is the probability of having an odd number in a single throw of a fair die with the faces numbered 1,2,3,4,5,6?","options":["5\/6","2\/3","1\/2","1\/3","1\/6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"A bag contains 3 white, 6 red, 5 blue identical balls. A ball is picked at random from bag. What is the probability that is either white or blue?","options":["9\/14","4\/7","3\/7","5\/14","3\/14"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1997"},{"question":"The 6th term of a G.P is -2 and its first term is 18. What is the common ratio?","options":["-<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","-1\/3","1\/4","2","3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">simplify  (2<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">6<\/span><\/div> -  1<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">2<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">3<\/span><\/div>) \/ 2<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">2<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">3<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["3\/16","7\/16","1 13\/24","2 11\/24","10 2\/5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Simplify 56x<sup>-4<\/sup> \/ 14x<sup>-8<\/sup>","options":["2x<sup>-12<\/sup>","3x<sup>-3<\/sup>","3x<sup>-4<\/sup>","4x<sup>-3<\/sup>","4x<sup>-4<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Simplufy Log<sub>10<\/sub>4 + Log<sub>10<\/sub>25","options":["1","2","3","4","5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"A boy measured the length and breath of a rectangular lawn as 59.6m and 40.3m respectively instead of 60m and 40m. What is the percentage error in his calculation of the perimeter of the lawn?","options":["10%","1.4%","7%","0.2%","0.1%"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Find the 9th term of the arithmetic progression 18, 12, 6, 0, -6 .........","options":["-54","-30","30","42","66"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Expand (2x - 5)(x - 3)","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> - 1x -15","2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x + 15","2<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x - 8","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x - 15","2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 6x + 15"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Simplify <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">5<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">x - y<\/span><\/div> - <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">4<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y - x<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">9<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">x - y<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">9<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y - x<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">x - y<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y - x<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">y - 9x<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">x - y<\/span><\/div><\/div>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"If 3p - q = 6 and 2p + 3q = 4, find q","options":["o","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","2\/3","1","3<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"M varies directly as an inversely as the square of p. If M = 3, when n = 2 and p = 1, find M in terms of n and p.","options":["M = 2n\/3p","M = 3n<sup>2<\/sup>\/2p<sup>2<\/sup>","M = n<sup>2<\/sup>\/2p","M = 3n\/2p<sup>2<\/sup>","M = 2n\/3p<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Solve the equation <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">4<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">a<\/span><\/div> + <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">5a<\/span><\/div> = 3<\/div>","options":["2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>","1<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>","1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","1<sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>15<\/sub>","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Make p the subject if formula y =  <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">a + p<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">a - p<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">2a + y<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">a + y<\/span><\/div> = p<\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">ay - y<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y + 1<\/span><\/div> = p<\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">a(y -1)<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y + 1<\/span><\/div> = p<\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">ay<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y + 1<\/span><\/div> = p<\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">2y -1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y - 1<\/span><\/div> = p<\/div>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Factorize 32x<sup>3<\/sup> - 8xy<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["4(4x + y)(2x - y)","(16x - y)(2x + y)","8x(2x - y)","8x(2x + y)(2x - y)","4(2x + y)(4x - y)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"The roots of a quadratic equation are -<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> and 3. The quadratic equation is","options":["4x<sup>2<\/sup> - 13x - 3 = 0","4x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x - 3 = 0","4x<sup>2<\/sup> + 11x - 3 = 0","3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x - 3 = 0","3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x + 3 = 0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"The graph of 2y = 5x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2 cuts the y axis at the point","options":["(1,0)","(-2\/5, 0)","(0, -1)","(0, -2)","(0, 1)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"<p>In the diagram above, O is the center of the circle of radius 3.5cm, \u2220POQ = 60<sup>o<\/sup><\/p><br>\r\n<p>Use the information to answer the question below [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]<\/p><br>\r\nWhat is the area of the minor sector POQ?","options":["148<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>","77cm<sup>2<\/sup>","32<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>12<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>","6<sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>12<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>","1<sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"If the hypotenuse of a right-angle isosceles triangle is 2, what is the length of each of the other side?","options":["1\/\u221a2","\u221a2 - 1","1","\u221a2","\u221a3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Find, correct to 1 decimal place, the volume of cylinder of height 8cm and base radius 3cm. [Take \u03c0 = 3.142]","options":["503.0cm<sup>3<\/sup>","300.0cm<sup>3<\/sup>","250.0cm<sup>3<\/sup>","226.2cm<sup>3<\/sup>","150.9cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"One side of a rectangle is 8cm and the diagonal is 10cm. What is the area of the rectangle?","options":["80cm<sup>2<\/sup>","48cm<sup>2<\/sup>","40cm<sup>2<\/sup>","36cm<sup>2<\/sup>","24cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"two towns X and Y both on latitude 60<sup>o<\/sup>S have longitude 27<sup>o<\/sup>E and 33<sup>o<\/sup>W respectively. Find to the nearest kilometers, the distance between X and Y measured along the parallel of latitude. [Take 2\u03c0R = 4 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>km, where R is the Radius of the earth]","options":["28850km","16667km","8333km","6667km","3333km"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"The angle of a sector of a circle of radius 35cm is 288<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the perimeter of the sector. [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["246cm","211cm","141cm","114cm","44cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"How many sides has a polygon if the sum of its interior angle is 1440<sup>o<\/sup>?","options":["6","7","8","9","10"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Each interior angle of a regular nonagon(nine sided polygon) is equal to","options":["160<sup>o<\/sup>","144<sup>o<\/sup>","140<sup>o<\/sup>","132<sup>o<\/sup>","36<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Which of the following is not true? You may construct a","options":["triangle given all the three sides","triangle given one side and two angles","triangle given two sides and the included angle","quatrilateral given all the four sides","parallelogram given two adjacent sides and the diagonal joining them"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"In the diagram, \u2220PMN =  \u2220PRQ and \u2220PNM = \u2220PQR. If \/Pm\/ = 3cm, \/MQ\/ = 7cm and \/PN\/ = 5cm, find \/NR\/","options":["1cm","3cm","3<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","5cm","6cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Two angles (a + 31) and (b - 49<sup>o<\/sup>) are adjacent angles on a straight line. Which of the following is true","options":["a + b = 198<sup>o<\/sup>","a + b = 180<sup>o<\/sup>","a + b = 162<sup>o<\/sup>","a + b = 100<sup>o<\/sup>","a + b = 80<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"If sin\\(\\theta\\) cos\\(\\theta\\), for 0<sup>o<\/sup> \\(\\leq\\) \u03b8 \\(\\leq\\) 360<sup>o<\/sup>, find the value of \\(\\theta\\)","options":["45<sup>o<\/sup>, 225<sup>o<\/sup>","135<sup>o<\/sup>, 315<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>, 315<sup>o<\/sup>","135<sup>o<\/sup>, 225<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>, 135<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"If tan x = \\(2\\frac{2}{5}\\), find the value of sin x; 0 \\(\\leq\\) x \\(\\leq\\) 90<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["5\/13","5\/12","144\/169","12\/13","13\/12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"The cumulative frequency curve may be used to find the","options":["variance","standard deviation","mode","median","mean"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"The marks obtained by pupils of class are grouped as shown below; 0 - 4, 5 - 9,10 -14, 15 -19. Which of the following is\/are not true? l. The mid values of the grouped marks are 2, 7, 12 and 17. II The class interval is 4. III The class boundaries are 0.5, 4.5, 9.5, 14.5 and 19.5","options":["I only","II only","III only","I and II only","II and III only"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"What percentage of observation lie outside interquartile range of any distribution?","options":["12<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>%","25%","50%","62<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> %","75%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"A bag contains 3 red, 4 black and 5 green identical balls. Two balls are picked at random, one after the other without replacement. Find the probability that one is red and the other is green","options":["2\/3","5\/11","5\/22","5\/24","5\/48"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1996"},{"question":"Find (101<sub>2<\/sub>)<sup>2<\/sup>, expressing the answer in base 2.","options":["10101","11001","10010","11101","10110"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"If three children shares N10.50 among themselves in ratio 6:7:8, how much is the largest share?","options":["N3.00","N3.50","N4.00","N4.50","N5.00"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Express 0.000834 in standard form","options":["8.34 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup>","8.34 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","8.34 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>","8.34 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>","8.34 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Given that log<sub>2<\/sub>a = log<sub>8<\/sub>4, find a","options":["2<sup>1\/3<\/sup>","4<sup>2\/3<\/sup>","4<sup>2\/3<\/sup>","2<sup>2\/3<\/sup>","2<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"By selling some crates of soft drinks for N600.00, a dealer makes a profit of 50%. How much did the dealer pay for the drinks?","options":["N1,200.00","N900.00","N450.00","N400.00","N200.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Find the nth term Un of the A.P., 11, 4, -3,....... .","options":["Un=19+7n","Un=19-7n","Un=18+7n","Un= 18-7n","Un= 17-7n"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"lf 16\/9 , x, 1, y are in Geometric Progression (GP), find the product of x and y.","options":["9\/16","3\/4","1","4\/3","16\/6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"If R = [2, 4, 6, 7] and S = [1, 2, 4, 8], then R\u222aS equal","options":["[1,2,4,6,7,8]","[1,2,4,7,8]","[1,4.7,8]","[2.6.7]","[2.4]"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Find the values of x for which the expression is underlined;<br>\r\n<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">6x - 1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">x<sup>2<\/sup> + 4x - 5<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["+4 or+1","-5 or+1","-5 or -1","+5 or -1","+4 -1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Solve the inequality: 1\/3(2x - 1) 5","options":["x < - 5","X<-6","X<7","x <8","x < 16"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"What is the smaller value  of x for which x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x + 2=O?","options":["1","2","3","4","5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Factorize the expression x(a - c) + y(c - a)","options":["(a - c)(y - x)","(a - c)(x - y)","(a + c)(x - y)","(a + c)(x + y)","(a - c)(x + y)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"If y = 1\/x and x= 3 when y=4, find y when x=2","options":["1","3","9","18","21"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Solve the equation 3x<sup>2<\/sup> + 25x -18 = 0","options":["-3,2","-2,3","-2,9","-9,2\/3","2\/3, 9."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Solve the equation (x +2)(x - 7) = 0","options":["x = 1 or8","x = 2or7","x = -4or5","x = -3 or6","x= -5or -2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Solve the following Simultaneous equations: x+ y = 3\/2; x - y = 5\/2 and use your result to find the value of 2y + x","options":["-2","-1","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","1","3<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The diagonals AC and BD of a rhombus ABCD are 16cm and 12cm long respectively. Calculate the area of the rhombus.","options":["24cm<sup>2<\/sup>","36cm<sup>2<\/sup>","48cm<sup>2<\/sup>","60cm<sup>2<\/sup>","96cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A water tank of height <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> m has a square base of side 1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> m. lf it is filled with water from a water tanker holding 1500 litres, how many litres of water are left in the water tanker? [1000 litres = 1m<sup>3<\/sup>]","options":["37.5litres","375 litres","3750 litres","37500 litres","375000 litres"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"<p>A cylindrical container, closed at both ends, has a radius of 7cm and height 5cm [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]<\/p>Find the total surface area of the container","options":["35cm<sup>3<\/sup>","154cm<sup>3<\/sup>","220cm<sup>2<\/sup>","528cm<sup>2<\/sup>","770cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"<p>A cylindrical container, closed at both ends, has a radius of 7cm and height 5cm [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]<\/p>What is the volume of the container?","options":["35cm<sup>3<\/sup>","154cm<sup>3<\/sup>","220cm<sup>3<\/sup>","528cm<sup>3<\/sup>","77Ocm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Find the total surface area of solid circular cone with base radius 3cm and slant height 4cm. [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["37 5\/7cm<sup>2<\/sup>","66cm<sup>2<\/sup>","75 3\/7cm<sup>2<\/sup>","78 2\/7cm<sup>2<\/sup>","88cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A hollow sphere has a volume of kcm<sup>3<\/sup> and a surface area of kcm<sup>2<\/sup>. Calculate the diameter of the sphere.","options":["3cm","6cm","9cm","12cm","More information is needed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The positions of two countries P and Q are (15<sup>o<\/sup>N, 12<sup>o<\/sup>E) and (65<sup>o<\/sup>N, 12<sup>o<\/sup>E) respectively. What is the difference in latitude?","options":["104<sup>o<\/sup>","100<sup>o<\/sup>","80<sup>o<\/sup>","50<sup>o<\/sup>","24<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"A 120<sup>o<\/sup> sector of a circle of radius 21cm is bent to form a cone. What is the base radius of the cone?","options":["3<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>cm","7cm","1O<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>cm","14cm","21cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The angle of a sector of a circle is 108<sup>o<\/sup>. If the radius of the circle is 3<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>cm, find the perimeter of the sector","options":["6 3\/5cm","6 4\/5cm","7 1\/10cm","10 2\/5cm","13 3\/5cm,"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"If log<sub>10<\/sub> x = 2.3675 and log<sub>10<\/sub>y = 2.9738, what is the value of x + y, correct lo three significant figures?","options":["O.117","0.118","0.903","O.944","0.946"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The locus of a point which is equidistant from two given fixed points is the","options":["perpendicular bisector of the straight line joining them","angle bisector of the straight lines joining the points to the origin","perpendiculars to the straight line joining them","parallel-line to the straight line joining them","a line making an acute angle with the line joining the two points"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Which of the following angles is an exterior angle of a regular polygon?","options":["95<sup>o<\/sup>","85<sup>o<\/sup>","78<sup>o<\/sup>","75<sup>o<\/sup>","72<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Without using tables, find the value of<br>\r\n<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">sin 20<sup>o<\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">cos 70<sup>o<\/sup><\/span><\/div> + <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">cos 25<sup>o<\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">sin 65<sup>o<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["2","1","o","-1","-2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"What is the mode of the numbers 8, 10, 9, 9, 10, 8, 11, B, 10, 9, 8 and 14?","options":["8","9","10","11","14"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"The mean of 20 observations in an experiment is 4, lf the observed largest value is 23, find the mean of the remaining observations.","options":["4","3","2.85","2.60","2.56"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"Find the median of the following numbers 2.64, 2.50, 2.72, 2.91 and 2.35.","options":["2.91","2.72","2.64","2.50","2.35"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"From a box containing 2 red, 6 white and 5 black balls, a ball is randomly selected. What is the probability that the selected ball is black?","options":["2\/13","5\/13","5\/11","5\/6","11\/13"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1995"},{"question":"If the 2nd and 5th terms of a G.P are 6 and 48 respectively, find the sum of the first for term","options":["-45","-15","15","33","45"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"If sin\\( \\theta \\) = K find tan\\( \\theta \\), 0<sup>o<\/sup> \\( \\leq \\) \\( \\theta \\) \\( \\leq \\) 90<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["1-K","\\( \\frac{k}{k - 1} \\)","\\( \\frac{k}{\\sqrt{1 - k^2}} \\)","\\( \\frac{k}{1 - k} \\)","\\( \\frac{k}{\\sqrt{ k^2 - 1}} \\)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Simplify: (2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>) \/ (2<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>) x (1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>)","options":["o","1","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Which of the following is equal to \\( \\frac{72}{125} \\)","options":["\\( \\frac{2^3 \\times 3^2}{5^3} \\)","\\( \\frac{2^4 \\times 3}{5^3} \\)","\\( \\frac{2^3 \\times 3}{5^3} \\)","\\( \\frac{2^4 \\times 3}{5^5} \\)","\\( \\frac{2^2 \\times 3^2 \\times 4^2}{5^2} \\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Express in \\( \\frac{8.75}{0.025} \\)standard form","options":["3.5 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","3.5 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","3.5 x 10<sup>1<\/sup>","3.5 x 10<sup>2<\/sup>","3.5 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Evaluate \\( \\frac{27^{\\frac{1}{3}}}{16^{-\\frac{1}{4}}} \\)","options":["6","5","4","3","2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Simplify: 16<sup>5\/4<\/sup> x 2<sup>-3<\/sup> x 3<sup>0<\/sup>","options":["o","2","4","10","20"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"simplify; 2log<sub>3<\/sub>6 + log<sub>3<\/sub>12 - log<sub>3<\/sub>16","options":["2","3","2 - 2log<sub>3<\/sub>2","3 - log<sub>3<\/sub>2","4 - log<sub>3<\/sub>2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"What is the number whose logarithm to base 10<br>\r\nis 3.4771?","options":["3.0","0.3","0.03","0.003","0.0003"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"A house bought for N100,000 was later auctioned for N80.000. Find the loss percent.","options":["20%","30%","40%","50%","60%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"A string is 4.8m. A boy measured it to be 4.95m. Find the percentage error.","options":["\\( \\frac{5}{16} \\)%","\\(1\\frac{5}{16} \\)%","\\( 3\\frac{1}{33} \\)%","\\( 3\\frac{1}{8} \\)%","25%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The sum of the 1st and 2nd terms of an A.P. is 4 and the 10th term is 19. Find the sum of the 5th and 6th terms.","options":["11","20","21","22","24"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"E = (integers 20), P = (multiples of 3), Q = (multiples of 4), what are the elements of P'\u2229Q?","options":["(12)","(4, 8, 16, 20)","(3, 6, 9, 15, 18)","(1,2,5,7,10,11,13,17,19)","(3, 4, 6, 8, 9, 12, 15, 16, 18, 20)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Given that 2p - m = 6 and 2p + 4m = 1, find the value of (4p + 3m).","options":["1","3","5","7","9"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Which of the following is a point on the curve y = x<sup>2<\/sup> -4x + 7?","options":["(0,6)","(1,4)","(2,0)","(7,0)","(3,2)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"If 8x- 4 = 6x- 10, find the value of 5x,","options":["-35","-15","-3","3","7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">For what value of x is the expression <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">x<sup>2<\/sup> + 15x + 50<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">x - 5<\/span><\/div> not defined ?<\/div>","options":["-10","-5","o","5","10"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"If x is positive, for what range of values of x is<br>\r\n4 + 3x < 10?","options":["0 < x < 2","x < 2","1 < x < 2","0 < x < 4 <sup>3<\/sup> <sub>4<\/sub>","0 > x > 2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a factors of 2p<sup>2<\/sup> - 2?","options":["2","p - 1","p + 1","2p - 2","2p + 1"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Find the quadratic equation whose roots are 3 and 2\/3.","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11 \/ 3x + 6 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x + 6 = O","3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x + 2 = O","3X<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x \u2013 2 = 0","3x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x + 6 = 0"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Which of the following is a root of the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> +6x = 0?","options":["o","1","2","3","It does not have any root."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Factorise: 6x<sup>2<\/sup> + 7xy - 5y<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["(6x + 5y)(x - y)","(2x + 5y)(3x - y)","(3x + y)(2x - 5y)","(3x + 5y)(2x - y)","(2x + y)(3x - 5y)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Solve the equation log<sub>8<\/sub>x - 4log<sub>8<\/sub>x = 2","options":["<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","1","2","4"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"A cuboid of base 12.5cm by 20cm holds exactly 1 litre of water. What is the height of the cuboid? (1 litre =1000cm<sup>3<\/sup>)","options":["2cm","4cm","5cm","8cm","10cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Two ships on the equator are on longitudes 45<sup>o<\/sup>W and 45<sup>o<\/sup>E respectively. How far are they apart along the equator, correct to 2 significant figures? (Take the radius of earth = 6400km and \u03c0 = 22\/7)","options":["15,000km","10,000km","6,400km","5,000km","3,200km"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Calculate, correct to 2 significant figures, the length of the arc of a circle of radius 3.5cm which subtends an angle of 75\u00b0 at the centre of the circle. [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7].","options":["2.3cm","4.6cm","8cm","16cm","110cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"A circle has radius x cm. What is the area of a sector of the circle with angle 135\u00b0, leaving the answer in terms of x and \u03c0?","options":["\\( \\frac{\\pi x^2}{8} \\)","\\( \\frac{3\\pi x^2}{8} \\)","\\( \\frac{5\\pi x^2}{8} \\)","\\( \\frac{3\\pi x}{8} \\)",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Two solid spheres have volumes 250cm<sup>o<\/sup> and 128cm<sup>o<\/sup> respectively. Find the ratio of their radii.","options":["125:64","25:16","2:1","4:3","5:4"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"IF the exterior angles of a quadilateral are y<sup>o<\/sup>, (2y + 5)<sup>o<\/sup> , (y + 15)<sup>o<\/sup> and (3y - 10)<sup>o<\/sup>, find y<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["61.43","60","52.86","51.43","50"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The sum of the angles of regular polygon is 2520<sup>o<\/sup>. How many sides does the polygon have?","options":["20","18","17","16","15"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a property of all parallelogram?","options":["the diagonal bisects  each other","Each diagonal bisects the area","the diagonal cut at right angles","The opposite sides are equal","The opposite angles are equal"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"A ladder 6m long leans against a vertical wall so that it makes an angle of 60<sup>o<\/sup> with the wall. Calculate the distance of the foot of the ladder from the wall","options":["3m","6m","2\u221a3m","3\u221a3m","6\u221a3m"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The bearing of Q from P is 122<sup>o<\/sup>, what is the bearing of P from Q?","options":["212<sup>o<\/sup>","238<sup>o<\/sup>","248<sup>o<\/sup>","292<sup>o<\/sup>","302<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"cos 57<sup>o<\/sup> has the same value as","options":["sin 213<sup>o<\/sup>","-cos 303<sup>o<\/sup>","sin 147<sup>o<\/sup>","cos 123<sup>o<\/sup>","cos237<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The mean heights of the three groups of students consisting of 20, 16 and 14 students are 1.67m, 1.50m and 1.40m respectively. Find the mean height of the students","options":["1.52m","1.53m","1.54m","1.55m","1.56m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Two cards are drawn one after the other with replacement from a well-shuffled ordinary deck of 52 cards containing four Aces. Find the probability that they are both Aces","options":["1\/221","1\/169","1\/52","1\/26","1\/13"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"Find the probability that a number selected from the number 30 to 50 inclusive is a prime","options":["1\/4","5\/21","2\/7","3\/10","1\/3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"The length of an exercise book is given as 20cm correct to the nearest centimeter. In which of the following ranges of possible measurement does the actual length lie?","options":["19.5 - 20.5cm","19.1 - 20.9cm","19.9 - 20.1cm","19.9 - 20.1cm","19 - 21cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1994"},{"question":"S = (1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6), T = (2,4,5,7) and R = (1,4, 5), and (S\u2229T) \u222a R","options":["(1, 4, 5)","(2, 4, 5)","(1, 2, 4, 5)","(2, 3, 4, 5)","(1, 2, 3, 4, 5)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Simplify: 3\/4 + 1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> x (1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>-2\/3)","options":["7\/30","7\/24","9\/25","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","18\/25"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Solve the inequality: 3m + 3 > 9","options":["m > 2","m > 3","m>4","m>6","m>12"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Convert 89ten to a number in base two.","options":["1101001","1011001","1001101","101101","11001"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"A stick of length 1.75m was measured by a boy as 1.80m. Find the percentage error in his measurement","options":["2<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub>%","2<sup>6<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>%","5%","27<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub>%","28<sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>%."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"The nth term of a sequence is given by (-1)<sup>n-2<\/sup> 2<sup>n+1<\/sup>. Find the sum of the second and third terms.","options":["-2","1","2","6","12"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Simplify: <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">4<sup>-<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub><\/sup> x 16<sup>3\/4<\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">4<sup>1\/2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","o","1","2","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Simplify: <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">log\u221a27<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">log81<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["1\/6","3\/8","1\/2","3\/4","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Factorize the expression 2s<sup>2<\/sup> - 3st - 2t<sup>2<\/sup>.","options":["(2s - t)(s + 2t)","(2s + t)(s - 2t)","(S + t)(2s - 1)","(25 + t)(s -t)","(2s + t)(s + 2t)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Solve the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x - 3 = 0","options":["(-3, 1)","(-1, -3)","(3,1)","(43, 0)","(-1, 3)."],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Write as a single fraction  <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">5<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">6r<\/span><\/div> - <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">3<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">4r<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">r<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">12<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">12<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">r<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">6r<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">r<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">6<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">12r<\/span><\/div><\/div>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Factorize 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 21x + 45","options":["(2x - 9)(x - 5)","(2x-15)(x + 3)","(2x +15)(x - 3)","(2x -15(x - 3)","(2x - 9)(x + 5)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Solve the simultaneous equations y = 3x; 4y - 5x =14","options":[".-2,-6","2,6","2,-6","-2,6","-1,-3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"A cone is 14cm deep and the base radius is 4<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>cm. Calculate the volume of water that is exactly half the volume of the cone.[Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["49.5cm<sup>3<\/sup>","99cm<sup>3<\/sup>","148.5cm<sup>3<\/sup>","297cm<sup>3<\/sup>","445.5cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"The area and a diagonal of a rhombus are 60cm and 12cm respectively. Calculate the length of the other diagonal.","options":["5cm","6cm","10cm","12cm","15cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"The angle of a sector of a circle radius 10.5cm is 120<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the perimeter of the sector [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["22cm","33.5cm","43cm","66cm","115.5cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"The sum of an interior angles of a regular polygon is 30 right angles. How many sides has the polygon?","options":["34 sides","30 sides","26 sides","17 sides","15 sides"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Simplify <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">2.25<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">0.015<\/span><\/div> leaving your answer in standard form<\/div>","options":["1.5 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup>","1.5 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","1.5 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","1.5 x 10<sup>1<\/sup>","1.5 x 10<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"State the fifth and seventh terms of the sequence -2, -3, -4<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> ...........","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-81<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">8<\/span><\/div>,<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-729<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">32<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">8<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">81<\/span><\/div>,<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">72<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">39<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-27<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">729<\/span><\/div>,<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-718<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">39<\/span><\/div><\/di","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-27<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">16<\/span><\/div>,<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-79<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">81<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-21<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">8<\/span><\/div>,<div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">32<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">618<\/span><\/div><\/div>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"If sin x = cos 50<sup>o<\/sup>, then x equals","options":["40<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>","50<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup>","130<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Given that tan x = 5\/12, what is the value of sin x + cos x ?","options":["5\/13","7\/13","12\/13","17\/13","5\/12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Cos 75<sup>o<\/sup> has the same value as","options":["cos 115<sup>o<\/sup>","cos 255<sup>o<\/sup>","cos 285<sup>o<\/sup>","-sin165<sup>o<\/sup>","-sin 255<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"If sin x = 12\/13, where 0<sup>o<\/sup>  <  x < 90<sup>o<\/sup>, find the value of 1-cos<sup>2<\/sup>x","options":["25\/169","64\/169","105\/169","144\/169","8\/13"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"The angle of elevation of the top of a tower from a point on the horizontal ground, 40m away from the foot of the tower is 30<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the height of the tower.","options":["20m","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">40\u221a3m <\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">3<\/span><\/div><\/div>","20\u221a3m","40\u221a3m","60cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"At a point 500m from the base of a water tank the angle of elevation of the top of the tank is 45<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the height of the tank,","options":["250m","353m","354m","433m","500m"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Find the median of the following set of numbers: 28, 29, 39, 38, 33, 37, 26, 20, 15, 25","options":["33","29.5","29","28.5","28"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Find the median of the set of numbers 12, 15, 13, 14, 12, 12.","options":["12","12.5","13","13.5","14"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"The distribution by state of 840 students in the Faculty of Science of a Nigerian University in a certain session is as follows:<br>\r\n<table><tr><td>Bendel<\/td> <td>45<\/td><\/tr><tr><td>kwara<\/td><td>410<\/td><\/tr><tr><td>Ogun<\/td> <td>105<\/tr><tr><td>Ondo<\/td> <td>126<\/td><\/tr><tr><td>Oyo<\/td> <td>154<\/td><\/tr><\/table><br>\r\n<p>In a pie chart drawn to represent this distribution, the angle subtended by Ondo's <\/p>","options":["36<sup>o<\/sup>","42<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>","48<sup>o<\/sup>","54<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"What is the probability that an integer selected from the set of integers (20, 21, ...., 30) is a prime number","options":["2\/11","5\/11","6\/11","9\/11","2\/3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"A fair die is rolled once. What is the probability of obtaining a number less than 3?","options":["1\/6","1\/3","2\/3","1\/2","5\/6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"What is the probability of having an even number in a single toss of a fair die?","options":["1\/6","1\/3","1\/2","2\/3","5\/6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"What is the probability that the total sum of seven would appear in toss of a fair die?","options":["5\/36","1\/6","7\/36","5\/6","1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"<p>A die  rolled 200 times. The outcome obtained are shown in the table above.<\/p><br>\r\nWhat is the probability of obtaining a number less than 3 ?","options":["0.125","0.150","0.275","0.500","0.725"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1993"},{"question":"Let U = (1, 2, 3, 4), P = (2, 3) and Q = (2, 4). What is (P\u2229Q)'?","options":["(1, 2, 3)","(1, 3, 4)","(2, 3)","(1, 3)","(1, 4)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Simplify (<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> + <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>) x 4<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> + 3<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","options":["1\/2","13\/12","10\/9","17\/12","13\/9"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Convert 77 to a number in base two","options":["1001 101","111001","100110","10101","10011"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"A bricklayer measured the length of a wail and<br>\r\nobtained 4.10m. If the actual length of the wall is<br>\r\n4.25m, find his percentage error.","options":["3 9\/17%","3 27\/41%","15%","35 5\/17%","36 24\/41%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"The nth term of a sequence is given by 3.2<sup>n+2<\/sup><br>\r\nWrite down the first three terms of the sequence.","options":["2\/3, 0, 6","3\/2, 3, 6,","2\/3, 3, 8\/3","2\/3, <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>,  6","2\/3, 3, 1\/3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Simplify: (16\/81) <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","options":["8\/27","1\/3","4\/9","2\/3","-4\/3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Evaluate log<sub>10<\/sub>25 + log<sub>10<\/sub>32 - log<sub>10<\/sub>8","options":["0.2","2","100","409","490"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Factorize the expression 2y<sup>2<\/sup> + xy - 3x<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["2y (y + x) - 3x<sup>2<\/sup>","(2y - x)(2y + X)","(3x - 2y(x - y)","(2y + 3) x (y - X)","(X \u2013 y)(2y + BX)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Construct a quadratic equation whose roots are<br>\r\n-<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> and 2.","options":["3x<sup>2<\/sup>-3x+2=0","3x<sup>2<\/sup>+3x-2=0","2x<sup>2<\/sup>+3x-2=0","2x<sup>2<\/sup>-3x+2=0","2x<sup>2<\/sup>-3x-2=0"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Write a single fraction <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">1 - x<\/span><\/div> + <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">2<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">1 + x<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1 + 3<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">1 - x<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">3 - x<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">(1 - x)<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">3 - x<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">1 - x<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">3 - x<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">(1 + x)<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">3 - x<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">1 - x<sup>2<\/sup><\/span><\/div><\/div>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"What must be added to the expression x<sup>2<\/sup> - 18X to make it a perfect square?","options":["3","9","36","72","81"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Solve the equation <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">m<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">3<\/span><\/div> + <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">1<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">2<\/span><\/div> = <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">3<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">4<\/span><\/div> + <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">m<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">4<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["-3","-2","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"The angle of a sector of a circle of radius Bam is<br>\r\n240<sup>o<\/sup>. This sector is bent to form a cone. Find the<br>\r\nradius of the base of the cone.","options":["16\/3cm","15\/3cm","16\/5cm","8\/3cm","16\/10cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"The curved surface area of a cylindrical tin is<br>\r\n704cm<sup>2<\/sup>. Calculate the height when the radius is<br>\r\n8cm. [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["3.5cm","7cm","14cm","28cm","32cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"The volume of a cone of height 9cm is 1848cm\u201c.<br>\r\nFind its radius. [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["7cm","14cm","28cm","98cm","196cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"The area of a parallelogram is 513cm2 and the<br>\r\nheight is 19cm. Calculate the base.","options":["13.5cm","25cm","27cm","54cm","108cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"A regular polygon has each of its exterior angles as 18<sup>o<\/sup>. How many sides has the polygon","options":["10","11","12","20","24"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Sin 60<sup>o<\/sup> has the same value as I. Sin 120<sup>o<\/sup> II. cos 240<sup>o<\/sup> III. -sin 150<sup>o<\/sup> IV. cos 210<sup>o<\/sup> V. sin 240<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["I only","II only","IV only","III only","IV and V only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"If cos \u03b8 = 5\/13, what is the value of tan 0 for<br>\r\nO < \u03b8 < 9O<sup>o<\/sup> ?","options":["13","5","13\/5","12\/5","5\/12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"The value of tan 315<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["1","\u221a2\/2","o","-1","-\u221a2\/2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"The value of sin 210<sup>o<\/sup> is","options":["-<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">-\u221a3<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">2<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">\u221a2<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">2<\/span><\/div><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">\u221a3<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">2<\/span><\/div><\/div>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Town P is on bearing 315<sup>o<\/sup> from town Q while town R is south of town P and west of town Q. lf town R is 60km away from Q, how far is R from P?","options":["30km","42km","45km","60km","120km"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"A ladder leans against a vertical wall at an angle<br>\r\n60\u00b0 to the wall, if the foot of the ladder is 5 metres<br>\r\naway from the wall, calculate the length of the<br>\r\nladder.","options":["<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">5\u221a3m<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">3<\/span><\/div><\/div>","5m","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">10\u221a3m<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">3<\/span><\/div><\/div>","5\u221a3m","10m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"A cliff on the bank of a river is 300 metres<br>\r\nhigh. if the angle of depression of a point on the<br>\r\nopposite side of the river is 60\u00b0 find the width of<br>\r\nthe river.","options":["100m","75\u221a3m","100\u221a3m","200\u221a3m","300m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Points X and Y are respectively 12m Nonh and<br>\r\n5m of point Z. Calculate XY","options":["7m","12m","13m","17m","18m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Find the median of the following set of scores:<br>\r\n65, 72, 55, 48, 78","options":["55","60","63.5","65","72"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"A group of students measured a certain angle<br>\r\n(to the nearest degree) and obtained the following<br>\r\nresults: 75<sup>o<\/sup>, 76<sup>o<\/sup>, 72<sup>o<\/sup>, 73<sup>o<\/sup>, 74<sup>o<\/sup>, 79<sup>o<\/sup>, 72<sup>o<\/sup>, 72<sup>o<\/sup>, 77<sup>o<\/sup>,<br>\r\n72<sup>o<\/sup>, 71<sup>o<\/sup>, 70<sup>o<\/sup>, 78<sup>o<\/sup>, 73<sup>o<\/sup>. Find the mode","options":["79<sup>o<\/sup>","78<sup>o<\/sup>","74<sup>o<\/sup>","73<sup>o<\/sup>","72<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"<p>The table above shows the scores of 15 students in a Physics test.<\/p>How many students scored at least 5?","options":["1","6","8","9","14"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"A number is chosen at random from the set (1 ,2,3<br>\r\n....,9, 10). What is the probability that the number<br>\r\nis greater than or equal to 7?","options":["1\/10","3\/10","2\/5","3\/5","7\/10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"What is the probability of throwing a number greater than 2 with a single fair die","options":["1\/6","1\/3","1\/2","2\/3","5\/6"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"A fair die is rolled once. What is the probability of<br>\r\nobtaining 4 or 6?","options":["1\/12","1\/6","1\/3","1\/2","2\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Three balls are drawn one after the other with replacement, from a bag containing 5 red, 9white and 4 blue identical balls, What is the probability that they are one red, one white and one blue?","options":["5\/102","5\/136","5\/162","5\/204","5\/243"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"<p>The data below shows the number of worker?<br>\r\nemployed in the various sections of a construction<br>\r\ncompany in Lagos. <\/p><br>\r\n<br>\r\n<p>Carpenters 24 Labourers 27<br>\r\nPlumbers 12 Plasterers 15<br>\r\nPainters 9 Messengers 3<br>\r\nBricklayers 18<\/p><br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf one of the workers is absent on a certain day,<br>\r\nwhat is the probability that he is a bricklayer?","options":["1\/12","1\/9","2\/9","1\/6","1\/4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"<p>The data below shows the number of worker?<br>\r\nemployed in the various sections of a construction<br>\r\ncompany in Lagos. <\/p><br>\r\n<br>\r\n<p>Carpenters 24 Labourers 27<br>\r\nPlumbers 12 Plasterers 15<br>\r\nPainters 9 Messengers 3<br>\r\nBricklayers 18<\/p><br>\r\nIf a worker is retrenched, what is the probability that he is a plumber or plasterer.","options":["1\/27","1\/9","5\/36","1\/4","3\/4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1992"},{"question":"Express 0.0462 in standard form","options":["0.462 x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>","0.462 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","4.62 x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>","4.62 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","4.62 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"The population of a village is 5846. Express this number to three significant figures","options":["5850","5846","5840","585","584"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Simplify: log6 + log2 --  log12","options":["-4","-1","o","1","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Find the number whose logarithm to base 10 is 2.6025","options":["400.4","0.4004","0.04004","0.004004","0.0004004"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Simplify: <span class=\"fr_num\">(1)<sup>-1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub><\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">4<\/span>","options":["1\/8","1\/4","2","4","8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"For what value of y is the expression <br>\r\n<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">(y + 2)<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">y<sup>2<\/sup> - 3y- 10<\/span><\/div> undefined?<\/div>","options":["y = 0","y = 2","y = 3","y = 5","y = 10"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Factorize 3a<sup>2<\/sup> - 11a + 6","options":["(3a - 2)(a - 3)","(2a -2)(a - 3)","(3a - 2)(a + 3)","(3a + 2)(a - 3)","(2a-3)(a + 2)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Solve the equation: 3a + 10 = a<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["a = 5 or a = 2","a = -5 or a = 2","a = 10 or a = 0","a = 5 or a = 0","a = 5 or a = -2"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Simplify \\(\\frac{3}{x} + \\frac{15}{2y} + \\frac{6}{xy}\\)","options":["\\(\\frac{2y - 5x}{4}\\)","\\(\\frac{9(2x - 5x)}{x^2y^2}\\)","\\(\\frac{5x - 2y}{2}\\)","\\(\\frac{c^2y^2}{18y - 45x}\\)","\\(\\frac{4}{2y - 5x}\\)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Simplify: <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>(2<sup>n<\/sup> - 2<sup>n+2<\/sup>)","options":["2<sup>n2<\/sup> - 2<sup>n<\/sup>","2<sup>n-2<\/sup>(1-2<sup>n<\/sup>)","2<sup>n<\/sup> + 2<sup>2n<\/sup> + 2","2<sup>2n<\/sup>",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Find the equation whose roots are -2\/3 and -<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","options":["12x<sup>2<\/sup> + 11x + 2 = 0","12x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x + 2 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11\/12x + 2 = 0","12x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11x - 2 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 11\/12x - 2 = 0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Solve: 6(x - 4) + 3(x + 7) = 3","options":["3\/2","2\/3","1\/2","1\/3","o"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"If 2x + y = 7 and 3x - 2y = 3, by how much is 7x greater than 10?","options":["1","3","7","10","17"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"A cylinder of base radius 4cm is open at one end . If the ratio of the area of its base to that of its curved surface is 1:4, calculate the height of the cylinder","options":["1cm","2cm","4cm","8cm","16cm"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"A headmaster contributes 7% of his income into a fund and his wife contributes 4% of her income. If the husband earns N5,500 per annum (p.a) and the wife earns N4,000 (P.a), find the sum of their annual contribution to the fund","options":["N1045","N605","N545","N490","N440"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"A car is travelling at an average speed of 80km\/hr. Its speed in meters per second (m\/s) is","options":["13.3m\/s","22.2m\/s","133.3m\/s","222.2m\/s","1333.3m\/s"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Mrs. Kofi sold an article for C7.50 instead of C12.75. Calculate her percentage of error, correct to one decimal place.","options":["41.2%","18.3%","5.3%","1.7%","1.4%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"The first term a of an A.P is equal to twice the<br>\r\ncommon difference d. Find, in terms of d, the 5th<br>\r\nterm of the A.P.","options":["4d","5d","6d","a + 5d","2a + 4d"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"The common ratio of a G.P. is 2. If the 5th term is<br>\r\ngreater than the 1st term by 45, find the 5th term,","options":["3","6","45","48","90"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Two towns, P and Q, are on (4<sup>o<\/sup>N 40<sup>o<\/sup>W) and (4<sup>o<\/sup>N<br>\r\n20<sup>o<\/sup>E) respectively. What is the distance between<br>\r\nthem, along their line of latitude? (Give your<br>\r\nanswer in teems of \u03c0 and R, the radius of the earth).","options":["2\u03c0R cos4<sup>o<\/sup>","\u03c0R sin40<sup>o<\/sup>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">\u03c0R<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">2<\/span><\/div> cos4<sup>o<\/sup><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">\u03c0R<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">3<\/span><\/div> cos4<sup>o<\/sup><\/div>","<div class=\"eq-c\"><div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">\u03c0R<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">6<\/span><\/div> cos4<sup>o<\/sup><\/div>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Given that sin 9 = -0.9063, where O \\(\\leq\\) \\(\\theta\\) <sup>o<\/sup> \\(\\leq\\) 270<sup>o<\/sup>,<br>\r\nfind \\(\\theta\\).","options":["65<sup>o<\/sup>","115<sup>o<\/sup>","145<sup>o<\/sup>","245<sup>o<\/sup>","265<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"P=(2, 1,3, 9, <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>)Q=(1,2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>,3, 7)and R=<br>\r\n(5, 4, 2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>)<br>\r\nFind P\u222aQ\u222aR","options":["(2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>)","(1, 9)","(1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7)","(5, 4, 2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>)","(<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>, 1, 2, 2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>, 3, 4, 5, 7, 9)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"P=(2, 1,3, 9, <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>)Q=(1,2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>,3, 7)andR=<br>\r\n(5, 4, 2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>)<br>\r\nFind P\u2229Q\u2229R","options":["(2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>)","\u2205","(1, 3, 7)","(4)","(5,7,9)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a measure of<br>\r\ndispersion?","options":["Mode","Mean deviation","Range","interquartile range","Standard deviation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"The mean of 30 observations recorded in an<br>\r\nexperiment is 5. lf the observed largest value of<br>\r\n34 is deleted, find the mean of the remaining<br>\r\nobservations","options":["5","4","3.9","3.4","3.0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"<p>If events X and Y are mutually exclusive, .<br>\r\nP(X) = 1\/3 and P(Y) = 2\/5,<br>\r\n<\/p><br>\r\nP(X\u2229Y) is","options":["o","2\/15","11\/15","4\/15","1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"<p>If events X and Y are mutually exclusive, .<br>\r\nP(X) = 1\/3 and P(Y) = 2\/5,<br>\r\n<\/p><br>\r\nP(X\u222aY) is","options":["o","2\/15","4\/14","11\/15","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"A box contains 2 white and 3 blue identical<br>\r\nmarbles. If two marbles are picked at random,<br>\r\none after the other without replacement, what is<br>\r\nthe probability of picking two marbles of different<br>\r\ncolours?","options":["2\/3","3\/5","2\/5","7\/20","3\/10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Mrs. Jones is expecting a baby. The probability<br>\r\nthat it will be a boy is <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> and probability that the<br>\r\nbaby will have blue eyes is <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>. What is the<br>\r\nprobability that she will have a blue-eyed boy?","options":["1\/8","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","3\/8","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","3\/4"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Which of the following about a rhombus may not<br>\r\nbe true?","options":["The diagonals are equal","The diagonals bisect the angles through which they pass","the diagonals bisect each other","The adjacent sides are equal","Opposite angles are equal"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"The angles of a pentagon are x<sup>o<\/sup>, 2x<sup>o<\/sup> (x + 6O) <sup>o<\/sup>,<br>\r\n(X + 10) <sup>o<\/sup>, (x -1O) <sup>o<\/sup>. Find the value of x","options":["40","60","75","80","90"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"In a given regular polygon, the ratio of the exterior angle to the interior angles is 1:3. How many side has the polygon?","options":["40","5","6","8","12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Find the area of an equivalent triangle of side 16cm","options":["64\u221a3cm<sup>2<\/sup>","72\u221a3cm<sup>2<\/sup>","96cm<sup>2<\/sup>","128\u221a3cm<sup>2<\/sup>","128cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1991"},{"question":"Simplify 125<sup>-1\/3<\/sup> x 49<sup>-1\/2<\/sup> x 10<sup>0<\/sup>","options":["350","35","1\/35","1\/350",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"If 3<sup>2x<\/sup> = 27, what is x?","options":["1","1.5","4.5","18","40.5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Express 0.00562 in standard form","options":["5.62 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>","5.62 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","562 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","5.62 x 10<sup>2<\/sup>","5.62 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Given that 1\/3log<sub>10<\/Sub> P = 1, find the value of P","options":["1\/10","3","10","100","1000"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Simplify <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">log\u221a8<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">log8<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["1\/3","1\/2","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>log\u221a2","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>log\u221a8","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>log\u221a2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Evaluate using the logarithm table, log(0.65)<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["1.6258","0.6272","0.6258","3.6258","1.6272"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"If log x = 2.3675 an log y = 0.9750, what is the value of x + y? Correct to three significant figures","options":["1.18","1.31","9.03","9.44","9.46"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"While doing his physics practical, Idowu recorded a reading as 1.12cm instead of 1.21cm. Calculate his percentage error","options":["1.17%","6.38%","7.44%","8.035%","9.00%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Find the 4th term of an A.P, whose first term is 2 and the common difference is 0.5","options":["0.5","2.5","3.5","4","4.5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"An arc of length 22cm subtends an angle of \u03b8 at the center of the circle. What is the value of \u03b8 if the radius of the circle is 15cm?[Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["70<sup>o<\/sup>","84<sup>o<\/sup>","96<sup>o<\/sup>","156<sup>o<\/sup>","168<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Find the sum of the first five terms of the G.P 2.6 18 ....","options":["484","243","242","130","121"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Let J be the set of positive integers, If H = (x: x\u2208J, x<sup>2<\/sup> < 3 and x \u2260 0), then","options":["H = (1)","H is an infinite et","H = (0, 1, 2)","H = ()","J \u2264 H"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"In a class of 80 students, every students had to study economics or geography, or both economics and geography, if 65 students studied economics and 50 studied geography, how many studied both subjects?","options":["15","30","35","45","50"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Factorize x<sup>2<\/sup> + 4x - 192","options":["(x-4) (x+48)","(x-48) (x+4)","(x-12) (x+16)","(x-12) (x-16)","(x+12) (x+16)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Factorize 2e<sup>2<\/sup> - 3e + 1","options":["(2e-1) (e-1)","(e+1) (2e+1)","(2e+3) (e+2)","(2e-3) (e-1)","(e<sup>2<\/sup>-3(2e-1)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Solve the equation 7y<sup>2<\/sup> = 3y","options":["y = 3 or 7","y = 0 or 7","y = 0 or 3\/7","y = 0 or 9","y = 0 or 10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Find the value of m which makes x<sup>2<\/sup> + 8 + m a perfect square","options":["2","4","8","12","16"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Solve the equation 2a<sup>2<\/sup> - 3a - 27 = 0","options":["3\/2, 9","-2\/3, 9","3, 9\/2","-3, -9\/2","-3, 9\/2"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"A sector of a circle of radius 7cm has an area of 44cm<sup>2<\/sup>. Calculate the angle of the sector correct to the nearest degree  [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["6<sup>o<\/sup>","26<sup>o<\/sup>","52<sup>o<\/sup>","103<sup>o<\/sup>","206<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"calculate the surface area of a sphere of radius 7cm [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["86cm<sup>2<\/sup>","154cm<sup>2<\/sup>","616cm<sup>2<\/sup>","1434cm<sup>2<\/sup>","4312cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"If the radius of the parallel of latitude 30<sup>o<\/sup>N is equal to the radius of the parallel of latitude \u03b8<sup>o<\/sup>S, what is the value of \u03b8?","options":["75<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>","30<sup>o<\/sup>","0<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"A cylindrical container closed at both ends, has a radius of 7cm and height 5cm [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]<br>\r\nFind the total surface area of the container","options":["35cm<sup>3<\/sup>","154cm<sup>3<\/sup>","220cm<sup>3<\/sup>","528cm<sup>3<\/sup>","770cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"<p><br>\r\nA cylindrical container closed at both ends, has a radius of 7cm and height 5cm [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]<\/P><br>\r\nWhat is the volume of the container","options":["35cm<sup>3<\/sup>","154cm<sup>3<\/sup>","220cm<sup>3<\/sup>","528cm<sup>3<\/sup>","770cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"Use mathematical table to evaluate (cos40<sup>o<\/sup> - sin30<sup>o<\/sup>)","options":["-0.2660","-0.0266","0.0266","0.2660","1.5320"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"The bearing of a point x from a point y is 074<sup>o<\/sup>. What is the bearing of y from x?","options":["106<sup>o<\/sup>","146<sup>o<\/sup>","164<sup>o<\/sup>","254<sup>o<\/sup>","286<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"If a student in favour of the proposal is selected for a post, what is the probability that he is from group A?","options":["8\/19","16\/35","10\/19","4\/7","4\/5"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"If a student is chosen at random, what is probability that he is against the proposal?","options":["3\/19","4\/19","5\/19","9\/19","10\/19"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1990"},{"question":"If 3loga + 5loga - 6loga = log64, what is a?","options":["4","6","8","16","32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"If the second and fourth term of a G.P are 8 and 32 respectively,what is the sum of the first four terms?","options":["28","40","48","60","68"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"<div class=\"eq-c\">Evaluate, using logarithm tables  <div class=\"fraction\"><span class=\"fr_num\">5.34 x 67.4<\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">2.7<\/span><\/div><\/div>","options":["1.332","13.32","133.2","1332","13.320"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Factorize 35 - 2b - b<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["(35-2b)(b-1)","(7+b)(5-b)","(3+7b)(5-b)","(35-b)(3b+7)","(7+b)(5+b)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Evaluate 0.009 \/ 0.012, leaving your answer in standard form","options":["7.5 x 10<sup>2<\/sup>","7.5 x 10<sup>1<\/sup>","7.5 x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>","7.5 x 10<sup>-2<\/sup>","7.5 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Factorize the following expression; 2x<sup>2<\/sup> + x - 15","options":["(2x+5)(x-3)","(2x-5)(x+3)","(2x-5)(x-3)","(2x-3)(x+5)","(2x+5)(x+3)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Instead of recording the number 1.23cm of the radius of a tube, a student recorded 1.32cm. Find the percentage of error, correct to one decimal place.","options":["6.8%","7.3%","9.6%","14.4%","15.4%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"An arc of a circle radius 7cm is 14cm long. What angle does the arc subtend at the center of circle?<br>\r\n[Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["25.7<sup>o<\/sup>","44<sup>o<\/sup>","51.43<sup>o<\/sup>","98<sup>o<\/sup>","114.55<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"If 5 times a certain integer is subtracted from twice the integer, the result is 63. Find the integer.","options":["21","9","7","4","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"If 3 <sup>y<\/sup> = 243, find the value of y","options":["2","3","4","5","6"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Points X and Y are respectively 20km North and 9km East of a point O. What is the bearing of Y from X? Correct to the nearest degree","options":["024<sup>o<\/sup>","114<sup>o<\/sup>","156<sup>o<\/sup>","204<sup>o<\/sup>","336<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Calculate the surface area of a hallow cylinder which is closed at one end, if the base radius is 3.5cm and the height 8cm.[take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["126.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","165cm<sup>2<\/sup>","176cm<sup>2<\/sup>","214.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","253.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Solve the following equation: 6x<sup>2<\/sup> - 7x - 5 = 0","options":["x = <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> or x = -2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","x = 1\/3 or x = 2<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","x = 1 <sup>2<\/sup>\/3 or x = -<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","x = 1<sup>2<\/sup>\/3 or x = <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","x = 5\/6 or x = -1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"If A = (a,b,c), B = (a,b,c,d,e) and C = (a,b,c,d,e,f). Find (A\u222aB)\u2229(A\u222aC)","options":["(a,b,c,d)","(a,b,c,d,e)","(a,b,c,d,e,f)","(a,b,c)","\u03a6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"What is the mode of the score","options":["3","4","5","6","7"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"What is the median score?","options":["2","7","8","9","10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"What is the range of the distribution?","options":["2","7","8","9","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Simplify <span class=\"fr_num\">9<sup><sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub><\/sup><\/span><span class=\"bar\">\/<\/span><span class=\"fr_den\">27<sup><sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub><\/sup><\/span>","options":["1","1\/3","1\/9","1\/18","1\/27"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Find the volume of a cone of radius 3.5cm and vertical height 12cm [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["3.4cm<sup>2<\/sup>","15.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","21.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","42.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","154.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"The angle of a sector of a circle of diameter 8cm [Take x = 22\/7].","options":["9<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>","12<sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>","18<sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>","25<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>","31<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"A sector is cut off from a circle radius 8.2cm to form a cone, if the radius of the resulting cone is 3.5cm, calculate the curved surface area of the cone. [take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["11.25cm<sup>2<\/sup>","12.83cm<sup>2<\/sup>","22.0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","67.2cm<sup>2<\/sup>","90.2cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"If log<sub>a<\/sub>x = p, express x in terms  of a and p","options":["x = u + p","x = a\/p","x = p","x = ap","x = a<sup>p<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Calculate and correct to three significant figures, the length of an arc subtends an angle of 70<sup>o<\/sup> at the center of the circle radius 4cm. [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["2.44cm","4.89cm","9.78cm","25.1cm","50.3cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Solve for x: (x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x + 1) = 25","options":["-6, -4","6, -4","6, 4","-6, 4","5, 5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Given that logp = 2 logx + 3logq, which of the following expresses p in terms of x and q?","options":["p = 5xq","p = 6xq","p = x<sup>2<\/sup> + q<sup>3<\/sup>","p = 2x + 3q","p = x<sup>2<\/sup>q<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"sin\u03b8 = <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub> and cos\u03b8 = -\u221a3\/2, what is the value of  \u03b8?","options":["30 <sup>0<\/sup>","60 <sup>0<\/sup>","90 <sup>o<\/sup>","120 <sup>o<\/sup>","150 <sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"What is the probability that 3 customers waiting in a bank will be served in the sequence of their arrival at the bank","options":["1\/6","1\/3","1\/2","2\/3","5\/6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"In an A.p the first term is 2, and the sum of the 1st and the 6th term is 16<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>. What is the 4th term","options":["12","9<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","8","7","5<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1989"},{"question":"Evaluate (101.5)<sup>2<\/sup> - (100.5)<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["1","2.02","20.02","202","2020"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Express the product of 0.06 and 0.09 in standard form","options":["5.4 * 10<sup>-1<\/sup>","5.4*10<sup>-2<\/sup>","5.4*10<sup>-3<\/sup>","5.4*10<sup>2<\/sup>","5.4*10<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Simplify 36<sup><sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub><\/sup> x 64<sup><sup>-1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub><\/sup> x 5<sup>0<\/sup>","options":["o","1\\24","2\/3","1<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","7<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Find the 8th term of the A.P -3, -1, 1 ......","options":["13","11","-8","-11","-17"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"If cos 60<sup>o<\/sup> = 1\/2, which of the following angle has cosine of -1\/2?","options":["30<sup>o<\/sup>","120<sup>o<\/sup>","150<sup>o<\/sup>","210<sup>o<\/sup>","300<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"What is the difference in longitude between P (lat. 50<sup>o<\/sup>N. long. 50<sup>o<\/sup>W) and Q (lat.50 sup>o<\/sup>N, long. 150W)?","options":["300<sup>o<\/sup>","200<sup>o<\/sup>","130<sup>o<\/sup>","100<sup>o<\/sup>","30<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"The  number  186,470 was corrected to 186,000. Which of the following describe the degree of approximation made?<br>\r\nI. to the nearest hundred II. to the nearest thousand III. to 3 significant figures Iv. 3 significant figures","options":["I & III only","I & IV only","II & III only","II & IV only","All of the above"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"<p>Points P and Q respectively 24m north and 7m east point R <\/p><br>\r\nWhat is the bearing of Q from P to the nearest whole degree?","options":["16<sup>o<\/sup>","17<sup>o<\/sup>","73<sup>o<\/sup>","106<sup>o<\/sup>","164<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"If sin\u03b8 = 3\/5 find tan\u03b8   for 0 < \u03b8 < 90<sup>o<\/sup>","options":["4\\5","3\\4","5\\8","1\\2","3\\8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Simplify (27<sup>1\/3<\/sup>)<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["4<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","6","9","18","81"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"A student told to draw the graph of y = x<sup>2<\/sup> + 4x - 6. He is then told to draw a liner graph on the same axis such that the intersection of the two graphs will give the solutions to the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> + 4x - 7 = 0, What is the equation of the linear graph he needs to draw?","options":["x = 1","x = -1","y = 1","y = -1","x + y = 1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Find the quadratic equation whose roots are x = -2 or x = 7","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x - 7 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2x + 7 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + 5 +14 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x - 14 = 0","x<sup>2<\/sup> + 5x - 14 = 0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"A sales girl gave a change of N1.15 to a customer instead of N1.25. Calculate her percentage error","options":["10%","7%","8.0%","2.4%","10%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"What is the probability of having an odd number in a single toss of a fair die?","options":["1\/6","1\/3","1\/2","2\/3","5\/6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Evaluate log<sub>10<\/sub>6 + log<sub>10<\/sub>45 - log<sub>10<\/sub>27 without using logarithm tables","options":["o","1","1.1738","1.3802","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Find the product xy if, x, 3\/2, 6\/7, y are in G.P","options":["24\/49","4\/7","9\/7","7\/4","21\/8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Factorize 5y<sup>2<\/sup> + 2y - 3a<sup>2<\/sup>","options":["(5y - a) (y + 3a)","(5y + a) (y - 3a)","5y<sup>2<\/sup> + a (2y - 3a)","(y - a) (5y + 3a)","(y + a) (5y - 3a)"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Abidjan is 4<sup>o<\/sup> west of Accra and on the same circle of latitude. If the radius of this circle of latitude is 6370km, how far is Abidjan west of Accra, correct  to the nearest kilometer? [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["222km","445km","890km","5005km","10010km"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"A cone is made from a  sector of circle of radius 14cm and angle of 90<sup>o<\/sup>. What is the area of the curved surface of the cone? (Take x = 22\/7)","options":["22cm<sup>2<\/sup>","38.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","77cm<sup>2<\/sup>","154cm<sup>2<\/sup>","308cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"A rope of length 18m is used to form a sector of a circle of radius 3.5m on a school playing field. What is the size of the angle of the sector, correct to the nearest degree?","options":["33<sup>o<\/sup>","40<sup>o<\/sup>","90<sup>o<\/sup>","180<sup>o<\/sup>","270<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"Cotonou and Niamey are on the same line of longitude and  Niamey is 7<sup>o<\/sup> north of Cotonou. If the radius of the earth is 6400km, how far is Niamey north of Cotonou along the line of longitude, correct to the nearest kilometer? [Take \u03c0 = 22\/7]","options":["391km","503km","782km","1006km","2012km"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"If Q = (all perfect squares less than 30) and P = (all odd numbers from 1 yo 10). Find Q \u2229 P.","options":["(1, 4, 9, 16, 25)","(1, 3, 4, 5, 7, 9, 16, 25)","(1, 3, 5, 7, 9)","(1, 9)","\u03a6"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"<p>The surnames of 40 children in a class arranged in alphabetical order. 16 of the surnames begins with O and 9 of the surname begins with A, 14, of the letters of the alphabet do not appear as the first letter of a surname<\/p><br>\r\nWhat is the probability that the surname of a child picked at random from the class begins with either O or A?","options":["5\/8","7\/8","9\/16","14\/25","39\/40"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1988"},{"question":"<p><br>\r\nThe surnames of 40 children in a class arranged in alphabetical order. 16 of the surnames begins with O and 9 of the surname begins with A, 14, of the letters of the alphabet do not appear as the first letter of a surname<\/p><br>\r\nIf more than one surname begins with a letter besides A and O, how may surnames begin with that letter","options":["2","3","4","5","6"],"answerIndex":5,"examYear":"1988"}]